Music playing...
音乐播放中……
All right, this is CS50, Harvard University's introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science and the arts of programming.
大家好，欢迎来到 CS50，这是哈佛大学计算机科学的知识探索和编程艺术的入门课程。
My name is David Malan, and I actually took this course myself back in 1996. I was a sophomore at the time.
我叫 David Malan，我本人在 1996 年也上过这门课。 当时我大二。
I was actually concentrating in government, because a year prior as a first year, I'd come into Harvard thinking that I liked history and constitutional law and sort of similar classes in high school.
实际上，我当时主修的是政府管理，因为大一的时候，我刚进哈佛时，觉得我喜欢历史和宪法之类的课程，和高中上的课差不多。
And so when I got here, I rather gravitated toward that which was familiar.
所以我来到这里后， 我更倾向于选择我熟悉的东西。
I figured if I liked and if I were good at that particular subject in high school, then that's presumably who I'm supposed to be here.
我想，如果我喜欢高中某一门特定的科目并且擅长它，那么我在这里就应该继续学习它。
But it wasn't until sophomore year that I got up the nerve to step foot in the CS50 classroom, and even then it was only out of curiosity.
但直到大二那年，我才鼓起勇气踏进了 CS50 的教室，即使在那时，也仅仅是 出于好奇。
Like, I had no intention of studying computer science, of even taking CS50 when I got to campus.
我根本没想过要学习计算机科学，甚至没想过在入学时要选修 CS50。
But people were talking about it.
但人们都在谈论它。
And there was a lot of, like, beware.
而且很多人都在说，要小心这门课。
And it was perhaps for the initiated only.
它可能只适合那些入门的人。
And I didn't really know, ultimately, what computer science was.
而且我当时并不真正了解计算机科学是什么。
But for me, The sort of light bulb went off.
但对我来说， 就像一盏灯在我心中亮了起来。
And I found that, contrary to what I'd seen in high school, where I saw friends of mine programming away in the computer lab, heads down, sort of anti-socially just doing whatever it was they were doing, it really wasn't that once I got to this particular class in this particular place.
我发现，与我在高中时看到的情景不同，我看到我的朋友们在计算机实验室里埋头编程，
不善社交，只顾着做自己的事情，而当我来到这个特殊的班级，这个特殊的地方时，情况就完全不同了。
It was much more about problem solving more generally and just learning how to express yourself in code in different languages so that you can actually solve problems of interest to you, even if you have no intention of being a computer scientist or an engineer,
它更多的是关于更普遍的问题解决，
学习如何用不同的语言用代码表达自己，这样你就可以解决你感兴趣的问题，即使你没有成为计算机科学家或工程师的打算，
But just want to be able to solve problems, analyze data, do interesting things in the arts, humanities, social sciences, physical sciences, or really any other field.
但只是想能够解决问题、分析数据，在艺术、人文、社会科学、物理科学或任何其他领域做一些有趣的事情。
And indeed, this particular path led me to computer science.
事实上，这条路最终引领我进入了计算机科学领域。
But the hope for CS50 more generally is that indeed you just find your way to applying principles that you'll learn over the coming months to whatever field is of interest to you.
但更广泛地说，CS50 的目标是希望你能找到方法，将你在未来几个月学到的原则应用到你感兴趣的任何领域。
With that said, it was definitely a lot of work.
话虽如此，这门课确实需要付出很多努力。
And not without its frustrations for me, but there was no better feeling
对我来说，这并非没有挫败感，但没有比这更好的感觉了，
Then, like, banging your head proverbial against the wall for some number of hours, even days, trying to fix a bug, a mistake in your code.
就像，花了好几个小时甚至好几天的时间，试图修复代码中的错误，却像是在用头撞墙一样，
And then, oh my god, the rush of emotion, of accomplishment, of pride, of exhaustion when you finally solve some problem that's really been weighing on you.
然后，当你最终解决了困扰你很久的问题时，你会感到无比激动、成就感、自豪感，以及疲惫感。
It's just so incredibly gratifying, but also empowering.
这不仅令人难以置信地满足，而且还赋予人力量。
Because unlike a lot of fields, computer science was built by humans themselves.
因为与许多领域不同，计算机科学是由人类自己创造的。
And so if a human built this, surely you, another human, can understand it as well.
如果一个人能创造出来，那么你，另一个同样是人，肯定也能理解它。
And so even though there's going to be some distractions along the way, you're going to see what looks incredibly cryptic if you've never programmed before over time.
因此，即使在学习过程中会有一些干扰，但随着时间的推移，如果你以前从未接触过编程，你将会看到一些看起来难以理解的东西。
And with practice, everything just starts to make more sense.
通过练习，一切都会变得越来越清晰。
And with time and with practice, you just get better at this particular field.
随着时间的推移和练习，你就会在这个领域越来越出色。
And indeed, really, the key to success in programming in general It's just to allow yourself enough time.
事实上，编程成功的关键在于 给自己足够的时间。
And so at least thankfully, I quickly got into the habit of starting early in the week, for instance, when writing actual code.
因此，值得庆幸的是，我很快就养成了一个习惯，比如在编写实际代码时，在一周的早些时候就开始。
Why? Because you're going to run up against a wall.
为什么？ 因为你将会遇到障碍。
You're not going to see some bug.
你不会发现一些错误。
Something's not going to jump out at you.
有些东西你不会一眼就看出来。
And that's fine.
这很正常。
That's when you sort of call it a day, take a break, move on to something else, and then just come back to it.
这时候你就应该停下来休息一下，做点别的事情，然后再回来继续。
And that's what keeps programming fun for me even all of these years later, whether it's teaching or actually applying it.
这也是为什么这么多年来，无论是教学还是实际应用，编程对我来说都很有趣的原因。
But there's, down the road, a history of, An MIT hack, and it looked a little something like this in yesteryear.
但接下来，我们会讲到 一个 MIT 的黑客事件，它在过去看起来像这样。
And there was a little sign the MIT students, when they made this hack, on the wall that says, getting an education from MIT is like drinking from a fire hose, which indeed they have connected to what should have been otherwise just a water fountain.
MIT 的学生们在进行这个黑客行动时，在墙上贴了一个小标语，
上面写着：“在MIT接受教育就像拿着消防水管喝水”。他们确实把消防水管接到了原本应该是饮水机的地方。
And that's going to be what it feels like sometimes, not just in computer science per se, but just an unfamiliar field.
这将是你有时会有的感觉，不仅仅是在计算机科学领域，在任何不熟悉的领域都是如此。
If you're not from STEM, if you're not from CS, that's fine.
如果你不是 STEM 专业，如果你不是计算机专业，那也没关系。
But so much of it ultimately is going to be absorbed by you and going to be
但最终你会吸收很多东西，
So just keep in mind, that's very much the intent, but you'll be amazed what you're able to create to accomplish just three or so months hence.
所以请记住，这就是我们的目的，你将会惊讶于你在短短三个月内就能创造和完成的事情。
Indeed, 2 thirds of you, contrary to what you might think or assume, have never taken a CS class before.
事实上，你们中三分之二的人，与你们的想象或假设相反，以前从未上过 CS 课。
So it's absolutely necessary.
所以这是绝对必要的。
And as you'll see in the coming weeks, as you write your own code and solve your own problems, what ultimately matters in this course is not so much where you end up relative to your classmates, but where you end up relative to yourself.
在接下来的几周里，你会发现，当你编写自己的代码并解决自己的问题时，这门课最终重要的不是你相对于同学的水平，而是你相对于自己的水平。
When you began, and it really is all about that delta, whether you've programmed or not, just getting something out of a class like this.
从你开始学习的时候，无论你是否编程，真正重要的是你在课堂上的进步。
And if it does take time, and if you do feel those frustrations, but you simultaneously eventually feel that sense of accomplishment, that just means it's all working.
如果确实需要时间，如果你确实感到沮丧，但同时你最终也感受到了成就感，那意味着一切都在朝着好的方向发展。
And indeed, hopefully, all the more worthwhile and gratifying, ultimately, as a result.
最终，希望这门课对你们来说更有价值、更有意义。
So what are we going to do in the coming week?
那么，接下来的一周我们要做什么呢？
So here we are in week 0.
现在是第 0 周。
We'll soon see why computers and computer scientists start counting, if you will, from 0.
我们很快就会明白为什么计算机和计算机科学家要从 0 开始计数。
But week 0 is one in which we explore computational thinking, sort of thinking like a computer and starting to clean up your thought processes, getting you to think to solve problems more methodically, and then ultimately translating that into code.
在第 0 周，我们将探索计算思维，像计算机一样思考，开始整理你的思路，让你更有条理地思考和解决问题，并最终将这些思路转化为代码。
And some of you might recognize this environment here, a.k.a. Scratch, coincidentally, also from MIT.
你们中有些人可能认出这个环境了，巧合的是，Scratch 也来自于麻省理工学院。
You might have used it.
你可能使用过它。
In grade school, we'll use it today and a little bit this weekend in the course's first homework assignment or problem set, but not so much to kind of play around in a way that you might have if you did use it in yesteryear, but to explore ideas of computer science and programming that we're going to use and reuse every week hereafter as well.
在本周和周末的第一份家庭作业或习题集中，我们会使用它，
但不是像你以前那样随意摆弄，而是借此探索计算机科学和编程的思想，这些思想我们将在之后每周都会用到。
Thereafter, we're going to transition just next week to week one, so to speak, whereby we'll introduce you to a more traditional language,
之后，我们将在下周过渡到第一周，我们将向你介绍一种更传统的语言，
a lower level language, an older language called C. And in C, you're going to use your keyboard, not so much your mouse and pointing and clicking, but you're going to write code that soon is going to look a little something like this.
一种更底层的语言，一种叫做 C 语言的古老语言。在 C 语言中，你将使用键盘，而不是鼠标进行指向和点击，你将编写的代码很快就会变成这样。
And if you've programmed before, you can probably glean what this is going to do if you've never programmed before, which is the case for most of you.
如果你以前编写过程序，你可能已经了解了这段代码的作用；如果你是大多数人一样从未编写过程序，
This, too, will soon make sense.
这很快也会变得容易理解。
But this is the most canonical program that most any programmer ever writes, called Hello World.
但这是大多数程序员都会编写的最经典的程序，叫做“Hello World”。
And indeed, that and all of the surrounding syntax above and below just that sentence, Hello World, will soon make all the more sense.
事实上，这句话以及它上面和下面所有的语法很快就会变得更加清晰易懂。
You'll learn how to use industry standard tools, so to speak.
你将学习如何使用行业标准工具。
Pictured here is something called Visual Studio Code, or VS Code.
图中所示的是 Visual Studio Code，简称 VS Code。
You'll use VS Code. A cloud-based version of it, initially, so you don't have to suffer with any technical difficulties or headaches like that.
你会使用 VS Code。 最初使用的是基于云的版本，因此你无需担心任何技术难题或麻烦。
It'll just work right off the bat.
它可以立即开始工作。
But we'll use that tool and others, ultimately, to then explore ideas in computer science, principles that you can apply.
但我们最终将使用该工具和其他工具来探索计算机科学中的思想和可以应用的原理。
And we'll take a look underneath the hood, so to speak, of your computer at your memory or RAM, Random Access Memory, where all of the data is ultimately going to be stored.
我们将看一下计算机内部的内存或 RAM（随机存取存储器），所有数据最终都将存储在那里。
We'll also take a look thereafter at data.
之后我们还会研究数据。
Bugs, a bug is a mistake in a program.
Bug，Bug 是程序中的错误。
Here is an actual bug in an actual computer in yesteryear.
这是过去一台实际计算机中的一个真实 Bug。
But we'll teach you how to debug programs, find your own mistakes, find others' mistakes, and improve that code as well.
但我们会教你如何调试程序，找到自己的错误，找到别人的错误，并改进代码。
We'll transition then to algorithms, step-by-step instructions for solving some problems, which we'll touch on today too.
接下来我们将过渡到算法，也就是解决问题的分步说明，我们今天也会讲到。
And if you picture here, this is actually a pretty representative problem.
想象一下，这实际上是一个非常有代表性的问题。
Odds are you haven't had to deal with something like this, but it's representative sorting, for instance.
你很可能没有遇到过这样的问题，但它代表着排序。
If you think of each of these small bars as being a small number, each of the bigger bars as being a bigger number, you might wonder, well, how could you, as a human, sort all of these bars?
如果你把这些小条中的每一个都看成是一个小数字，把每一个大条都看成是一个大数字，你可能会想，作为一个人，你怎么能对所有这些条进行排序？
Like, get all the short bars over here, all the big bars over there.
比如，把所有短的条放在这边，把所有长的条放在那边。
Well, odds are, if you're like me, you would probably kind of eyeball it.
如果你像我一样，你可能会用肉眼观察。
And if you could physically interact,
如果你能进行物理交互，
You might just start grabbing the smallest elements first, put them over on the left, maybe grab the biggest elements, put them over on the right.
你可能会先抓住最小的元素，把它们放在左边，也许再抓住最大的元素，把它们放在右边。
But what's your algorithm there?
但你的算法是什么？
How would you teach someone younger than you who's never done that before how to do it?
你如何教一个比你年轻、以前从未做过这件事的人如何做？
How would you compel your Mac or PC or phone to do something like that?
你如何让你的 Mac、PC 或手机做这样的事情？
You can't just kind of wave your hand and say, oh, figure it out, move things around.
你不能只是挥挥手说，把它弄清楚，把东西移来移去。
You have to express yourself more methodically.
你必须更有条理地表达自己。
So we'll translate even ideas like this into code too.
所以我们也要把这样的想法转化成代码。
And that's what the Googles and others of the world are doing constantly as they sort and organize the world's information.
这就是 Google 和世界上的其他公司在对世界信息进行分类和组织时一直在做的事情。
We'll use metaphors along the way if it helps.
如果有帮助，我们会使用比喻。
We'll talk about your computer's memory as kind of being like a postal address, like every mailbox in the world has some form of postal address, street, city, state, country, and the like.
我们会把你的计算机内存比作邮政地址，就像世界上的每个邮箱都有一定的邮政地址，街道、城市、州、国家等等。
And it turns out that's how your Mac, your PC, and your phone also work.
事实证明，你的 Mac、PC 和手机也是这样工作的。
You've got a whole bunch of memory, like the picture before.
你有大量的内存，就像之前的图片一样。
But you can think of it really as individual mailboxes.
但你可以把它想象成一个个的邮箱。
And you can put anything you want in those mailboxes, and you can go to a mailbox to grab information that's from it.
你可以在这些邮箱里放任何你想放的东西，你也可以去邮箱里获取里面的信息。
So at the end of the day, that's really all your computer's doing with information.
所以说到底，这就是你的电脑处理信息的方式。
It's just kind of organizing it, not into mailboxes per se, but a term you probably know called bytes, for instance, instead.
它只是在组织信息，不是以邮箱的形式，而是以一种你可能知道的术语，叫做字节。
We'll talk about problems that arise, even nowadays.
我们会讨论即使在今天也会出现的问题。
In fact, most of you are familiar with your Mac, PC, even phone, like spontaneously rebooting sometimes, crashing, the little annoying spinning beach ball or hourglass icon that happens.
事实上，你们大多数人都熟悉自己的 Mac、PC，甚至是手机，它们有时会自动重启、崩溃，出现烦人的旋转沙滩球或沙漏图标。
What is with that?
这是怎么回事？
Well, those are just bugs in programs that humans at Apple and Google and Microsoft and others, they screwed up.
这些只是 Apple、Google、Microsoft 和其他公司的人写的程序里的 bug，他们搞砸了。
And they wrote buggy code in your computer when it encounters those mistakes.
他们在你的电脑里写了有 bug 的代码，当它遇到这些错误时。
Doesn't know what to do.
它不知道该怎么办。
And so 9 times out of 10, so to speak, it just crashes or freezes or the like.
所以可以这么说，十有八九它会崩溃、死机或者类似的情况。
But that kind of stuff will make more sense.
但这类事情会变得更有意义。
So even the real world will make sense.
所以即使是现实世界也会变得有意义。
And pictured here are some lower level terms we'll eventually get to mid-semester.
图中所示的是一些较低级的术语，我们最终会在学期中期学到。
But generally speaking, when something is going this way, as per this arrow, and something is going this way, as per this arrow, that does not end well.
但总的来说，当某样东西像这个箭头一样向这个方向发展，而另一样东西像那个箭头一样向那个方向发展时，就不会有好结果。
And that often is what happens when your computer crashes.
这通常就是你的电脑崩溃时发生的情况。
Someone's using memory up here, but someone else is using memory down here.
有人在上面使用内存，但有人在下面使用内存。
And then they're not really talking left-hand and right-hand.
然后他们并没有真正地互相沟通。
So that is just a high-level overview of some of the problems we'll encounter.
这就是我们将遇到的一些问题的高级概述。
But we'll focus too on data, ultimately.
但我们最终也会关注数据。
So pictured here is something fairly technical called a hash table.
图中所示的是一种相当技术性的东西，叫做哈希表。
It's an amalgam of something we're going to soon call an array and also something we call a linked list.
它融合了我们很快就会讲到的“数组”和“链表”。
And these are just fancy terms for describing how you can organize information even more flexibly than just putting individual values in mailboxes.
这些只是描述如何组织信息的专业术语，比仅仅将单个值放入邮箱更加灵活。
Like, how could you build structures, like actual data structures, so to speak, two-dimensional structures at that?
例如，如何构建结构，比如实际的数据结构，也就是二维结构？
And so what you're seeing here is a glimpse.
你现在看到的是一个例子。
As some of you might have recognized of some Harry Potter universe names, but they're organized somewhat alphabetically.
你们中有些人可能已经认出来了，这些是哈利波特宇宙中的人物名字，它们按字母顺序排列。
And notice that any time there's multiple people with a name that starts with H, like Hermione, Harry, and Hagrid, well, they can't all fit in that mailbox if each of these squares along the left is that same mailbox.
请注意，如果左侧的每个方框都代表同一个邮箱，那么当有多个人的名字以 H 开头时，比如赫敏、哈利和海格，他们就不能都放在同一个邮箱里。
So you have to kind of chain them together.
所以你必须把它们链接在一起。
Well, you'll learn how to do that in code so that even if you get more data than you expect, if your business is booming and you're some web-based business, how do you keep adding and adding information to your software to actually keep up with it?
你会学习如何在代码中实现这一点，这样即使你得到的数据比预期多，
如果你的业务蒸蒸日上，并且你经营着某种基于网络的业务，你也能不断地向你的软件添加信息来跟上发展。
But this, again, is what code is going to soon look like, as soon as next week in week one, this here being C, but will transition in a few weeks to a more modern, higher-level language, so to speak, called Python.
同样，这就是代码很快就会有的样子，就在下周的第一周，这里使用的是 C 语言，但几周后就会过渡到更现代、更高级的语言，比如 Python。
Indeed, the course very deliberately, back in my day and now this, introduces you first to C, which, funny enough, many people don't tend to program in, certainly, every day.
事实上，这门课有意先向你介绍 C 语言，有趣的是，现在很多人都不会每天使用 C 语言编程。
I use C. Generally, September, October, November, December when teaching CS50 itself, but it's everywhere nonetheless.
我使用 C 语言。 通常在 9 月、10 月、11 月和 12 月教授 CS50 这门课时会用到，但它无处不在。
In fact, even today's other languages with which you might be familiar, like Python and Java and yet others still, you see the same primitive language underneath the hood because it's so darn fast.
事实上，即使是今天你可能熟悉的其他语言，比如 Python、Java 等等，你也会发现它们底层使用的是相同的底层语言，因为它非常快。
And as you'll learn over the coming weeks, it really gives you access to and an understanding of what's going on conceptually down here so that thereafter, after CS50, when you're writing code, you can sort of think at a very high level what's actually going on.
在接下来的几周里，你会学到，它让你能够真正理解底层概念，所以在CS50之后，当你编写代码时，你就能从一个非常高的层次思考实际发生的事情。
So in fact, in just a few weeks, what looks like this in C is going to look instead like this in Python.
事实上，几周后，C 语言中的代码将会变成 Python 中的代码。
And you'll better understand what's going on underneath the hood.
你会更好地理解底层发生了什么。
And odds are, after this class, you'll reach for a language like Python more frequently than C. But you're going to benefit from that bottom-up understanding thereof.
而且很有可能，在这门课之后，你会比 C 语言更频繁地使用 Python 这样的语言。但你将从这种自下而上的理解中受益。
Thereafter, and towards term's end, we'll introduce you to a few other ideas, like where do you put large amounts of data in things called databases, not things like spreadsheets like here,
之后，在本学期末，我们将向你介绍其他一些概念，比如如何将大量数据存储在称为数据库的东西中，不是像电子表格这样的东西，
but actual databases where using those same kinds of data structures, you lay things out in an interesting way in memory.
而是实际的数据库，在数据库中，使用相同类型的数据结构，你可以以一种有趣的方式在内存中组织数据。
Thereafter, we'll transition to a very familiar environment that you and I use every day, the web.
之后，我们将过渡到一个你我每天都在使用的非常熟悉的环境，那就是网络。
The web has become, rather, the user interface or UI that we use everywhere on the laptops, desktops, and even mobile devices nowadays.
网络已经成为我们在笔记本电脑、台式机，甚至现在的移动设备上随处可见的用户界面或 UI。
Well, pictured here is a language called HTML.
图中所示是一种叫做 HTML 的语言。
It's not a programming language.
它不是一种编程语言，
It's a markup language.
而是一种标记语言。
And some of you might have made home pages or portfolios in the past.
你们中有些人可能过去做过个人主页或作品集，
But you'll understand what's going on here.
所以你们会理解这里发生的事情。
But more powerfully, you'll understand how the computer sees that same kind of code, builds up a hierarchical family tree type structure in memory.
但更强大的是，你会明白计算机如何看待同一种代码，并在内存中构建出一种类似家族树的层次结构。
And then you can manipulate that tree with code to actually add more and more information, chat messages, anything on the screen that you like.
然后你可以用代码操作这棵树，添加越来越多的信息，聊天信息，以及任何你想在屏幕上显示的内容。
And finally, we'll tie all of this together
最后，我们会把所有这些内容联系在一起，
By introducing what are called frameworks and libraries, third party code that makes it a lot easier to solve problems of interest to you.
介绍一下所谓的框架和库，它们是第三方代码，可以让你更容易地解决你感兴趣的问题。
And so in particular here, this is the very first web app that I myself made back in like 1997.
这里展示的是我自己在 1997 年制作的第一个网络应用。
I was part of the first year intramural sports program, not as an athlete, but as the programmer.
我参加了第一年的校内体育项目，不是作为运动员，而是作为程序员。
And I was teaching myself how to build web applications.
当时我正在自学如何构建网络应用，
I only knew C and maybe a little bit of something else at the time, but this became,
我只懂 C 语言，可能还懂一点其他的，但这个项目成为了
For Harvard, at least, the very first website for the first year intramural sports program.
至少对哈佛来说，这是第一个为一年级校内体育项目设计的网站。
And it wasn't just a static website with links and images and the like. It was interactive.
它不仅仅是一个包含链接、图片等的静态网站， 而是交互式的。
You could register for sports. We could input exactly who was in a tournament bracket or the like. And it could actually automatically keep track of this data.
你可以报名参加体育运动， 我们可以输入参加比赛的选手名单等等， 它还可以自动跟踪这些数据。
So there, too, after just three months of a class like this, you'll go from writing quite simply, this week and next, hello world, to building things like this for whether it's web, mobile, or other platforms as well, if you so choose.
在学习了三个月的课程后，你将从编写简单的 "hello world" 程序，发展到为网络、移动或其他平台构建这样的应用程序，如果你愿意的话。
But we'll get you off of the course's infrastructure.
我们会让你脱离课程的基础设施。
By the end of the term, you won't be using any toy environments along the way.
到学期末，你将不再使用任何玩具环境。
We'll empower you ultimately to write code after CS50, especially if this is the only CS class you ever take on your own Mac or PC using the same software, but not the cloud-based version thereof.
我们最终将使你能够在 CS50 之后编写代码，特别是如果这是你唯一一门 CS 课程，你将能够在你自己的 Mac 或 PC 上使用相同的软件，而不是基于云的版本来编写代码。
But all of this software is itself free and can be used by you powerfully after the course's own end.
但所有这些软件本身都是免费的，你可以在课程结束后继续使用。
But along the way, as you may know, is there this tradition within the class, particularly in healthy times, of a number of events that really brings people together, not just collaboratively,
但在此过程中，你可能知道，这门课内有一个传统，特别是在条件允许的情况下，会举办一些活动，将大家聚集在一起，不仅是为了合作和学习，
but to just solve problems and generally engage with each other as well, coming up first CS50 Puzzle Day, which is meant to be not jigsaw puzzles, but logic puzzles that require no prior experience with computer science or programming, but it's just an opportunity to sort of
也是为了解决问题，并进行更广泛的互动。首先是 CS50 谜题日，它不是拼图游戏，而是逻辑谜题，不需要任何计算机科学或编程方面的经验，只是一个与朋友们一起
Quietly work on a packet of puzzles with some number of friends for prizes and more.
安静地研究一包谜题，并有机会赢取奖品。
Later in the semester, once you tackle your final projects, the capstone of the course, where we don't give you a homework to write, you yourself come up with something to build.
在本学期晚些时候，当你完成你的期末项目时，也就是课程的压轴戏，我们不会给你布置作业，而是由你自己想出一个项目来构建。
We'll get together generally around 7 PM in the evening, wrap up around 7 AM, if you so choose.
我们通常会在晚上 7 点左右聚在一起，如果你愿意的话，可以一直到早上 7 点结束。
And it's an evening, a 12-hour opportunity to collaborate with classmates on your very own final project in a large space on campus.
这是一个持续 12 小时的夜晚，你可以在校园的一个大空间里与同学们一起完成你自己的期末项目。
That ends, if you're awake with us, at 5 AM, we can hop on some CS50 shuttles and go down the road for some pancakes at IHOP around 6.
如果你和我们一样熬夜到凌晨 5 点，我们可以乘坐 CS50 班车去 IHOP 吃煎饼。
Of course, this is 6, 7 AM at that point, but it's an opportunity finally to lead into what's called the CS50 Fair, which is an end of semester celebration, an exhibition of everything that you'll accomplish over the coming months.
当然，那时已经是早上 6、7 点了，但这是一个很好的机会，
可以让你参加 CS50 展览会，这是一个学期末的庆祝活动，也是对你几个月来所取得的所有成就的展示。
And in fact, pictured here are some of your predecessors in healthy times
事实上，这里展示的是一些在条件允许的情况下举办的往届展览
The CS50 Fair allows you to come with your laptop or phone and exhibit to students, faculty, and staff across campus, put together something in person and on video that people can delight in seeing as you exhibit what it is you created and what you learned over the course of the several weeks, and ultimately, a chance to just share and inspire others as well.
在 CS50 展览会上，你可以带着你的笔记本电脑或手机，向全校的师生展示你的作品。
你可以制作一些实体的或视频的形式的作品，让人们欣赏你的创作和你在这几周的课程中学到的东西，并最终有机会分享和激励他人。
And you all walk home ultimately with your own I took CS50 t-shirts saying as much as well.
最后，你们都会拿着自己的“我参加了 CS50”的 T 恤回家。
So with that high-level overview of the course, I propose that we begin to take a look at what computer science itself is and what it is we're going to be doing over the next several weeks at this lower level than 2.
好了，在对课程进行了高层次的概述之后，我建议我们开始更深入地了解什么是计算机科学，以及我们在接下来的几周里要做什么。
So what is computer science, right?
那么，什么是计算机科学呢？
If you're maybe like me or new people like my friends in high school, you probably assume that it means programming.
如果你像我，或者像我高中时的新朋友一样，你可能会认为这意味着编程。
And that's absolutely a big part of it for a lot of people, because with code, you can write, you can express ideas and solve actual problems, especially involving data.
对很多人来说，这绝对是其中很大一部分，因为通过代码，你可以编写、表达想法并解决实际问题，尤其是涉及数据的问题。
But computer science itself is really the study of information, if you will.
但计算机科学本身实际上是对信息的学问。
How do you represent it, and how do you actually process it?
你如何表示信息，以及如何处理信息？
And in that sense, computational thinking is just the application of ideas from computer science, a course like this, to problems of interest to you, again, in the arts,
从这个意义上说，计算思维只是将计算机科学中的思想应用到你感兴趣的问题上，同样，在艺术领域，
So with that, if computer science is all about information and with it the solving of problems, well, what does it actually mean to solve a problem?
如果说计算机科学是关于信息以及用信息解决问题，那么解决问题究竟意味着什么呢？
Let's see if we can't propose a model into which all of the lessons learned will ultimately follow.
让我们看看是否可以提出一个模型，将所有学到的知识最终都融入其中。
And I propose that this.
我建议这样。
is problem solving.
这就是解决问题。
You've got some input, which is like the problem you want to solve.
你有一些输入，就像你想解决的问题。
The goal is to solve it.
目标是解决它。
So that's the so-called output.
这就是所谓的输出。
And then somewhere in here, the proverbial black box, is some kind of secret sauce that gets the work done.
在这个众所周知的黑匣子里，是某种能完成工作的秘制酱料。
And in the coming months, we'll have to decide, well, how are we going to represent these inputs and outputs?
在接下来的几个月里，我们必须决定，我们要如何表示这些输入和输出？
And really, how do we code up?
以及，我们如何编码？
How do we write solutions for what it is that's solving the problem of interest to us?
我们如何为解决我们感兴趣的问题编写解决方案？
So when it comes to representation of information, there's a lot of ways we can do this.
说到信息的表示，我们有很多方法可以做到这一点。
And for instance, if the problem at hand quite simply is to take attendance at the beginning of class on the first day of school, well, how could we go about doing this?
例如，如果眼前的问题只是在开学第一天上课开始时点名，那么，我们怎样才能做到这一点呢？
Well, we could actually use a system called unary.
我们可以使用一种叫做一进制的系统。
Well, what is that?
那是什么？
Well, that's a fancy way of saying 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, maybe 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
这是一种表示 1、2、3、4、5，也许是 6、7、8、9、10 的奇特方式。
And I can use my digits, pun intended, on my fingers to actually count everyone up.
我可以用手指上的数字来计算所有的人数。
And eventually, you need toes and whatnot if you have to count so high.
如果要数得很高，最终你需要用上脚趾什么的。
But unary is a very simple system of using a single symbol, a human finger in this case, to just solve some problem, like counting the number of people in the room.
但是，一进制是一个非常简单的系统，它使用单个符号来解决某些问题，比如计算房间里的人数。
Let's make this slightly more technical for a moment, a little more mathy.
我们稍微升级一下技术，更偏数学一点。
That's just called base 1, where the base under which you're operating has one digit in it, like literally a human finger and maybe multiple such fingers if you need to count higher.
这叫做一进制，你操作的基数只有一位数字，就像一根手指，如果要计数更大的数，可能需要多根手指。
But of course, most of you, if not all of you, generally, vaguely know that computers use something other than unary.
当然，你们大多数人，如果不是全部，大体上都知道计算机使用的不是一进制。
And even you and I probably don't use this that often.
即使是我们，也可能不经常使用它。
They use what language or alphabet instead?
它们用什么语言或字母表？
Yeah, so. Binary.
没错。 二进制。
So binary is indeed the system that computers somehow use.
二进制确实是计算机使用的系统。
So in this case, bi implying two.
“bi” 表示二。
And so computers have two digits, it turns out, at their disposal.
事实证明，计算机可以支配两位数字。
And in fact, if you've ever heard the technical term bit, which is like a smaller version of a byte, more on that soon, well, a binary digit
如果你听说过“bit”这个专业术语，它就像一个更小的字节，稍后会详细介绍，它源于二进制数字“binary digit”。
is the origin of that term bit, because if you get rid of some of the letters and are left from binary digit with just bit, thus is a bit.
因为如果去掉一些字母，从“binary digit”中只剩下“bit”。
A bit is just a 0 and 1.
bit 就是 0 和 1。
It's two more digits than you might have on your own finger.
比你一根手指上的数字多两位。
And of course, it's fewer, though, than you and I have.
当然，它比我们拥有的要少。
You and I typically use, as humans, the decimal system.
作为人类，我们通常使用十进制。
Dec meaning 10, because you and I generally use 0 through 9.
“Dec” 表示十，因为我们通常使用 0 到 9。
So on the one hand, another pun intended, you've got unary.
一方面，你有一进制。
Computers use binary.
计算机使用二进制。
We humans generally think and talk in terms of decimal.
我们人类通常用十进制思考和交谈。
But at the end of the day, these are fundamentally going to be the same thing, which is to say that it's all pretty accessible to us.
但说到底，这些本质上是一样的，也就是说，这对我们来说都很容易理解。
Even if you're not a computer person, I dare say you're about to be.
即使你不是计算机专业人士，我敢说你马上就要成为专家了。
So what is a bit?
那么什么是比特呢？
Well, a bit then is a 0 or a 1.
比特就是一个 0 或 1。
That is a so-called binary digit.
这就是所谓的二进制数字。
But how do computers only speak in binary?
但计算机如何只用二进制说话呢？
How do they solve problems, represent information using only binary?
它们如何仅使用二进制来解决问题、表示信息？
Well, at the end of the day, if they want to represent 0 and 1,
说到底，如果它们想表示 0 和 1，
We need to do so physically somehow.
我们需要以某种物理方式来实现。
And I dare say that maybe the simplest way to think about a bit, a 0 or 1, is like a light bulb.
我敢说，理解比特（0 或 1）的最简单方式可能就像电灯泡一样。
And so by human convention, let's just assume that if you are a computer, be it a laptop, desktop, phone, or the like, and you want to represent the number 0, you know what?
根据人类的约定，我们假设如果你是计算机（无论是笔记本电脑、台式机、手机还是类似设备），并且你想表示数字 0，你知道吗？
You just keep a light switch off.
你只需关闭电灯开关。
You keep a light bulb off.
保持电灯泡熄灭。
If, by contrast, you're that same computer and you want to represent the number 1, you take that same switch, that same light bulb, and just turn it on.
相反，如果你是同一台计算机，并且想表示数字 1，你就使用同一个开关、同一个灯泡，把它打开。
So a light bulb that's on represents a 1, and a light bulb that's off represents a 0.
亮着的灯泡表示 1，熄灭的灯泡表示 0。
So why is this relevant to computers?
那么，这对计算机有什么意义呢？
Well, at the end of the day, you and I are charging our laptops or phones at night.
说到底，你我晚上都在给笔记本电脑或手机充电。
So there's some physical resource being replenished there, whether you're on battery or some power cord.
所以无论你是使用电池还是电源线，都有一些物理资源在被补充。
And so inside of a computer are just thousands, millions,
在计算机内部，有成千上万个，
Of tiny little switches nowadays, you can think of them metaphorically as light bulbs, but they don't get it to actually shine light.
现在是数百万个微小的开关，你可以把它们比喻成灯泡，但它们实际上并不发光。
But there are tiny, tiny little switches.
但这里面有非常非常小的开关。
And those switches, if you've ever heard the term, are just called transistors.
这些开关，如果你听说过这个术语，就叫做晶体管。
So like computers have millions of transistors that can either be flipped on to represent ones or flipped off to represent zeros.
像计算机这样的设备，有数百万个晶体管，它们可以打开表示 1，也可以关闭表示 0。
And from that very simple mechanism, electricity is there, Or it's not.
从这个非常简单的机制来看，要么有电， 要么没电。
A 1 or a 0, computers can actually count obviously from 0 to 1, but it turns out even higher if they use a little more electricity as well.
1 或 0，很明显计算机可以从 0 数到 1，但事实证明，如果它们使用更多电力，还能数到更高。
So how might I do this?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me go ahead and propose that I just grab one of our own light bulbs here on stage.
让我拿一个舞台上的灯泡来演示一下。
This one's off.
这个灯泡现在是关着的。
So for instance, if this were miniaturized inside of your Mac, PC, or phone, this would be a transistor.
例如，如果这个灯泡被小型化到你的 Mac、PC 或手机里，它就是一个晶体管。
And indeed, here's the little switch on the bottom.
实际上，这就是底部的小开关。
And if your computer wants to represent a 0, it just leaves the switch off, and the light is not shining.
如果你的计算机想表示 0，它就让开关保持关闭状态，灯泡就不会亮。
If you want to represent a 1, well, now I've counted as high as 1, because the switch is now on.
如果你想表示 1，现在我已经数到 1 了，因为开关现在是打开的。
I've grabbed a little electricity.
我接通了一点电流。
I'm holding onto it inside of the computer.
我把电存储在计算机里。
And so now I see that this is a 1.
所以现在我看到了一个 1。
All right, but unfortunately, with just one switch, one light bulb, I can only count from 0 to 1.
但是，不幸的是，只有一个开关，一个灯泡，我只能从 0 数到 1。
How do I count out higher, might you think intuitively?
你认为如何才能数到更大的数字呢？
Say again?
再说一遍？
Yeah, so more light bulbs.
是的，用更多的灯泡。
So let me do this.
我来演示一下。
Let me just grab something to put these on so I can use a few of them at a time.
我先拿个东西把这些灯泡放上去，这样我就可以一次用好几个了。
And let me propose that here, instead of having just one light bulb, let me give myself maybe three in total.
我建议在这里，我们不只用一个灯泡，而是用三个。
So all of them are initially off.
一开始它们都是关闭的。
And if you think of this in miniature form in your mind's eye, this is like a computer with three transistors, three switches, representing now the number you and I know as 0.
如果你在脑海中想象一下这个缩小版的模型，它就像一台有三个晶体管的计算机，三个开关，现在代表着我们都知道的数字 0。
Why?
为什么？
They're just all off.
因为它们都关着。
So how does a computer go about representing the number 1?
那么计算机如何表示数字 1 呢？
Well, it turns on one of these light bulbs.
它会打开其中一个灯泡。
And how does the computer represent the number 2?
那么计算机如何表示数字 2 呢？
Well, you might think, if I may, you just turn on a second light bulb.
你可能会想，打开第二个灯泡就可以了。
And if you might think, how does a computer represent 3, you just turn on the third light bulb.
你可能还会想，计算机如何表示 3，打开第三个灯泡就行了。
And so as such, with three bits, a computer would seem to be able to count from 0 on up to 1, 2, 3.
因此，有了三个比特，计算机似乎就可以从 0 数到 1、2、3。
But it turns out, if I'm a little smarter here, I can actually count higher than that.
但事实证明，如果我再聪明一点，我实际上可以数得更高。
Why?
为什么？
Well, I'm just considering the combination of bulbs being on here.
我只是在考虑灯泡亮灭的组合。
What if I do something like this?
如果我这样做呢？
This is still 0, I will claim.
我仍然认为这是 0。
But what if I propose now that this will be how a computer represents 1?
但如果我现在假设这是计算机表示 1 的方式呢？
On, off, off.
开、关、关。
This, though, will be how the computer represents 2.
这样，计算机就能表示数字 2 了。
Notice I didn't turn on the same 2.
注意我没有打开相同的 2。
I'm just turning on the 1 in the middle.
我只是打开了中间的 1。
This, I now claim, will be how a computer represents 3.
现在我认为，计算机就是这样表示数字 3 的。
This is going to be, in just a second, how a computer represents the number we know as 4.
再过一秒钟，这将是计算机表示我们所知的数字 4 的方式。
And yet, I'm still only using three bulbs.
然而，我仍然只用了三个灯泡。
This is going to be the number the computer represents as 5.
这将是计算机表示数字 5 的方式。
This is going to be how the computer represents the number 7.
这将是计算机表示数字 7 的方式。
And then lastly, it turns out with three light bulbs, if you're smart about it, you can count.
最后，事实证明，如果足够聪明，用三个灯泡就能计数。
It seems as high as seven.
看起来最高可以数到 7。
Now, even if you kind of lost track of what I was turning on and why, I claim there were eight different patterns, from all of them off to all of them on.
现在，即使你没有完全记住我打开和关闭灯泡的原因，但我认为从全灭到全亮，一共有八种不同的模式。
But notice that I started to permute them.
但请注意，我已经开始对它们进行排列了。
I took into account which ones were on and which ones were off.
我把哪些灯泡亮着，哪些灯泡灭了都考虑进去了。
Why, though, do these represent the numbers we know as 0 through 7?
但是，为什么这些模式代表着我们所知的数字 0 到 7 呢？
Well, let me go ahead and maybe let's do this.
好吧，让我继续，也许我们可以这样做。
Instead of just considering there to be light bulbs, let's assign some special significance to each of them based on where it is.
我们不只是把它们看作灯泡，而是根据它们的位置给每个灯泡赋予一些特殊的意义。
And maybe for this, could we get?
也许为此，我们可以请……
Maybe three volunteers?
三位志愿者？
Three volunteers?
OK.
You're being volunteered.
你来啦。
OK, come on up if you want to go over to the stage there.
想上台的话就上来吧。
Yeah, you want to come on up as well, and over here as well.
你也上来吧，到这边来。
So there's some stairs on either end.
两边都有楼梯。
Maybe a round of applause for our first volunteers of term.
来点掌声，欢迎这学期的第一批志愿者。
All right, so you want to be your number one.
你想当一号。
And if you want to go ahead and stand roughly right here, how about you want to be number two?
请你站在这边，你想当二号吗？
OK, come on over to the right of here, and you'll be number four, it turns out.
到这边右边来，你就是四号了。
And if you want to come over here on this end, let's give you all a moment to introduce yourselves briefly to your classmates, if you'd like.
请你到这边来，各位同学先互相介绍一下吧。
Hi, I'm Ellie.
大家好，我是 Ellie。
I'm a senior.
我是大四的。
Nice to meet.
很高兴认识你。
I'm Rayhana, and I'm a first year.
我是 Rayhana，大一新生。
Welcome.
欢迎你。
Hi, I'm Joseph.
大家好，我是 Joseph。
I am a first year.
我是大一新生。
Welcome.
欢迎你。
All right, so glad to have all three of you up here.
很高兴你们三位能上来。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Let me propose now that we'd like you three to represent, how about the number 0?
现在请你们三位来表示数字 0。
And I claim now that if each of you now represents a switch, you have sort of fancier light bulbs now.
我现在假设你们每个人代表一个开关，你们现在有更花哨的灯泡。
One is a 1, one is a 2, one is a 4.
一个是 1，一个是 2，一个是 4。
But each of you still just has a switch on the bottom, in fact, of your plastic devices.
但你们每个人仍然只有一个开关，就在你们的塑料设备底部。
I claim these three volunteers are representing the number 0.
我认为这三位志愿者代表数字 0。
Let me ask you all now, how might you represent the number 1?
现在我问你们所有人，你们如何表示数字 1？
How should you cooperate here?
你们应该如何合作？
OK, so we would have on, off, off, which I think matches what I did with my three light bulbs as well.
好，所以应该是开、关、关，这和我用三个灯泡做的一样。
If you want to go ahead and turn yours off, how might you three represent the number two?
如果你们想继续，把你们的关掉，你们三个如何表示数字 2？
OK, so off, on, off now, from right to left, how would you three represent the number three?
好，所以现在从右到左是关、开、关，你们三个如何表示数字 3？
Ah, so that's why my two light bulbs went on at the end.
这就是为什么我的两个灯泡最后亮了。
How would you three represent the number four?
你们三个如何表示数字 4？
Perfect, number five?
很好，数字 5 呢？
Number six and number seven.
数字 6 和数字 7。
All right, and give us one more.
好的，再给我们一个。
How would you represent eight?
你们如何表示 8？
OK, you can't. How about then one more volunteer?
好的，你们能不能再请一位志愿者上来怎么样？
One more volunteer?
再一位志愿者？
OK, come on up.
好的，上来吧。
All right, what's your name?
你叫什么名字？
If you want to say it there.
如果你想说的话。
My name's Moeen.
我叫 Moeen。
All right. And Moeen, you're going to be number eight.
Moeen，你将是 8 号。
And if now you all actually let's make this, how would you represent number eight?
现在我们来实际操作一下，你们会如何表示数字 8？
All collectively as four bits or four switches.
全部用四个比特或四个开关表示。
OK, eight.
好的，8。
And now lastly, give me 15.
最后，给我 15。
Everyone's awkwardly doing arithmetic in their head.
每个人都在脑子里笨拙地做算术。
Oh, using unary.
用的是一进制。
Yeah, is everyone?
是的，每个人都是吗？
Yes, OK, round of applause.
是的，掌声鼓励。
OK, thank you all.
好的，谢谢大家。
If you want to leave your numbers over here, we have a CS50 stress ball for you.
如果你愿意把你的号码留在这里，我们有一个 CS50 解压球送给你。
But thank you for volunteering.
但还是要感谢你们的志愿服务。
You can turn those numbers off and leave them over here.
你可以把这些号码关掉，然后把它们留在这里。
So thank you.
谢谢。
So how do we go from there to creating these patterns?
那么我们如何从那里开始创建这些模式呢？
Well, even though we still had three bits initially and three switches, later four bits and four switches ultimately, we still used the same approach fundamentally to actually representing information.
尽管我们最初仍然只有三个比特和三个开关，后来是四个比特和四个开关，但我们仍然从根本上使用了相同的方法来表示信息。
And now why were they those patterns?
为什么是那些模式呢？
And why did I very deliberately have our volunteers line up in that way?
我为什么要让志愿者们特意那样排队呢？
Well, I wanted them using base 2, AKA binary.
因为我想让他们用二进制。
But with binary, there come certain rules.
但二进制有一些规则。
And even if you're not familiar with binary beyond that it exists and relates somehow to computers, it's actually pretty much identical to the system you and I use every day known as base 10, AKA decimal.
即使你对二进制的了解仅仅停留在它与计算机有关，它实际上和你我每天使用的十进制非常相似。
So let's consider, if you will, by rewinding to primary school for just a moment, like how decimal works.
让我们回到小学，回顾一下十进制是如何运作的。
And you'll see that even if you're not a computer person, you actually are.
你会发现，即使你不是计算机专家，你也能理解。
You just have to tweak your mental model ever so slightly.
你只需要稍微调整一下你的思维模式。
So here is the number that you're probably viewing as 123.
这里有一个数字，你可能把它看作 123。
But why is that?
但为什么呢？
Well, it's not really 123.
它其实不是 123。
This is just a pattern of three symbols on the screen, 1, 2, 3.
这只是屏幕上的三个符号 1、2、3 的一种排列。
And your mind is sort of rapidly assigning mathematical meaning to them, 123.
你的大脑正在快速地赋予它们数学意义，即 123。
But why is that?
但为什么呢？
Well, if you're like me, you probably learned back in the day when you have a three-digit number like this.
如果你像我一样，你可能很早以前就学过，当你有一个像这样的三位数时。
The rightmost number is in the ones place.
最右边的数字在个位。
The middle digit is the tens place.
中间的数字在十位。
The leftmost digit is in the hundreds place.
最左边的数字在百位。
And why is that relevant?
这有什么关系呢？
Well, if you then quickly do some mental math, as you and I just do instantly nowadays, that just means 100 times 1 plus 10 times 2 plus 1 times 3.
如果你快速进行心算，就像你我今天瞬间就能完成的那样，这意味着 100 × 1 + 10 × 2 + 1 × 3。
Of course, 100 plus 20 plus 3 gives us the number you and I know as 123.
当然，100 + 20 + 3 就是你我都知道的 123。
But beyond that, how do we get to just two digits instead of as many as nine in the decimal system?
但除此之外，我们如何才能只得到两位数，而不是十进制中的九位数呢？
Well, let's generalize this.
让我们概括一下。
In the decimal system, you and I know if we've got three digits represented by these hashes here, yes, it's the ones place, tens place, hundreds place.
在十进制系统中，你我都知道，如果我们有三位数用这些井号表示，没错，就是个位、十位、百位。
And if we keep going, thousands, ten thousands, and so forth.
如果我们继续下去，就是千位、万位，等等。
But why is that?
但为什么会这样呢？
Well, base terminology is now a little more germane.
基数这个术语现在更贴切了。
That's technically the 10 to the 0th column, the 10 to the 1, 10 to the 2.
从技术上讲，那是 10⁰ 列、10¹ 列、10² 列。
So these are powers of 10, where 10 is your base.
所以这些是 10 的幂，其中 10 是你的基数。
Computers just simplify things a little bit, because computers, at the end of the day, only have access to electricity on or off.
计算机只是把事情简化了一点，因为计算机最终只能处理通电或断电。
They don't have access to, like, 10 different types of electricity, just two on or off, if you will.
它们无法处理 10 种不同类型的电流，如果你愿意的话，只有两种，开或关。
Well, they just use a different base.
它们只是使用不同的基数。
And the rightmost digit would be in the so-called 2 to the 0's.
最右边的数字将在所谓的 2⁰ 位。
Then the middle digit is 2 to the 1.
中间的数字是 2¹。
The leftmost is 2 to the 2, a.k.a. 1's place, 2's place, 4's place.
最左边的是 2²，也就是个位、二位、四位。
And as we kept going, 8.
如果我们继续下去，就是 8。
And if we keep going, 16, 32, 64, 128, and so forth.
如果我们继续下去，就是 16、32、64、128，等等。
But the idea is fundamentally the same.
但原理基本相同。
So why is this how?
那么为什么会这样呢？
The computer represents the number you and I know is 0.
计算机将你我都知道的数字 0 表示出来。
Well, off, off, off from right to left, or in this case, left to right, is just 0.
从右到左，或者现在这样说，从左到右，关闭，关闭，关闭，就是 0。
Why?
为什么？
Because that's 4 times 0 plus 2 times 0 plus 1 times 0 is, of course, 0.
因为 4 乘以 0 加上 2 乘以 0 加上 1 乘以 0 当然是 0。
This is why.
这就是原因。
001 represents 1.
001 代表 1。
This is why 010 represents 2 and 3 and 4 and 5 and 6 and 7 on up.
这就是为什么 010 代表 2，3，4，5，6，7 等等。
And why did we need a fourth bit to represent 8?
那为什么我们需要第四个比特来表示 8 呢？
Well, we kind of needed to carry the 1, so to speak, using our familiar human terminology.
用我们熟悉的人类术语来说，我们有点需要进位 1。
But for that, we need a fourth bit, another transistor.
但为此，我们需要第四个比特，另一个晶体管。
And this now represents the number 8.
现在它代表数字 8。
And that's why we ended with on, from left to right, off, off, off.
这就是为什么我们最终从左到右是开，关，关，关。
So I keep saying on and off, or the light bulb is on or off.
所以我一直说开和关，或者灯泡是开着还是关着。
But really, I just mean one or zero.
但实际上，我只是指 1 或 0。
And so computers and we humans think of things digitally as just being zeros and ones.
所以计算机和我们人类认为数字化的东西就是 0 和 1。
But mechanically, you can think of it, indeed, as these light bulbs.
但从机械角度来看，你可以把它想象成这些灯泡。
Now, a bit is not very useful.
现在，一个比特不是很实用。
Even three bits, four bits, not that useful.
即使是三个比特，四个比特，也不是那么有用。
You can count to seven or 15.
你只能数到 7 或 15。
Generally speaking, bytes are a more useful unit of measure.
一般来说，字节是一个更有用的度量单位。
And anyone familiar how many bits is in a byte?
有谁知道一个字节有多少比特吗？
Yeah, so 8 bits are in a byte.
8 位组成 1 个字节。
You can think of it as an octet equivalently.
你可以把它看作一个八位字节。
In some contexts, there are nuances there.
在某些情况下，两者之间存在细微差别。
But think of a byte as just being 8 bits.
但可以将字节理解为 8 位。
And that's just a more useful measure.
这是一个更有用的度量单位。
So what does this mean in real terms?
那么这实际上意味着什么呢？
Well, if you've ever downloaded a music file or a photograph or a video, those are measured in bytes, probably not small numbers of bytes, probably kilobytes for thousands of bytes, megabytes for millions of bytes, gigabytes for billions of bytes, especially for video.
如果你下载过音乐文件、照片或视频，它们的大小都是以字节为单位的，可能不是少量字节，
可能是千字节（KB，代表数千字节）、兆字节（MB，代表数百万字节）、千兆字节（GB，代表数十亿字节），尤其是视频。
That just means you have a lot.
这仅仅意味着你有很多数据。
of patterns of 8 bits, some combination of 0's and 1's on your computer's hard drive.
计算机硬盘驱动器上由 8 位模式（0 和 1 的某种组合）组成的数据。
Here then, with a byte of bits, 8 bits is how a computer would typically represent the number 0.
这里，用一个字节（8 位）来表示数字 0，这就是计算机的典型做法。
And if that same computer uses all 8 of its bits, its full byte to change it to 1, anyone who's quick with math or have seen this before, how high can a computer count with 8 bits or 1?
如果同一台计算机使用全部 8 位（即完整的一个字节）来表示数字 1，
对于那些数学计算快或者以前见过这种情况的人来说，使用 8 位或 1 个字节，计算机最大可以计数到多少？
Yeah, 255. Why is that?
是 255。 为什么呢？
Well, we're not going to turn this into a constant math exercise.
我们不会把它变成一个持续的数学练习。
Indeed, after today, we're not really going to think about or talk about bits at this low level.
实际上，今天之后，我们不会再考虑或讨论这种低级别的位。
But this is the ones place, twos, fours, eight, 16, 32, 64, 128.
但这是个位、2位、4位、8位、16位、32位、64位、128位。
And if I do all of that math from left to right, that indeed gives me 255.
如果我从左到右进行所有这些数学计算，结果确实是 255。
It ignores how we might represent negative numbers, but perhaps more on those some other day.
这忽略了我们如何表示负数，但也许改天再讨论这个问题。
But computers, of course, do so much more than numbers and math and all this low-level stuff.
当然，计算机的功能远不止数字、数学和所有这些底层的东西。
We send text messages, write documents, emails, and the like.
我们可以发送短信、编写文档、电子邮件等等。
So how might a computer represent something like the letter A?
那么计算机如何表示字母 A 呢？
I claim, at the end of the day, your Mac, your PC, your phone just has lots of transistors, lots of switches that it can use in units of 8, in units of bytes.
我认为，归根结底，你的 Mac、PC、手机都只有大量的晶体管，大量的开关，它们可以使用 8 个一组的单位，也就是字节来表示。
How, though, if it's already using those patterns of 0's and 1's apparently to represent numbers from 0 on up, how do you go about representing letters of the alphabet, might you think?
但是，如果它已经在用 0 和 1 的模式来表示从 0 开始的数字，那你觉得它如何表示字母表中的字母呢？
Yeah.
OK, so we could assign a number to every letter.
我们可以给每个字母分配一个数字。
OK, so let me just conjecture.
让我来推测一下。
Well, let's just call a 0 for simplicity, b 1, c 2.
为了简单起见，我们称 A 为 0，b 为 1，c 为 2。
And now let me play devil's advocate.
现在让我来唱个反调。
OK, how do I now represent 0 or 1 or 2?
那我该如何表示 0、1 或 2 呢？
Well, we've maybe created a problem for ourselves if now we have to steal some numbers to represent letters.
如果我们现在必须“偷”一些数字来表示字母，那我们可能给自己制造了一个问题。
We kind of have to pick a lane.
我们得选定一个方案。
But there's a solution to that too that we'll see.
但我们一会儿会看到，这个问题也是有解决办法的。
And it turns out.
事实证明。
And the world is not quite as simple as a being 0. a typically is represented by computers everywhere, phones everywhere, with the number 65, the decimal number 65.
世界并不像 A 是 0 那么简单。A 通常在世界各地的计算机和手机中，都用十进制数 65 来表示。
Using 8 bits, if we turn some of the zeros to ones, let me just stipulate, you can represent the letter a using 8 bits by turning certain ones on and certain ones off.
使用 8 个比特，如果我们将一些 0 变成 1，我直接说吧，你可以通过打开和关闭某些比特来用 8 个比特表示字母 A。
But we will try not to focus on that binary level too much.
但我们会尽量不去过多关注二进制层面。
So if a is 65, it turns out that b is going to be 66, and c is going to be 67, and so forth.
如果 A 是 65，那么 B 就是 66，C 就是 67，以此类推。
And so where does that get us?
那这会让我们得到什么呢？
Well, it turns out there's a whole system that maps numbers to letters.
事实证明，有一个完整的系统将数字映射到字母。
And here, as I alluded to verbally a moment ago, is the pattern of 0's and 1's via which you'd represent 65.
就像我刚才口头上提到的，这里就是 65 的 0 和 1 的表示模式。
And just quick check here, we won't constantly do math.
我们不会一直计算。
1's place, that's easy.
个位，这很简单。
2's, 4's, 8's, 16, 32, 64's place, so 64.
2、4、8、16、32、64 位，所以是 64。
Plus 1 gives us 65.
64 + 1 = 65。
So once I do that, how do I get to all of the others?
那么我这样做之后，如何得到其他的字母呢？
Well, it turns out a bunch of Americans years ago came up with this, ASCII, the American Standard Code for Information Interchange.
事实证明，多年前一群美国人发明了 ASCII，美国信息交换标准代码。
Now, what does that mean?
这是什么意思呢？
Well, it's just an acronym describing what really you proposed, a mapping between numbers and letters.
它只是一个首字母缩略词，描述了你提出的内容，即数字和字母之间的映射关系。
Not quite as simple as 0, 1, 2.
并不像 0、1、2 那么简单。
Starts at 65, 66, 67 for capital letters.
大写字母从 65、66、67 开始。
But here are most of the letters in use today, at least with this system.
但这里至少在这个系统中是今天使用的大多数字母。
So this is just a big chart from online.
所以这只是一张从网上找到的大图表。
And you'll see it in the middle of this chart here.
你会在这张图表的中间看到它。
Here's my 65A.
这是我的 65A。
Here's my 66B, C. And let's see, 72 is H.
这是我的 66B，C。让我们看看，72 是 H。
73 is I, and so forth.
73 是 I，以此类推。
So there's a mapping, at least for English, between all of these numbers and all of these letters.
所以至少对于英语来说，所有这些数字和所有这些字母之间都存在映射关系。
And if we focus here, those are the beginning of our uppercase alphabet.
如果我们关注这里，这些是我们大写字母表的开头。
So suppose, then, that today, tomorrow, you receive a text message from someone.
假设今天或明天，你收到了某人发来的一条短信。
And underneath the hood, now that you're a computer person, you figure out a way to see what pattern of zeros and ones was sent.
作为一名计算机人士，你找到了查看发送的 0 和 1 模式的方法。
In this case, it's wireless as opposed to wired.
这种情况下用的是无线传输，而不是有线传输。
But it's still some pattern of zeros and ones.
但它仍然是用 0 和 1 的某种模式来表示的。
And your phone is turning some switches of its own on and off to represent that message from a friend.
你的手机也会打开和关闭它自己的一些开关，来代表来自朋友的信息。
Suppose that the three patterns you received were these three bytes from left to right, spelling out a three-letter word.
假设你收到的这三个模式是从左到右的三个字节，拼出一个三个字母的单词。
Well, if we do out the math, ones place, twos place, and so forth, I'll spoil it for you.
如果我们计算一下，个位、二进制位等等，我就直接告诉你答案吧。
Suppose that you received a text message that doesn't literally say 72, 73, 33, but you received a pattern of 8 plus 8 plus 8, 24 bits that, if you do out the math, represent the decimal number 72, 73, 33.
假设你收到一条短信，它不是直接显示 72、73、33，而是收到 8 加 8 加 8，24 位的模式，如果你计算一下，就代表十进制数 72、73、33。
Anyone recall what message you might have received from the green and white chart?
有人记得从绿色和白色图表中你可能收到了什么信息吗？
Yeah?
什么？
Hi.
Hi!。
But yes, hi is the message.
没错，信息是 HI!。
But 72, 73 gives us h and i. What's 33?
72、73 表示 H 和 I。那 33 呢？
Any guesses to 33?
有人猜到 33 是什么吗？
Yeah, over here?
这边？
Yeah, so it's an exclamation point.
对，是感叹号。
How would you know that?
你怎么知道的？
Well, you really do need some kind of cheat sheet, a.k.a. ASCII in this case.
你需要某种备忘单，在这种情况下是 ASCII。
And if we look elsewhere, let me highlight the left of the chart, you can see that next to 33 in decimal is indeed the exclamation point.
如果我们看看其他地方，我来高亮显示一下图表的左边，你可以看到十进制的 33 旁边确实是感叹号。
So back in the day, a bunch of humans got in a room, decided that, hey, when we start building PCs and later Macs and phones, we all just have to agree on this form of representation
所以那时候，一群人聚在一个房间里决定，当我们开始制造 PC，以及后来的 Mac 和手机时，我们都必须同意这种表示形式。
of letters of the English alphabet in this case.
在这种情况下，是用英文字母来表示。
We just need to agree on this mapping.
我们只需要在映射关系上达成一致。
But somewhat curiously, notice this.
但奇怪的是，注意这一点。
It turns out that once you paint yourself into this corner and start using 65 for A, 66 for B, well, how do you represent 65 the number and 66 the number if you want to do math or use Excel or something like that?
如果你决定用 65 表示 A，66 表示 B，那么问题来了，如果你想进行数学运算、使用 Excel 或类似的东西，你要如何表示数字 65 和 66 呢？
Does anyone kind of see the solution, perhaps?
有人知道解决方案吗？
How do you represent the number 1 in ASCII?
如何在 ASCII 中表示数字 1？
Yeah, in the middle?
在中间？
Yeah, so this is getting a little, maybe, inception or something.
这有点像盗梦空间。
But you could represent numbers with other numbers.
但你可以用数字来表示数字。
And so if you want to represent the number you and I know as 1, like when you type it on your keyboard, turns out the computer stores that as the decimal number 49.
所以你想表示的数字 1，就像你在键盘上输入的那样，实际上计算机存储的是十进制数 49。
If you hit 2 on your keyboard, the computer's not storing 2 per se.
如果你在键盘上按 2，计算机存储的不是 2。
It's storing the decimal number 50.
它存储的是十进制数 50。
Now, thankfully, the
现在，值得庆幸的是，
The paradox kind of stops there.
这种悖论到此为止。
We just have a mapping now of numbers to numbers.
我们现在只是建立了数字到数字的映射关系。
But really, at the end of the day, and you're going to learn this when we start writing code in that other language C next week, it's just context dependent at the end of the day.
但实际上，归根结底，下周我们开始用 C 语言编写代码时就会明白，这最终取决于上下文。
Inside of your Mac, PC, and phone, there's just all of these permutations of bits, all of these patterns of zeros and ones.
在 Mac、PC 和手机内部，都只是比特的不同排列，0 和 1 的不同模式。
And generally speaking, when you open up a text message,
一般来说，当你打开短信时，
That you've received from someone, it's zeros and ones.
你收到的信息也是 0 和 1。
But obviously, if it's a text message, the whole point of text messages is to send text.
但显然，如果是短信，那么短信的意义就是发送文本。
And so those patterns of zeros and ones, by default, will typically be interpreted as letters of the alphabet.
所以这些 0 和 1 的模式，默认情况下，通常会被解释为字母表中的字母。
So you won't see zeros and ones.
你不会看到 0 和 1。
You won't see decimal numbers.
也不会看到小数。
You'll see the English message that your friend intended.
你会看到朋友想表达的英文信息。
By contrast, if you open up something like Excel,
相反，如果你打开 Excel 之类的软件，
That same pattern of 0's and 1's might indeed work out to be 72, 73, 33.
相同的 0 和 1 的模式可能会是 72、73、33。
You might see cells in your spreadsheet with literally those three numbers.
你可能会在电子表格的单元格中看到这三个数字。
Why?
为什么？
Because spreadsheets are all about numbers and number crunching and math in many cases.
因为电子表格都是关于数字、数字运算以及很多情况下的数学。
If by contrast, you open up Photoshop.
相反，如果你打开 Photoshop，
And try to look at that same pattern of zeros and ones.
并尝试查看相同的 0 和 1 的模式，
It's not going to be 72, 73, 33.
它不会是 72、73、33。
It's not going to be zeros and ones.
它不会是 0 和 1。
It's not going to be high.
也不会是高。
It's going to be some color of the rainbow.
它会是彩虹的颜色。
You're going to use those patterns of zeros and ones, it turns out, too, to represent colors.
事实证明，你会使用这些 0 和 1 的模式来表示颜色。
And indeed, so long as you and I just agree, as humans long have, what these patterns are going to be, all of our systems, many of our systems nowadays, are indeed interoperable.
事实上，只要你和我，像人类长期以来那样，就这些模式达成一致，我们所有的系统，现在很多系统，确实是可互操作的。
But I'm being very biased here.
但我在这里有很大的偏见。
And indeed, the A in ASCII is very American-centric.
实际上，ASCII 中的 A 是以美国为中心的。
What do you not see in this chart?
你在这个图表中看不到什么？
If you speak any other language than English, odds are you're not seeing characters you know and love and need every day to type or send messages.
如果你说的不是英语，很有可能你没有看到你每天都知道、喜欢以及需要用来打字或发送信息的字符。
Well, there's a huge character set that's not supported here, whether it's accented characters and a lot of Asian alphabets.
这里不支持很多字符集，包括带重音符号的字符和很多亚洲语言的字母。
You have many more symbols than can fit even on this screen here.
符号太多，连这个屏幕都放不下。
And so humans kind of painted themselves into a corner early on, or really, Americans did.
人类很早就把自己逼到死胡同了，或者更准确地说，是美国人把自己逼到死胡同了。
But on a typical keyboard, US English keyboard, yeah, you have A's and B's and C's, uppercase and lowercase.
在一个典型的键盘上，比如美式英语键盘，有 A、B、C 等等，有大写和小写。
But you also have accented characters here.
但也有带重音符号的字符。
And nowadays, not sure if this is maybe necessary, but nowadays you have other characters on your keyboard like these.
现在，虽然不确定是否有必要，但键盘上还有其他字符，比如这些。
And these are kind of a playful incarnation of what's actually a technical solution to this problem.
这些字符很有趣，实际上是解决这个问题的技术方案的化身。
If I claim for the moment that ASCII historically used 7 bits to represent letters, and let's just round that up to a byte, 8 bits to represent letters.
如果说 ASCII 过去使用 7 个比特来表示字母，我们将其四舍五入为一个字节，即 8 个比特。
ASCII can represent as many as 255 or really 256 total characters.
ASCII 最多可以表示 255 或 256 个字符。
Why 256?
为什么是 256？
Well, if you have them all 0, that's 0.
因为如果所有位都是 0，那就是 0。
And the highest number I claimed a moment ago was 255.
我刚才说过的最大数字是 255。
So that's 256 total possibilities.
所以总共有 256 种可能性。
That's not many letters.
这并不多。
It's fine for English, but not a lot of human languages.
对英语来说够了，但对很多其他语言来说不够。
So what might the intuitive solution be if you want to represent accented characters, Asian characters, emoji, even like these, which are just keys on a keyboard nowadays?
那么，如果想表示带重音符号的字符、亚洲字符、表情符号，甚至像这些现在键盘上的按键，直观的解决方案是什么？
What's the intuitive solution if a byte's too few?
如果一个字节不够，直观的解决方案是什么？
Yeah, so add another digit.
增加一位。
Just like we had a fourth volunteer come on up to give us a fourth bit, let's just throw hardware at the problem and use a few more bits.
就像我们请第四位志愿者上来给我们第四个比特一样，我们直接用硬件解决这个问题，多用几位。
So maybe instead of one byte, let's use two.
也许我们不再使用 1 个字节，而是使用 2 个字节。
Or heck, let's use three or four bytes, even though it's getting a little expensive.
或者，使用 3 个或 4 个字节，即使这样成本有点高。
We're going from 8 to 16 to 24 or 32 bits.
我们从 8 位、16 位、24 位到 32 位。
That's how computers do things these days.
这就是现在计算机的处理方式。
And thankfully, we have so much memory inside of our computers and phones, we can certainly spare a few to represent these things.
值得庆幸的是，我们的电脑和手机中有如此多的内存，我们当然可以匀出一些来表示这些内容。
And the solution then to ASCII is what we'll call Unicode.
ASCII 的解决方案就是我们所说的 Unicode。
So Unicode is also just a mapping of numbers to letters, but in many different languages.
Unicode 也是数字到字母的映射，但它支持许多不同的语言。
And indeed, the Unicode Consortium is a bunch of people from all different companies and a lot of different companies and countries and cultures whose mission as an organization is to capture digitally
Unicode 联盟是由来自不同公司、国家和文化的人们组成的一个团体，他们的使命是用数字方式捕捉
All forms of human language in this case.
所有形式的人类语言。
And to ensure that especially smaller demographics of humans speaking lesser known languages are nonetheless represented and preserved digitally using some mapping of these zeros and ones.
并确保即使是使用较少为人知的语言的人群也能以数字方式表示和保存，使用 0 和 1 的某种映射。
It turns out, though, if you start using 32 bits, as many as 32 bits to represent characters on a keyboard, that's 4 billion possible permutations of zeros and ones.
但事实证明，如果开始使用 32 位来表示键盘上的字符，那就是 40 亿种 0 和 1 的可能排列。
That's way more than we need for most human languages.
这远远超过了我们对大多数人类语言的需求。
There's a little bit of room in there for some of those more playful things, like those emoji.
其中还有一些空间可以用来表示一些更有意思的东西，比如 emoji。
So for instance, suppose you got a text message with this pattern of 0's and 1's.
例如，假设你收到了一条包含这种 0 和 1 模式的短信。
Or if we do out the math, suppose you receive a text message that if you do out the math, in decimal is 4,036,991,106.
或者，假设你收到一条短信，经过计算，它的十进制表示是 4,036,991,106。
Anyone know what emoji you're looking at?
有人知道这是什么 emoji 吗？
This would be weird if you do, but.
如果知道的话，那就奇怪了。
What is this?
这是什么？
Well, it turns out that, as of this past year, this is the most popular emoji to be sent by many measures, face with tears of joy.
事实证明，截至去年，这是使用最多的 emoji，是“喜极而泣”的表情。
So that is the pattern that a bunch of humans in the Unicode Consortium decided would represent this.
Unicode 联盟中的一群人决定用这种模式来表示它。
But you'll notice many of you might have iPhones.
但你们可能注意到了，很多人用的是 iPhone。
Some of you might have Android devices, too.
有些人可能也在使用 Android 设备。
And sometimes these don't actually look quite the same.
有时它们看起来不太一样。
This happens to be the current version.
这是当前版本。
of face with tears of joy on iOS.
iOS 上“喜极而泣”的表情符号。
On Android, it tends to look a little something more like this.
在 Android 上，它看起来更像这样。
And here's kind of a curiosity.
这里有一个有趣的事实。
Even though you and I look at these things and they look like images, they're not images.
即使你我看着这些东西，它们看起来像图像，但它们不是图像。
They're characters, at least as we've defined them now in Unicode.
它们是字符，至少在我们现在对 Unicode 的定义中是这样。
And iOS and Android and Windows and Facebook and other companies and apps nowadays
如今，iOS、Android、Windows、Facebook 和其他公司和应用程序
Do you really just have different fonts, if you will?
真的只是使用了不同的字体，可以这么说吗？
So just like fonts with English and other languages can give you different characters with serifs or not, emoji are themselves, yes, drawings that someone made, but they're really just a font.
就像英语和其他语言的字体可以给你提供带或不带衬线的不同字符一样，表情符号本身就是有人绘制的图画，但它们实际上只是一种字体。
And so that same pattern of zeros and ones might just render slightly differently on someone's phone or another.
同样的 0 和 1 的模式可能在不同人的手机上渲染出来略有不同。
If you've ever gotten an icon on your phone that's broken,
如果你曾经在手机上看到过一个损坏的图标，
And you've been sent an emoji, but it's like a square or something arbitrary and not sensible.
你收到一个表情符号，但它像一个方块或其他任意的、无意义的东西。
It might just mean that you have not updated to the latest version of iOS or Android, which just updates the font of supported emoji.
这可能只是意味着你没有更新到最新版本的 iOS 或 Android，这些版本更新了支持表情符号的字体。
Because those folks at Unicode pretty much every year nowadays are adding more and more emoji to that particular character set.
因为 Unicode 的那些人现在几乎每年都在为特定的字符集添加越来越多的表情符号。
Now, I went down the rabbit hole figuring out the other day just which are the most popular emoji these days.
前几天，我深入研究了一下，想弄清楚最近哪些表情符号最受欢迎。
On Twitter specifically this past year, the most popular emoji, by contrast, Was loudly crying face.
相比之下，在过去的一年里，Twitter 上最受欢迎的表情符号是 “放声大哭”的表情。
I don't know if that says more about 2021 or about Twitter, but you'll see different trends certainly in how these are used.
我不知道这更能说明 2021 年还是 Twitter，但你会看到它们在使用方式上的不同趋势。
But even humans themselves didn't necessarily think two steps ahead.
但即使是人类本身也不一定有提前两步思考。
And now a lot of the emoji are the sort of default yellow color, but there's a lot of emoji that aren't sort of these cartoon characters, but they're meant to represent humans and various professions or gestures or the like.
现在很多 emoji 都是默认的黄色，但也有很多 emoji 不是卡通人物，而是代表人类和各种职业、手势等等。
And nowadays, too, you've probably noticed on your phone
如今，你可能也在手机上注意到了
And Macs and PCs, there are different skin tones that you can assign to certain emojis.
在 Mac 和 PC 上，你可以为某些 emoji 分配不同的肤色。
If it's supported by the company and by Unicode, you can actually touch and hold on a certain emoji.
如果公司和 Unicode 支持，你实际上可以触摸并按住某个 emoji。
And then you can choose the appropriate skin tone to represent yourself or someone else.
然后你可以选择合适的肤色来代表你自己或其他人。
And that then modifies the display.
然后就会修改显示内容。
Well, let's just think for a moment here, how did Apple and Google and Microsoft and others go about implementing support for emoji with different skin tones?
我们来想一想，Apple、Google、Microsoft 和其他公司是如何实现对不同肤色 emoji 的支持的？
How could you do this?
你怎么做呢？
If you want to represent some smiling emoji, but in five, in this case, different skin tones, you could come up with, what, five different patterns that are identical structurally, except for the skin tone used in places in that image.
如果你想表示一个微笑的 emoji，但要用五种不同的肤色，你可以想出五个不同的图案，它们的结构完全相同，只是图像中使用的肤色不同。
But that's a little inefficient, right, to kind of just do copy, paste, paste, paste, paste, and change the color in Photoshop, if you will.
但这有点低效，对吧，就像复制、粘贴、粘贴、粘贴、粘贴，然后在 Photoshop 中改变颜色一样。
That's going to use more bits, more information than you might need to.
这将使用比你可能需要的更多的比特，更多的信息。
How else, if you now start to think a little bit more like a computer scientist, if at the end of the day, all you have are 0's and 1's, how else could you implement skin tones, might you think?
如果你现在开始像计算机科学家一样思考，如果你最终只有 0 和 1，你还能如何实现肤色呢？
OK, so RGB, we'll come to that in just a moment.
RGB，我们稍后会讲到。
That stands for red, green, blue. That's one way.
它代表红、绿、蓝。 这是一种方法。
In this case, though, I'm seeking an alternative to just using five different patterns of 0's and 1's to represent the same emoji, but different skin tones.
但在这种情况下，我正在寻找一种替代方法，而不是仅仅使用五种不同的 0 和 1 的模式来表示相同的 emoji，但肤色不同。
So not quite RGB.
所以不完全是 RGB。
Yeah?
是吗？
OK, so store one copy of the emoji, and then store different variants of the color that you want to assign to that emoji.
好，存储一份表情符号副本，然后存储要分配给该表情符号的不同颜色变体。
Yeah, so this is actually an example of, do you want to elaborate?
这实际上是一个例子，你想详细说明一下吗？
OK, so you can use a loop to actually output these things.
好，你可以使用循环来实际输出这些东西。
More on that in a moment.
稍后会详细介绍。
Let me go down this road for just a moment.
让我先沿着这条路走下去。
This would be, in some sense, sort of a better design, if you will.
从某种意义上说，这将是一个更好的设计。
But why?
但为什么呢？
Yeah?
是吗？
OK, so filter, if we think sort of the Instagram sense, you can sort of change the color of something.
好，过滤器，如果我们从 Instagram 的角度来思考，你可以改变某样的颜色。
And that could be related here, too.
这在这里也可能是相关的。
Oh, interesting.
有意思。
So maybe it could be just a completely different font.
所以也许它可以是完全不同的字体。
And you have five different fonts that are almost identical, except for the various interpretations of skin tone for those same emoji.
你有五种几乎相同的字体，除了对相同的 emoji 有不同的肤色解释。
Let me spoil.
让我来揭晓答案。
I think if we go down this one particular road, the way the Unicode folks decided to do this some years ago were the first
我认为如果我们沿着这条路走下去，Unicode 的开发者们几年前决定这样做的方式是第一个
A byte or bytes that you receive via text or email just represent the structure of the emoji, the default yellow version thereof.
你通过短信或电子邮件收到的一个或多个字节只代表表情符号的结构，即默认的黄色版本。
But if it's immediately followed by a certain pattern of bits that these humans standardized to represent each of these different shades of skin tone, then the phone, the Mac, the PC will change that default color, yellow in most cases, to whatever the more apt human tone is.
但如果紧随其后的是这些人标准化的一定模式的比特位，
用来表示每一种不同的肤色，那么手机、Mac、PC 就会把默认的颜色（大多数情况下是黄色）改成更合适的肤色。
So you just use twice as many bits, but you don't use five times as many bits.
所以你只使用了原有两倍的比特位，而不是五倍的比特位。
So what do I mean?
我的意思是？
You don't have five completely distinct patterns per se.
本身并没有五个完全不同的图案。
For each of these possible variants, you have a representation of just the emoji itself structurally, and then reusable patterns for those five skin tones.
对于这些可能的变体，每个表情符号本身都有一个结构表示，然后是五种肤色的可重复使用图案。
Unfortunately, that wasn't quite versatile enough for other features that were in the pipeline.
不幸的是，这对于计划中的其他功能来说还不够通用。
And nowadays, too, and there's a double meaning now to representation, emojis intended to focus on certain professions.
如今，表示方式有了双重含义，表情符号旨在关注某些职业。
And early on, too, were certain professions associated with certain genders and vice versa.
而且在早期，某些职业与某些性别相关联，反之亦然。
And you couldn't necessarily be one gender or another in a certain profession or another.
你不可能在某个职业中是某种性别，或者反过来。
There were these combinatorics that just weren't possible.
这些组合是不可能的。
Nowadays, as you might have seen, you can have couples in love, for instance, that actually look a little more like three emojis, but just kind of combined into one.
如今，你可能已经见过，你可以拥有恋爱中的情侣，例如，它们实际上看起来更像是三个表情符号，但只是组合成一个。
And indeed, this is just one key press on your phone.
实际上，这只是手机上的一个按键。
And you can combine different emoji on the left and on the right with an emoji in the middle.
你可以将左侧和右侧的不同表情符号与中间的表情符号组合起来。
And so it turns out how computers nowadays represent these patterns.
事实证明，如今计算机是如何表示这些图案的。
Are one set of bits for the character on the left, one set of bits for a character on the right, one set of bits for whatever emoji you want in the middle, and then you assemble more complicated compositions of emoji by just reusing those same patterns and bits and bits.
左侧字符使用一组比特位，右侧字符使用一组比特位，
中间任何想要的表情符号使用一组比特位，然后通过重复使用相同的图案、比特位和比特位来组合更复杂的表情符号。
Emoji doesn't, the Unicode folks don't have to come up with a whole new representation for some very specific incarnation.
Unicode 的人们不必为某些非常具体的化身想出一个全新的表示方式。
They can create one for person, for male, for female, for other characters that you might want to display and reuse those same patterns of zeros and ones.
他们可以为人物、男性、女性以及你可能想要显示的其他字符创建一个，并重复使用相同的零一模式。
And so here you see sort of the imperfection of or lack of foresight of humans for building a system early on that was entirely American-centric, no characters, emoji or the like, that's evolved to.
所以你可以看到，人类早期构建一个完全以美国为中心的系统的缺陷或缺乏远见，没有字符、表情符号或类似的东西演变而来。
And so that's an important detail in computing nowadays.
这是当今计算中的一个重要细节。
It, too, is evolving.
它也在不断发展。
And the languages you're about to learn in the coming days, those, too, are evolving as well.
你在未来几天将要学习的语言，也都在不断发展。
And new features are getting added.
并且正在添加新功能。
And even programming languages have version numbers.
甚至编程语言也有版本号。
You might have a different version of an app on your phone.
你的手机上可能安装了不同版本的应用程序。
Programming languages, too, have different versions as well.
编程语言也有不同的版本。
Questions then thus far on how information is represented using ASCII or Unicode or anything in between, yeah.
目前为止，关于如何使用 ASCII 或 Unicode 或介于两者之间的任何编码来表示信息，大家还有什么疑问吗？
A good question.
问得好。
So to recap, why can't you just, well, let me summarize that as, why can't you similarly use different patterns to change the context of what these patterns of bits represent, whether it's a number or a letter or a graphic?
总结一下，为什么不能用不同的模式来改变这些比特模式所代表的上下文呢？无论它是数字、字母还是图形？
In actuality, that's kind of what's happening underneath the hood.
实际上，这与底层的运作方式很像。
It's not standardized in quite the same way.
只是它没有以完全相同的方式标准化。
But starting next week when we transition from scratch to C, you'll learn about types, data types, where the onus initially is going to be on you,
但从下周开始，当我们从 Scratch 过渡到 C 语言时，你将学习到类型，也就是数据类型。最初你需要负责，
The programmer to tell the program whether or not this pattern of bits should be interpreted as a number or as a letter or as a color or something else.
作为程序员，你需要告诉程序，这个比特模式应该被解释为数字、字母、颜色还是其他东西。
Nowadays, though, and toward the end of the semester, you'll use languages like Python, where the computer just figures it out for you by context, which makes it even easier and faster to program as well.
不过，现在，以及到学期末，你将使用 Python 这样的语言。计算机可以通过上下文自行判断，这使得编程变得更加容易和快捷。
Other questions on Unicode, ASCII, or the like?
关于 Unicode、ASCII 或类似的编码，还有其他问题吗？
All right, well, how about just a few other forms of information?
那么，我们来看看其他几种信息形式。
RGB was called out earlier, red, green, blue.
前面提到的 RGB，也就是红、绿、蓝。
How do images get represented in computers?
图像在计算机中是如何表示的？
Well, in fact, it's typically an assembly of some amount of red, some amount of green, some amount of blue.
实际上，它通常是由一定量的红色、一定量的绿色和一定量的蓝色组合而成的。
But there are other representations.
但还有其他的表示方法。
If you're a graphic designer, you might know them.
如果你是一名图形设计师，你可能知道。
But RGB is still pretty common.
但 RGB 仍然很常见。
What does this mean?
这意味着什么？
This means to represent every dot on your phone or every dot on your TV or your laptop or desktop, there is a number representing how much red that dot should show, a number representing how much green, and a number representing how much blue it should show, red, green, blue, respectively.
这意味着，要表示手机、电视、笔记本电脑或台式机上的每一个点，
都需要一个数字来表示该点应该显示多少红色、多少绿色和多少蓝色，分别对应红、绿、蓝三种颜色。
So for instance, if a dot on your screen were using these three numbers, these three values or bytes, 72, 73, 33,
例如，如果屏幕上的一个点使用这三个数字，这三个值或字节，72、73、33，
In a text message or email, that would be interpreted as, I claimed, high.
在短信或电子邮件中，它会被解释为，我声称，high。
But in Photoshop or in some graphical program, that same pattern would be interpreted as, let's call it a medium amount of red, a medium amount of green, and a little bit of blue.
但是在 Photoshop 或一些图形程序中，相同的模式会被解释为，我们称之为中等程度的红色，中等程度的绿色和一点蓝色。
And why medium and little?
为什么是中等和一点？
Turns out that each of these are bytes.
事实证明，这些都是字节。
The smallest value you can have in a byte, we said, is 0.
我们说过，一个字节可以存储的最小值是 0。
The largest value you can have in a byte is 255.
一个字节可以存储的最大值是 255。
So I'm just kind of spitballing here.
所以我只是在这里随便说说。
This is like medium, medium, and a low amount of red, green, blue.
这就像中等程度的红色，中等程度的绿色和少量的蓝色。
Specifically, those three colors, like wavelengths of light, are combined in such a way that you would have this dot on the screen, a sort of murky shade of yellow or brown that is how a computer would store precisely that color.
具体来说，这三种颜色，就像光的波长一样，以某种方式组合在一起，
你会在屏幕上看到这个点，一种模糊的黄色或棕色阴影，这就是计算机存储这种颜色的精确方式。
And in fact, we've seen this color.
事实上，我们已经见过这种颜色了。
When you type in face with tears of joy, generally on your screen it looks like this, typically much smaller.
当你输入带有喜悦泪水的表情符号时，通常在你的屏幕上它看起来像这样，通常要小得多。
But let's zoom in.
但是让我们放大一点。
Or let's zoom in a little more.
或者让我们再放大一点。
What are you starting to see, if you know the term?
如果你知道这个术语，你开始看到什么了？
So pixels, it's getting very pixelated.
所以像素，它变得非常像素化。
A pixel is just a dot on the screen.
像素只是屏幕上的一个点。
And if you really zoom in on it, you can literally see all of the dots that compose an emoji, in this case on iOS, in the font that Apple's using to represent this particular pattern of zeros and ones.
如果你真的放大它，你可以从字面上看到组成一个表情符号的所有点，在这种情况下是在 iOS 上，在 Apple 用来表示这种特殊的零一模式的字体中。
So one of those yellow dots, and there's many of them, all kind of blend together here.
所以其中一个黄色的点，有很多，都在这里混合在一起。
Each dot on the screen, I claim, is three bytes.
我声称，屏幕上的每个点都是三个字节。
How much red, green, blue for this dot?
这个点需要多少红色、绿色和蓝色？
And you'll notice, too, that when it gets to be sort of brownish here, the dots really stand out.
你还会注意到，当它变成这种褐色的时候，这些点真的很显眼。
The three values, the three bytes, a.k.a.
这三个值，这三个字节，也就是
24 bits, are just slightly different.
24 位，只是略有不同。
And so underneath the hood, this is why images, photographs that you take, or GIFs that you download get so darn big, potentially, because you have a number representing every dot on the screen.
这就是为什么你拍摄的照片或下载的 GIF 图像会变得如此之大，因为屏幕上的每个点都有一个数字来表示。
Well, if this, I claim, is indeed how images are typically represented using pattern of bits that are assigned to some amount of red, green, or blue, how do you get video?
我认为，如果图像确实是通过这种方式用分配给一定数量的红色、绿色或蓝色的位模式来表示的，那么视频是如何实现的呢？
What is a video if, at the end of the day, all we have are 0's and 1's?
如果最终我们只有 0 和 1，那么视频是什么？
What's a video, perhaps?
也许，视频是什么？
Yeah. Oh, let's go here. Way in back.
我们请这位同学回答。 最后面的那位。
Yeah, pixels really changing values over time.
是的，像素值随时间不断变化。
And do you want to confirm or deny the hand that went up here?
你想要确认还是否认刚才举手的那位同学的说法？
Yeah, or equivalently, a sequence of images that over time are changing on the screen.
是的，或者说，是一系列图像，它们在屏幕上随时间变化。
So both of those are valid interpretations.
所以这两种解释都是有效的。
And just for fun, if you grew up with these sort of picture books, you might remember a little something like this.
有趣的是，如果你小时候看过这种图画书，你可能会记得类似的东西。
If we could dim the lights.
如果我们可以把灯调暗一点。
So that's sort of the old school analog way to implement a video in the sense that that artist wrote out like hundreds of pieces of paper with almost identical images, but where the ink from their pencil or pen was slightly moving.
这就是老式的模拟方式来实现视频，艺术家在几百张纸上画了几乎相同的图像，只是他们的铅笔或钢笔的墨水略有移动。
And if you digitize that such that each of those strokes are represented with dots instead, that's really what you're seeing is a sequence of all of these images flying across the screen.
如果你把它数字化，用点来表示每一笔画，你所看到的实际上就是所有这些图像在屏幕上飞舞的序列。
And if we dive into the real world, if you've ever watched a film, a Hollywood movie,
如果我们深入到现实世界，如果你曾经看过电影，一部好莱坞电影，
It's typically 24 FPS, frames per second.
它通常是 24 FPS，每秒帧数。
That really means you're seeing 24 images per second.
这实际上意味着你每秒看到 24 张图像。
Or on TV or in soap operas, it's often 30 frames per second.
或者在电视或肥皂剧中，通常是每秒 30 帧。
That makes things look a little more smooth.
这使得画面看起来更流畅。
So it's not actual motion picture, if you will.
所以它不是真正的电影，如果你想这么说的话。
It's sequences of pictures, and your brain and mind Are kind of interpolating that, oh, this is smooth movement, even though we're just seeing a lot of pictures really fast.
它是一系列的图片，你的大脑和思维正在进行插值，认为这是一个流畅的动作，即使我们只是看到很多图片快速闪过。
Now, that gets really big.
现在，这变得非常大了。
And we'll talk later in the semester how you can compress information so that you're not using way more bits than you actually need to.
我们将在本学期晚些时候讨论如何压缩信息，以便你不会使用比实际需要更多的比特。
And there's fancy algorithms that folks have developed.
人们已经开发出了一些复杂的算法。
But at the end of the day, that's really all a video might be is a sequence of images.
但归根结底，视频可能就是一系列图像。
Conversely, if you want to represent the music that accompanies that or something else, if any of you play an instrument and can read sheet music, how could you digitize this?
反过来，如果你想表示伴随它的音乐或其他东西，如果你们中有人会演奏乐器并且会读乐谱，你们如何将其数字化？
Like, how could you represent musical notes in a computer?
比如，如何在计算机中表示音符？
You and I hear them when we play files, but what's really going on underneath the hood?
当我们播放文件时，你我能听到它们，但实际上是怎么回事？
Any musicians?
有音乐家吗？
Piano players?
弹钢琴的吗？
Anyone?
有吗？
Yeah.
有。
OK, so Hertz value, so some frequency.
赫兹值，表示频率。
So sound is some frequency, and it's kind of hitting your eardrum, and that's what makes it sound low or high or somewhere in between.
声音有一定的频率，它会撞击你的耳膜，让你听到高低不同的声音。
So maybe we could assign, just like there's letters A through G here, maybe we could assign specific frequency values, which are just going to be numbers measured in something called Hertz, something per second.
就像字母 A 到 G 一样，我们可以为每个音符分配特定的频率值，这些值是用赫兹来衡量的，单位是“每秒”。
And maybe we could have a few other numbers for each of these notes, not just the note or the frequency.
除了音符或频率之外，我们还可以为每个音符添加一些其他的数字。
Maybe we could represent the loudness of it, like how hard or how softly a human might equivalently press it.
比如响度，就像人用力或轻轻地按压琴键一样。
Maybe a third number, like duration, like how long is their finger on the keyboard.
再比如持续时间，就像手指在键盘上停留的时间。
So you could imagine quantizing something like music that, in the real world, is perfectly continuous as something more discrete by representing each note over time as just some sequence of values.
你可以想象，将现实世界中完全连续的音乐量化，通过用一系列值表示每个音符随时间的变化，把它变成离散的数据。
And there's so many different ways to do this, MIDI, if you've heard,
有很多不同的方式可以做到这一点，比如你可能听说过的 MIDI，
MP3s, AAC, I mean, almost all of the file extensions you see on your Mac or PC, if you see them at all, ultimately just mean there's a different form of representation for, in this case, something like sound.
MP3、AAC，我的意思是，你在 Mac 或 PC 上看到的所有文件扩展名，最终都只是代表了一种不同的数据表示形式，比如声音。
So let me just stipulate there are these and many more ways to represent inputs and outputs.
我要强调的是，有很多方法可以表示输入和输出。
And thankfully, humans have standardized a lot of this.
值得庆幸的是，人类已经将很多东西标准化了。
They don't always agree.
但他们并不总是一致。
And this is why we have different file formats for Apple Numbers and Microsoft Excel and Google Spreadsheets and sort of stupid incompatibilities like that.
这就是为什么 Apple Numbers、Microsoft Excel 和 Google Spreadsheets 会有不同的文件格式，以及类似的愚蠢的不兼容问题。
But generally speaking, humans have standardized how we represent the inputs and outputs to and from problems.
但总的来说，人类已经标准化了我们如何表示问题的输入和输出。
But let's now focus on this black box, so to speak, in the middle, this abstraction.
现在让我们把注意力集中在这个“黑盒子”，也就是抽象上。
So abstraction is technically a term that you'll see all over the place in computer science and really problem solving that just refers to the simplification of something so that you don't focus on the lower level implementation details.
抽象是你在计算机科学和解决问题过程中随处可见的一个专业术语，它指的是简化事物，让你不必关注底层的实现细节。
You really just focus on the high level goals or the process itself.
你只需要关注高层的目标或流程本身。
Therefore, your car, if you have a license and have driven or have been in a car,
如果你有驾照，开过车或者坐过车，
A car, so far as you're concerned, is probably an abstraction. Most of us, if you're like me, probably don't really know or care how the engine works and all the parts that are moving.
那么汽车对你来说就是一个抽象的概念，如果你和我一样，很可能并不真正了解或关心发动机的运转方式以及所有运动部件的细节。
To you, it's just a way of getting from point A to point B. It's an abstraction.
对你来说，这只是从 A 点到 B 点的一种方式，一种抽象。
But someone, hopefully, the mechanic, does know those lower-level implementation details.
但有人，希望是机械师，了解那些底层的实现细节。
If you had to understand how a car works every time you want to go to school or to the store, it's probably going to be a pretty slow process.
如果你每次想去学校或商店都必须了解汽车是如何工作的，那效率可能会很低。
You just want to think and operate at this higher level of abstraction.
你只想在这个更高的抽象层次上思考和操作。
And we're going to do this all the time when writing code and solving problems.
我们在编写代码和解决问题时会一直这样做。
So what then is in this black box, this abstraction at the moment?
那么，这个黑盒子，这个抽象概念里到底是什么呢？
Well, generally, it's what a computer scientist would call an algorithm, step-by-step instructions for solving some problem.
通常，计算机科学家将其称为算法，即解决某个问题的分步说明。
Now, let's consider the implementation details.
现在，让我们考虑一下实现的细节。
That is to say, how you might solve certain problems.
也就是说，你如何解决某些问题。
And let's take a sort of old school example, but in modern form.
让我们举一个有点老套但以现代形式呈现的例子。
This icon, if you have an iPhone, is, of course, for your contacts application.
如果你有 iPhone，这个图标就是你的通讯录应用程序。
And if you've got a whole bunch of family members or friends or colleagues in your phone book, you have some kind of contacts pictured here.
如果你的手机通讯录里有一大堆家人、朋友或同事，你就会看到类似这样的联系人。
And it's alphabetized typically by first name and last name.
通常情况下，它们会按姓氏和名字的字母顺序排列。
And odds are you and I are in the habit, if they're not already a favorite,
如果他们还不是你的常用联系人，你我可能都习惯这样做，
And what happens when you start typing autocomplete?
当你开始输入自动完成时会发生什么？
Well, if you type in the letter H, you'll see only, presumably, Hagrid, Harry, Hermione, and so forth.
假设你输入字母 H，你只会看到 Hagrid、Harry、Hermione 等等。
If you type in HA, that shows you only Hagrid and Harry, and it all happens super fast.
如果你输入 HA，它只会显示 Hagrid 和 Harry，而且速度非常快。
So how is that happening?
这是怎么做到的呢？
Well, typically, you could just start at the top and look to the bottom, searching for all of the H's or all of the HAs.
通常，你可以从头开始一直往下看，查找所有包含 H 或 HA 的结果。
But for larger data sets, that's going to get slow.
但对于更大的数据集，速度会很慢。
For the Googles of the world, that's going to get really slow.
对于 Google 这样的大公司，这种做法会变得非常慢。
And even on our phones, when you have hundreds, thousands of contacts eventually, even that kind of approach, that algorithm step by step might be slow.
即使在我们的手机上，当你最终有成百上千个联系人时，即使是这种逐步骤的算法方法也可能很慢。
So how might we go about searching for someone in a phone book like this?
那么，我们怎样才能在这样的电话簿中搜索某个人呢？
Like, say, John Harvard, well, here's an old-school incarnation of this.
比如，John Harvard，这是一个老式的版本。
And odds are you might not have had occasion to even physically use this thing nowadays.
而且很有可能你现在都没有机会亲手使用这个东西。
And in fact, this is a bit of a white lie because this is the Yellow Pages, which means this is a book of companies, not people.
事实上，这有点言过其实，因为这是黄页，这意味着这是一本公司名录，而不是人名录。
But this is all you can find.
但这就是你能找到的全部内容。
And at that, it's even hard to find this.
即使这样，也很难找到。
But this is the same thing in analog form, physical form.
但这和模拟形式、物理形式是一样的。
So if I wanted to search for someone like John Harvard, how could I do that?
如果我想搜索像 John Harvard 这样的人，我该怎么做？
Well, I could start on page 1.
我可以从第一页开始。
And I could start searching for page 2, page 3, page 4, page 5.
然后我可以开始搜索第 2 页、第 3 页、第 4 页、第 5 页。
A little hard to do physically, especially since no one's used this phone book in a lot of years.
这在物理上有点难做到，尤其是在这么多年来都没有人用过这本电话簿的情况下。
But is this algorithm correct, turning page by page?
但是这种一页一页翻的算法正确吗？
Very inelegantly.
非常笨拙。
Is this correct?
这正确吗？
Will I find John Harvard if he's in here?
如果 John Harvard 在里面，我能找到他吗？
All right, so yes.
是的。
I mean, this is a little stupidly tedious, because if there's like 1,000 pages, he might be a few hundred pages into this.
我的意思是，这有点愚蠢和乏味，因为如果有 1000 页，他可能在几百页之后。
But it's correct.
但它是正确的。
At some point, I will find him.
我迟早会找到他。
And if he's on the page, I'll be able to call.
如果他在这页上，我就能打电话了。
Why?
为什么？
Because presumably, the names are alphabetized in here.
因为这里的名字大概是按字母顺序排列的。
And there's no cheat sheet on the edge.
而且旁边也没有索引。
So I have to search for John Harvard from left to right, searching for H, if it's alphabetized by last name.
所以我得从左到右搜索 John Harvard，如果按姓氏排序的话，就搜索 H。
Well, what would be marginally better?
那有什么稍微好一点的方法吗？
Well, how about two pages at a time?
一次翻两页怎么样？
It's hard to do.
这很难做到。
20-year-old phone book where the pages are kind of grown together.
一本有 20 年历史的电话簿，书页都粘在一起了。
But 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12.
但 2、4、6、8、10、12。
This algorithm, is this correct?
这个算法正确吗？
All right, so no, why?
不对，为什么？
Yeah, so I'm skipping every other page.
我在每隔一页跳过。
So if I don't consider that and I find myself in the i section or the j section, well, I might accidentally conclude, nope, I haven't found John Harvard yet, just because I skipped him because he was sandwiched between two pages.
所以如果我没有考虑到这一点，我发现自己在 I 部分或 J 部分，
我可能会不小心得出结论，没有，我还没有找到 John Harvard，仅仅是因为我跳过了他，因为他夹在两页之间。
Now, I can fix this, I think, if I do hit the i section.
现在，我想如果我翻到 i 部分，我可以解决这个问题。
Well, let me just double back one page, just in case he was in that last page.
让我往回翻一页，以防他在最后一页。
So it's recoverable, but it's almost twice as fast, minus that hiccup there.
所以它是可以恢复的，但它几乎快了两倍，减去中间的小插曲。
But what most of us would do and what your phones are doing, albeit digitally, is they open up roughly to the middle of the phone book.
但我们大多数人会做的是，你们的手机也在做的是，他们打开电话簿的大致中间部分。
And they look down and they say, oh, I'm in roughly the M section.
他们往下看，说，我大概在 M 部分。
So I'm roughly halfway through this 1,000-page phone book.
我差不多翻完了这本 1000 页的电话簿的一半。
But what do I now know about John Harvard?
但我现在对 John Harvard 了解多少？
Where is he?
他在哪里？
To my left or to my right?
在我的左边还是右边？
All right, so alphabetically, he's presumably to my left.
按字母顺序排列，他应该是在我的左边。
And so here I can both metaphorically and physically tear the problem in half.
所以我既可以象征性地，也可以物理地把这个问题撕成两半。
You don't need to be impressed.
不用太惊讶。
It's really easy down the spine that way.
沿着书脊撕开很容易。
But I know that John Harvard is to the left here.
我知道 John Harvard 在这儿的左边。
But now I can throw unnecessarily dramatically half and page one out of the way.
现在我可以把一半的书页扔到一边去，虽然有点夸张。
And what do I now know?
现在我知道了什么？
I've gone from 1,000 pages to like 500.
我已经从 1000 页缩减到了 500 页。
I can kind of repeat roughly the same algorithm, go to the half of this.
我可以大致重复相同的算法，找到这一半的中间位置。
And so this time I went back a little too far.
这次我翻过头了。
I'm in now the e section.
我现在翻到了 E 部分。
So what do I know?
那么我知道了什么？
Is John Harvard to my left or to my right?
John Harvard 在我的左边还是右边？
To my right, so I can, again, tear the problem in half, throw this half away, and now I'm really flying.
在我的右边，所以我可以再次把问题撕成两半，把这一半扔掉，现在速度快多了。
I'm doing it verbally slowly, but that went from 1,000 pages to 500 to now 250.
我嘴上说得慢，但实际上已经从 1000 页缩减到 500 页，现在是 250 页了。
And now I can do it again, 125.
我可以再做一次，125 页。
I'd do it again, roughly like 67, and keep doing it again and again and again until I get left with, hopefully, just one single page, or in this case, an ad for, ironically, a mechanic.
我会重复这样做，大概重复 67 次，然后一次又一次地重复，直到最后只剩下一个页面，或者在这个例子中，是一个讽刺的是，一个机械师的广告。
OK, so.
What is the implication for our performance?
这对我们程序的性能有什么影响？
Well, let's just do this.
我们来做一下这个。
Sort of in the abstract, if you will, if that first algorithm were to be plotted just quickly on a chart without even numbers, here's my x-axis, size of problem on the x-axis.
抽象地说，如果把第一个算法绘制在一张图表上，甚至不用数字，这里是我的 x 轴，x 轴表示问题的规模。
So the bigger the problem, the farther out that way.
所以问题越大，就越往那边走。
Time to solve the problem, the higher you go up on the y-axis, the more time you're taking to solve it.
解决问题的时间，你在 y 轴上越高，解决它所需的时间就越多。
How would we draw the running time?
我们如何绘制运行时间？
The amount of time taken to run that first algorithm.
运行第一个算法所需的时间。
Well, it's going to be a straight line.
它会是一条直线。
Why?
为什么？
Because if you add one more page next year because more people moved to Cambridge, you're going to add one more page turn potentially.
因为如果明年因为有更多人搬到剑桥而增加一页，你就要多翻一页。
So one more second, one more unit of time.
所以要多一秒钟，多一个单位的时间。
So it's a straight line, and we'll abstract it away as n. If there's n pages in the phone book, the slope of this line is essentially n. The second algorithm, wherein I was doing two pages at a time,
所以它是一条直线，我们把它抽象为 n。如果电话簿里有 n 页，这条线的斜率基本上就是 n。第二个算法，我每次翻两页，
It was twice as fast, but it's still a straight line.
速度快了一倍，但它仍然是一条直线。
And in fact, let me just draw some dotted lines here.
事实上，让我在这里画几条虚线。
If the phone book is this big, with my first algorithm, it might take this many units of time, this many steps, this many page turns.
如果电话簿有这么大，用我的第一个算法，可能需要这么多单位的时间，这么多步，这么多页的翻页。
But with that second algorithm, notice that the intersection is much lower on the yellow line than on the red.
但是用第二个算法，注意到黄线上的交点比红线上的要低很多。
So n over 2 means there's half as many pages here if n is the number of pages.
所以如果 n 是页数，那么 n/2 就意味着这里的页数少了一半。
So indeed, that algorithm, the second one, is twice as fast.
第二个算法确实快了两倍。
Minus the little hiccup that I have to double back one page.
只是出了一点小状况，我得返回上一页。
But that's not a big deal if I'm still doing things twice as fast.
但这没什么大不了的，因为我的速度还是原来的两倍。
But the third algorithm looks fundamentally different.
但第三种算法看起来完全不同。
It looks like this.
它看起来像这样。
Logarithms, if you recall from high school or prior, if you don't, that's fine too.
对数，如果你还记得高中或以前学过的知识，如果不记得也没关系。
It's just a fundamentally different function, a different shape.
它只是一个完全不同的函数，形状也不同。
And notice that the green line is going up and up and up, but a much slower rate of increase.
请注意，绿线一直在向上延伸，但增长的速度要慢得多。
Which means crazy things are possible.
这意味着可能会发生不可思议的事情。
If two towns in Massachusetts, like Cambridge and Allston across the river, merge next year, for instance, in terms of their phone book, their phone book just got twice as big.
例如，如果马萨诸塞州的两个城镇，比如隔河相望的剑桥和奥尔斯顿，明年合并，就他们的电话簿而言，他们的电话簿规模会翻倍。
For the first algorithm, that's going to take me twice as many steps to go through.
对于第一种算法，我需要花费两倍的步骤才能完成。
The second algorithm, it's going to take me 50% more steps to go through, two at a time.
第二种算法，我需要多花 50% 的步骤，每次两步。
But the third algorithm that I ended with, tearing things again and again, dividing and conquering,
但第三种算法，我最后使用的算法，不断地拆分，如果你愿意，可以称之为分而治之，
if you will, in half and in half and in half, how many more steps will my third algorithm take If Cambridge and Alston merge into a phone book that's twice as big?
分成一半，再分成一半，如果剑桥和奥尔斯顿合并成一本两倍大的电话簿，我的第三种算法需要多做多少步？ ？
Just one more step, right?
只需要多一步，对吧？
No big deal.
没什么大不了的。
You just take a really big bite out of the problem once you decide if John Harvard is to the left or to the right, and so you've made much faster progress.
一旦你确定 John Harvard 在左边还是右边，你就可以在这个问题上迈出一大步，所以你的进度会快很多。
And so this, in essence, is what your computer, your phone, is probably doing underneath the hood when searching for Harry or Hermione or Hagrid or anyone else, because it's that much faster, especially when you have large data.
从本质上讲，这就是你的电脑、你的手机在搜索 Harry、Hermione、Hagrid 或其他任何人时，
可能在后台所做的事情，因为它要快得多，尤其是在处理大量数据时。
If you don't have that many contacts, it's
如果你的联系人不多，那就
Probably doesn't matter if you search from top to bottom or more in the form of this divide and conquer algorithm.
从上到下搜索还是以这种分治算法的形式搜索，可能并不重要。
But if you're the Googles of the world or you're analyzing large data sets, indeed, this is going to add up quite quickly.
但如果你是 Google 这样的公司，或者你正在分析大型数据集，那么这确实会很快累积起来。
So where do we go with this?
那我们接下来要做什么？
Well, we're going to introduce next something called pseudocode.
接下来我们要介绍一个叫做伪代码的东西。
How can I translate what I did verbally there?
我该如何把我刚才口头表达的内容翻译出来呢？
Sort of intuitively to actual code, well, this won't be Scratch.
如何直观地转换成实际代码？当然，这不会是 Scratch。
This won't be C or Python just yet.
也不会是 C 语言或 Python。
It's just going to be an English-like syntax.
它只是一种类似英语的语法。
And this is how many programmers would start solving a problem.
很多程序员就是这样开始解决问题的。
They don't start typing out code in C or Python or the like.
他们不会一开始就用 C 语言、Python 或其他语言编写代码。
They use English or whatever their human language is to jot down an outline for their ideas.
他们会用英语或者其他任何人类语言来记下他们想法的概要。
My first step really was picking up the phone book.
我的第一步实际上是拿起电话簿。
My second step was opening to the middle of the phone book.
第二步是打开电话簿的中间。
My third step was somewhat different.
我的第三步有点不同。
Look at the page, because why?
看这一页，为什么？
My fourth step was, if person I'm looking for is on the page, I then do what?
我的第四步是，如果我要找的人在这一页上，我接下来要做什么？
Never happened in my example, but I call the person.
在我的例子中从来没有发生过，但我应该打电话给他。
So I'm done.
这样我就完成了。
Else if the person is earlier in the book alphabetically, as John Harvard was in the case of my age, then I should search to the middle of the left of the phone book.
否则，如果这个人的名字按字母顺序排在电话簿的前面，
比如 John Harvard 在我这个年龄段的电话簿里，那么我应该在电话簿左半部分的中间查找。
And then I should go back to step three.
然后我应该回到第三步。
Step three is look at the page, thereby repeating the same process again and again.
第三步是查看页面，从而一遍又一遍地重复相同的过程。
Step nine, though, might be else if the person is later in the book, then let's go ahead and open to the middle of the right half of the book and then go back to line three.
但是，第九步可能是，否则，如果这个人的名字在电话簿的后面，那么让我们继续打开电话簿右半部分的中间，然后回到第三行。
Else there's a fourth scenario we should probably consider, lest my search process freeze or crash or give me one of those spinning beach balls with a bug.
否则，我们可能还要考虑第四种情况，以免我的搜索过程冻结、崩溃或出现旋转的沙滩球和错误信息。
Yeah, what if John Harvard isn't in the phone book?
是的，如果 John Harvard 不在电话簿里怎么办？
I'd prefer that my algorithm, my phone not just reboot or freeze, I should handle that with some kind of catch-all, else, so to speak, let's just quit the program.
我更希望我的算法，也就是我的手机，不要只是重启或冻结，我应该用某种“全部捕获”（catch-all）的方式来处理这种情况，或者说，退出程序。
So there's well-defined behavior for every possible scenario of the four.
对于这四种可能出现的情况，都有明确的行为定义。
Now let's call out a few of these salient terms.
现在，我们来看几个重要的术语。
It turns out if I highlight in yellow here, there's a pattern to what I've been doing here.
事实证明，如果我在这里用黄色突出显示，我一直在做的事情是有规律可循的。
These are all of my English verbs.
这些都是我的英文动词。
And in a moment, we're going to start calling those verbs functions.
稍后，我们会开始把这些动词称为函数。
When you program or write code and you want the program or the computer to do something for you, some action or verb, we're going to refer to those actions or verbs as these things called functions, like those here.
当你编写代码并希望程序或计算机为你执行某个操作或动词时，我们会将这些操作或动词称为函数，就像这里展示的这些。
By contrast, I've just highlighted instead my if, my else if, my else if and else.
相反，我在这里突出显示了我的 `if`、`else if`、`else if` 和 `else`。
This is going to represent what we're going to start calling a conditional, a proverbial fork in the road, where you can either go this way or that way, do this thing or this other thing.
这代表着我们将要开始称之为条件语句的东西，一个比喻为岔路口的东西，你可以走这条路，也可以走那条路，做这件事，或者做另一件事。
And you're going to decide which of those things to do
你需要根据情况决定要做什么。
Based on what I've now highlighted here, which are going to be called Boolean expressions.
基于我现在在这里突出显示的内容，这些内容将被称为布尔表达式。
Bool referring to a mathematician last name Bool.
Bool 指的是一位数学家的姓氏 Bool。
A Boolean expression is just a question with a yes, no, a true, false, a one or a zero answer, if you will.
布尔表达式就是一个可以用是、否、真、假、1 或 0 来回答的问题。
And it governs whether you do this thing or this thing or this thing or that.
它决定了你做这件事、那件事、这件事还是那件事。
The indentation in this case is important.
在这种情况下，缩进很重要。
The fact that I've indented line 5 implies, by convention in programming, that I should only do line 5 if the answer to line 4 is a yes or a true.
根据编程惯例，我对第 5 行进行了缩进，这意味着只有当第 4 行的答案是“是”或“真”时，我才应该执行第 5 行。
And same for these other indented lines as well.
其他缩进的行也是如此。
And the last characteristic here is this here.
最后一个特征在这里。
Someone called this out earlier, in fact.
实际上，有人之前已经提到过这个了。
These lines 8 and 11 are now highlighted and represent what?
第 8 行和第 11 行现在高亮显示，它们代表什么呢？
What might we call these in code if you've done that?
如果你写过代码，你会怎么称呼它们？
Yeah, so these are loops, some kind of cycles that result in my doing the same thing again and again.
对，这些是循环，某种类型的循环，导致我一遍又一遍地做同样的事情。
But there's a key detail with this algorithm in pseudocode.
但这个用伪代码表示的算法有一个关键细节。
Even though it's telling me to go back to line 3, why is this algorithm eventually going to stop?
尽管它告诉我返回第 3 行，但为什么这个算法最终会停止呢？
Why do I not constantly keep looking for John Harvard forever by nature of these loops telling me to keep going back to line 3?
为什么我不会因为这些循环让我不断回到第 3 行而永远寻找 John Harvard？
Good.
很好。
Eventually, he'll be on the page, or to your point earlier, he won't be at all, and we're out of pages, and so we just quit.
最终，他会出现在页面上，或者像你之前说的，他根本就不在，而且我们已经翻完了所有页面，所以我们就退出了。
And that's the key about going to the left half or the right half.
这就是去左半边还是右半边的关键。
It doesn't matter if you do the same thing again and again.
即使你一遍又一遍地做同样的事情也没关系。
You're not going to get stuck in the so-called infinite loop so long as you keep dividing the problem and shrinking it into something smaller, smaller, smaller.
只要你不断地划分问题，把它缩小，缩小，再缩小，你就不会陷入所谓的无限循环中。
Eventually, there's going to be no problem left to solve.
最终，就不会有任何问题需要解决了。
So even if you don't think of yourself as a computer person, even if you've never written code, what you'll find in the coming days is that these ideas that we've just kind of harnessed from real life are at your fingertips already.
即使你不认为自己是一个计算机专业人士，即使你从未写过代码，在接下来的几天里，你会发现我们刚刚从现实生活中汲取的这些想法已经触手可及。
And a lot of the process of learning to code is just going to be some bumps in the road because you can't quite see the new syntax in a familiar way.
学习编程的过程很大程度上会遇到一些障碍，因为你无法以熟悉的方式看待新的语法。
But you'll find that the ideas, in fact, are going to be more familiar than you might otherwise think.
但你会发现，这些想法实际上比你想象的要熟悉得多。
And so we'll see in a bit, and we'll take a break in a moment to take a breather, that you will see these same ideas in a moment in the context of Scratch, an actual programming language via which we'll drag and drop puzzle pieces to make actual code work.
我们稍后会看到，我们会稍作休息，喘口气，
你会在 Scratch 中看到同样的想法，Scratch 是一种真正的编程语言，我们可以通过拖放拼图块来使实际代码工作。
We'll see some variants of these ideas, things called arguments and return values and variables, but we'll ultimately convert it into this somehow.
我们会看到这些想法的一些变体，称为参数、返回值和变量，但我们最终会以某种方式将其转换为这种形式。
Anyone want to wager what this program will do if fed to your Mac or PC or phone?
如果把这个程序输入到你的 Mac、PC 或手机中，有人想打赌它会做什么吗？
Here's just a massive pattern of zeros and ones.
这里只是一大堆 0 和 1。
It will indeed say, rather disappointingly, apparently, just hello, world.
它确实会显示，相当令人失望地，显然，只是“hello, world”。
And indeed, baked into all of these zeros and ones are not just the H-E-L-L-O, but also the verbs, the action of printing something to the screen.
事实上，在所有这些 0 和 1 中，不仅包含了“H-E-L-L-O”，还包含了动词，即将内容打印到屏幕上的动作。
And there's other stuff, too, so that the program knows how to start and how to stop, a lot of stuff that we won't have to worry about that whoever designed the computer or the language did.
还有其他东西，比如程序如何开始和停止，很多我们不必担心的事情，那些设计计算机或语言的人已经做好了。
But at the end of the day, you're never going to be writing these zeros and ones yourselves, though our ancestors once upon a time did in some form.
但最终，你永远不会自己写这些 0 和 1，尽管我们的前辈曾在某种程度上这样做过。
We'll be using a much higher level language like this in C, or better yet in just a moment like in Scratch like this.
我们将使用更高级的语言，比如 C 语言，或者更好的是，像 Scratch 这样的语言。
And indeed, this is why today we focus on and begin with Scratch, this graphical programming language, so we have a way of expressing ourselves with functions, conditionals, loops.
事实上，这就是我们今天关注并从 Scratch 开始的原因，这种图形编程语言，让我们能够用函数、条件语句、循环来表达自己。
And more, but in a way that doesn't have stupid parentheses and curly braces and all these visual distractions in the way.
还有更多，但不会出现愚蠢的括号、花括号以及所有这些视觉上的干扰。
And we'll translate that thereafter to this lower level language.
之后我们会将其翻译成这种低级语言。
But for now, that was a lot.
但现在，内容太多了。
That was definitely a fire hose.
这绝对是信息量过载。
Let's go ahead and take a 10 minute break.
我们休息十分钟吧。
Feel free to get up or stay here.
可以起来走走，也可以留在这里。
And we'll resume in a bit with some actual code.
我们稍后会继续，写一些实际的代码。
We're your weather girls.
我们是你的天气预报员。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
And have we got news for you.
我们有个消息要告诉你。
You better listen.
你最好听着。
Get ready for your lonely girls.
准备好迎接你的孤独女孩们吧。
And leave those umbrellas at home.
把雨伞留在家里吧。
All right.
It is rising.
它正在上升。
Rising.
上升。
And how does it go?
它是怎么上升的？
How does it go, girl?
姑娘，它是怎么上升的？
According to all sources.
根据所有消息来源。
What sources now?
现在是什么消息来源？
The streets, the place to go.
街上，要去的地方。
We better hurry up.
我们最好快点。
Because tonight for the first time.
因为今晚是第一次。
All right.
So this, then, is Scratch, a graphical programming language from our friends down the road at MIT's Media Lab that, indeed, some of you might have used in grade school or the like for playing and writing code and the like.
这就是 Scratch，一种来自麻省理工学院媒体实验室我们朋友的图形编程语言，你们中的一些人可能在小学或类似的地方用它玩耍、编写代码等等。
But you maybe didn't necessarily think about how some of these primitives ultimately worked.
但你可能不一定会想到这些基本元素是如何运作的。
And in fact, everything you've done, if you've used Scratch before, and everything you'll see today is going to apply.
事实上，如果你以前使用过 Scratch，你所做的一切以及你今天将看到的一切都将适用。
We apply to all of the weeks to come as we explore these things called functions and loops and conditionals, Boolean expressions, and more.
在接下来的几周里，当我们探索函数、循环、条件语句、布尔表达式等等时，我们将应用所有这些内容。
With Scratch, because it's so graphical and animated, can you create animations like this one, interactive art and software more generally?
使用 Scratch，因为它具有图形化和动画效果，你能创建像这样的动画、互动艺术和更通用的软件吗？
But you'll do so by dragging and dropping puzzle pieces that only lock together if it makes logical sense to do so.
但你要通过拖放拼图块来实现，这些拼图块只有在逻辑上合理的情况下才会组合在一起。
And what you won't have to deal with in this first week of class is curly braces, parentheses, all of the weird symbology that you might recall seeing when we just wanted to say hello, world.
在这第一周的课程中，你不需要处理花括号、圆括号以及所有那些我们只想说“hello, world”时你可能记得见过的奇怪符号。
Now, this particular program, Raining Men, was written by a former CS50 teaching fellow, Andrew Berry, who's actually now the general manager of the Cleveland Browns, the American football team.
这个名为“Raining Men”的程序是由前 CS50 助教 Andrew Berry 编写的，他现在是美国橄榄球队克利夫兰布朗队的总经理。
And so these are just some of the programs that some of your predecessors in the class have created.
这些只是你们的一些前辈在这门课上创建的一些程序。
And you'll see in the remainder of class here a couple of others as well and more in the course's first assignment.
在接下来的课程中，你会看到其他几个例子，在课程的第一个作业中还会看到更多。
Namely, problem set 0.
也就是问题集0。
So how do we get there?
那我们如何实现呢？
Well, first, a quick tour of what it is we're going to do.
首先，快速浏览一下我们要做什么。
This in Scratch is perhaps the simplest program you can write.
在 Scratch 中，这可能是你能写出的最简单的程序。
And even if you've never seen Scratch or any programming language before, you can probably guess that this just says on the screen somehow, hello world.
即使你以前从未见过 Scratch 或任何编程语言，你也可以猜到，这只是在屏幕上以某种方式显示“Hello World”。
But what you don't have to do is type esoteric commands and weird syntax, those curly braces and parentheses I keep alluding to.
但你不需要输入深奥的命令和奇怪的语法，那些我一直提到的花括号和圆括号。
You just drag this yellow puzzle piece.
你只需要拖动这个黄色的拼图块。
You drag this purple puzzle piece, let them magnetically lock together, so to speak, click a button, and boom.
拖动这个紫色的拼图块，让它们像磁铁一样吸附在一起，然后点击一个按钮，就完成了。
With those same building blocks and several others, can you make what exactly the sorts of things that Andrew brought to life as well?
利用这些构建块和其他一些构建块，你能做出 Andrew 所展示的那种东西吗？
So here's what we're about to see.
下面是我们即将看到的。
At scratch.mit.edu,
在 scratch.mit.edu，
is a cloud-based programming environment on MIT servers.
是一个基于云的编程环境，运行在 MIT 的服务器上。
You can also download it offline on your own Mac or PC.
你也可以把它下载到你的 Mac 或 PC 上离线使用。
And it gives you an interface like this.
它提供了一个像这样的界面。
On the left-hand side of the screen, you'll see a blocks palette.
在屏幕左侧，你会看到一个积木面板。
These puzzle pieces, a.k.a.
这些拼图块，也称为
blocks, come in different colors, which rather categorize them.
积木，有不同的颜色，这些颜色对它们进行了分类。
So pictured here, for instance, in blue, are a whole bunch of motion-related blocks.
例如，图中蓝色的是一堆与运动相关的积木。
So Andrew used a whole bunch of those to have the singer and the men moving around on the screen in synchronicity with the song that was playing in the background.
Andrew 就使用了大量的这类积木，让歌手和人们在屏幕上随着背景音乐同步移动。
Meanwhile, in the middle of this interface is going to be the code area.
同时，这个界面的中间是代码区域。
And this is where Andrew and Sun Yoo will drag and drop some of those puzzle pieces and other colors as well and lock them together to get your characters, soon to be invented, to do something on the screen.
Andrew 和 Sun Yoo 会将一些拼图块和其他颜色的块拖放到这里，并将它们组合在一起，使你的角色（即将被创造出来）在屏幕上做一些事情。
Indeed, on the bottom right here will you see, ultimately, A sprite area, where a sprite is a technical term for a character in a video game or a programming environment like this.
事实上，在右下角你最终会看到一个 Sprite 区域，Sprite 是电子游戏或编程环境（比如 Scratch）中角色的技术术语。
By default, historically, Scratch is the cat, the mascot, if you will, for this programming environment.
默认情况下，Scratch 的吉祥物是一只猫。
And so here we see by default just one sprite selected, because on the top right of the screen is the stage for that sprite.
所以在这里，我们默认情况下只看到一个 Sprite 被选中，因为屏幕的右上角是该 Sprite 的舞台。
And you can click and zoom in to make it full screen.
你可以点击并放大到全屏。
But this is the world in which Scratch, by default the cat, will live.
但这就是默认情况下 Scratch 猫所生活的的世界。
But you can change Scratch's costume so that it looks like a singer or the man falling from the sky or the like or anything else, either creating the art yourself or importing some of the things that come with it or elsewhere online.
但你可以改变 Scratch 的服装，让它看起来像一个歌手，或者一个从天上掉下来的人，
或者任何其他的东西，你可以自己创作艺术，或者导入一些 Scratch 自带的或网上的东西。
So what is this world that Scratch rather lives in?
那么 Scratch 所处的这个世界是什么样的呢?
Well, generally speaking, we won't have to care too much about numbers because we'll be able to ask questions like interactive ones, like is Scratch the cat or any character otherwise touching the edge of the screen, touching something else?
一般来说，我们不需要太关心数字，因为我们可以问一些交互式的问题，比如 Scratch 猫或其他角色是否接触到屏幕边缘，是否接触到其他东西？
But Scratch does exist in this two-dimensional, A coordinate system world.
但 Scratch 的确存在于这个二维的坐标系世界中。
So when the cat or any character is dead center in the middle, that would be xy location 0 comma 0, if you will.
所以当猫或任何角色位于正中央时，它的坐标位置是 (0, 0)。
Meanwhile, over here is 240 pixels or dots all the way to the right.
同时，右侧的坐标是 (240, 0)，表示距离中心 240 像素或点。
So this would be 240 comma 0, where y is 0 because it's right on that midline.
所以这个点的坐标是 (240, 0)，其中 y 是 0，因为它正好在中线上。
So it's neither up or below.
所以它既不在上面也不在下面。
Over here to the left, of course, would be negative 240 and 0.
当然，左侧的坐标是 (-240, 0)。
Above the cat would be x equals 0, because it's right on that vertical midline, and 180.
猫的正上方坐标是 (0, 180)，因为它正好在垂直中线上。
And then down here, as you might guess, would be 0 comma negative 180.
然后你可能已经猜到了，下面的坐标是 (0, -180)。
Generally speaking, we don't have to care about those precise pixel coordinates.
一般来说，我们不需要关心这些精确的像素坐标。
But it's helpful, ultimately, if you do want the cat to move up, down, left, or right, having some sense of direction.
但最终，如果你想让猫向上、向下、向左或向右移动，了解方向感还是有帮助的。
According to the x-axis and y-axis as well can help you express your ideas ultimately.
根据 x 轴和 y 轴，最终可以帮助你表达你的想法。
So what might some of those ideas be?
那么其中一些想法可能是什么呢？
Well, let's do this.
我们来试试这个。
I'm going to go ahead and create on scratch.mit.edu just an empty screen like this one here.
我要在 scratch.mit.edu 上创建一个像这样空白的屏幕。
And so this is the exact same interface, but now I'm in my browser.
这是完全相同的界面，但现在是在我的浏览器里。
Full screen so that I can start writing some code.
全屏显示，这样我就可以开始编写代码了。
And let's get that cat to say something actually on the screen.
让我们让这只猫在屏幕上说点什么。
Now, this takes a little bit of practice.
这需要一些练习。
But honestly, just by scrolling through these puzzle pieces, can you quickly get a sense of what's possible, not just categorically, but specifically?
但是说实话，仅仅通过滚动浏览这些拼图块，你能快速了解到什么是可能的，不仅仅是类别上，还有具体内容上？
And I'll jump around because I've done this, of course, before.
我会跳来跳去，因为我以前做过这个。
But I'm going to go to events in yellow first.
但我首先要进入黄色的事件部分。
And I'm going to drag and drop this first block called when green flag clicked.
我要拖放第一个块，叫做“当绿旗被点击”。
And I've zoomed in there just to make it a little more legible.
我在那里放大了，只是为了让它更清晰一些。
And notice that the shape of this green flag just so happens to mirror this green flag here at top next to this red stop sign of sorts.
请注意，这个绿旗的形状正好与顶部这个红色停止标志旁边的绿旗相对应。
And the green flag is going to mean go.
绿旗表示开始。
And the red stop sign is going to mean stop, to start or stop our program.
红色停止标志表示停止，用来启动或停止我们的程序。
Next week, you're going to be writing a textual command at your keyboard to do the exact same idea.
下周，你将在键盘上编写一个文本命令来实现同样的想法。
But for now, it's a button.
但现在，它是一个按钮。
So when green flag clicked, what do I want Scratch to do?
点击绿旗后，我想要 Scratch 做什么呢？
Well, how about we have Scratch just initially say something like, hello, world, which indeed, historically, is the first program that most any programmer might write.
我们先让 Scratch 说一句“hello, world”吧，从历史上看，这确实是大多数程序员编写的第一个程序。
So anything related to what the cat looks like it's doing is actually going to be under Looks here in purple.
任何与这只猫看起来正在做的事情有关的指令，实际上都在这里紫色的外观类别下。
So I'm going to drag over Say Hello.
我要把“说 Hello”拖过来。
And you'll notice something curious and different about this purple block.
你会注意到这个紫色积木块有一个奇特而不同的地方。
It says, of course, say in purple.
它用紫色写着“说”。
But then there's this white oval and some text that by default is hello, because MIT just decided that by default the placeholder will be hello.
然后是一个白色的椭圆形，里面有一些默认的文本“hello”，因为 MIT 决定默认的占位符是“hello”。
But anytime you see this white oval, it's an opportunity to provide an input into the function
但每当你看到这个白色椭圆形时，就表示有机会为函数提供输入。
It's called say.
它被称为“说”。
And so here, I'm borrowing terminology from before.
这里我借用了之前的一些术语。
Problem solving, again, is all about inputs, producing outputs.
解决问题，归根结底就是输入，产生输出。
And in between there is some algorithm.
在这两者之间是一些算法。
In a moment, we're going to start referring to algorithms quite frequently as functions.
稍后，我们会开始频繁地将算法称为函数。
Why?
为什么呢？
Because it's the implementation of some algorithm.
因为它是一些算法的实现。
So let me override the default with hello comma world.
让我用“hello, world”覆盖默认值。
I'll zoom out.
我缩小一下。
And now, if I go to the top right of the screen and click the green flag, we'll see, hopefully, my very first program in code.
现在，如果我点击屏幕右上角的绿色旗帜，我们应该能看到我用代码写的第一个程序。
Now, it wasn't a huge lift.
这并不难。
It only was a matter of dragging and dropping puzzle pieces.
只需要拖放拼图块即可。
But what has now happened?
但是现在发生了什么？
Well, it turns out that two things have happened.
实际上，发生了两件事。
When I, the human, clicked on that green flag, I triggered what we're going to start calling now an event.
当我点击绿旗时，我触发了一个我们将要称为“事件”的东西。
An event is generally something graphical or interactive that just happens in a computer program.
事件通常是指在计算机程序中发生的图形化或交互式的操作。
You and I trigger events on our phones all day long.
我们每天都在手机上触发各种事件。
Whenever you tap or drag or long press or pinch or any of those gestures in vogue nowadays on phones, you are triggering events.
每当你在手机上点击、拖动、长按、缩放或进行任何其他手势操作时，你都在触发事件。
And people at Apple and Google and elsewhere have written code that listen for those events and do something when that event happens.
Apple、Google和其他公司的程序员编写了代码来监听这些事件，并在事件发生时执行相应的操作。
That's what I just did.
这就是我刚才所做的。
When green flag is clicked, I want something to happen, namely, I want this purple function, this verb, this action called say to do something.
当点击绿旗时，我希望发生一些事情，也就是让这个紫色的函数、动词、名为“说”的动作执行一些操作。
What do I want it to do?
我希望它做什么呢？
I want it to say what this input is.
我希望它说出这个输入是什么。
And I'm going to introduce another vocabulary term.
我要介绍另一个词汇。
The white ovals here are, yes, inputs very generically.
这里白色的椭圆形是输入，广义上的输入。
But in a programmer's terminology, they're called arguments, otherwise known as parameters.
但在程序员的术语中，它们被称为“参数”，也称为“形参”。
And that just means an input to a function that modifies its behavior in some way.
它指的是函数的输入，用于以某种方式修改函数的行为。
When I click Stop, that's just another event.
当我点击“停止”时，这只是另一个事件。
And that one is just built into Scratch.
而这个事件是内置在Scratch中的。
Scratch knows that when you click the green stop sign, everything should just stop automatically.
Scratch知道当你点击红色的停止标志时，一切都应该自动停止。
I don't have to write code to support that feature.
我不需要编写代码来支持这个功能。
So that's all fine and good.
所以这一切都很好。
Hello, world.
Hello, world
But if I keep doing stop and start and stop and start, it's going to do the same thing again and again.
但如果我一直这样停停走走，它就会一遍又一遍地做同样的事情。
And it's really not that interesting at the end of the day.
到头来，这真的没什么意思。
It may be gratifying once, but it'd be nice if this were a little more interactive.
一次可能会让人满足，但如果这能更具互动性就好了。
So it turns out that we can do that too, but we need a different mental model instead.
事实证明，我们也可以做到，但我们需要一个不同的思维模型。
So in this case here, when we think about this function say in this input hello world, this actually maps pretty cleanly to this model earlier that I propose is problem solving, is computer science, if you will.
所以在这种情况下，当我们考虑这个函数，比如在这个输入“hello world”中，它实际上与我之前提出的解决问题、计算机科学的模型非常吻合。
The input to the current problem is going to be in white here, hello world.
当前问题的输入将是这里的白色部分，“hello world”。
The algorithm is the say algorithm.
算法就是 say 算法。
Now, I don't know how MIT got it to print out the little pretty speech bubble on the screen, but they wrote those underlying low-level implementation details, and they gave me and you a purple function called say that just does that for you.
我不知道麻省理工学院是如何让它在屏幕上打印出漂亮的小对话框的，
但他们编写了那些底层的实现细节，并给了我和你一个叫做 say 的紫色函数，它可以为你做到这一点。
You and I don't have to reinvent that wheel.
你我都不需要重新发明轮子。
The output of say is another technical term now called a side effect.
say 的输出是另一个技术术语，叫做副作用。
A side effect is usually something visual that happens, like as a side effect of you calling a function.
副作用通常是发生的可视化结果，就像调用函数的副作用一样。
And so the side effect here is that the cat has this speech bubble magically appear, inside of which is hello world.
所以这里的副作用是猫神奇地出现了一个对话框，里面是“hello world”。
So we have an input.
所以我们有一个输入。
We have an output.
我们有一个输出。
We have an algorithm.
我们有一个算法。
But now we're talking about these ideas in the context of programming.
但现在我们是在编程的背景下讨论这些概念。
So now the input is an argument.
所以现在输入是一个参数。
The algorithm is a function.
算法是一个函数。
And the output in this case is a side effect.
在这种情况下，输出是一个副作用。
Terminology that you'll just hear more and more, and it'll eventually sink in.
这些术语你会听到越来越多，最终会理解的。
But not to worry if the terminology doesn't come naturally early on.
如果一开始不熟悉这些术语也不用担心。
So what more might I do with this?
那么我还能用它做什么呢？
Well, let me go back to Scratch here and make this maybe perhaps more interactive and actually get the cat to say something a little more dynamically.
我回到 Scratch，让它更具交互性，让这只猫更动态地说些话。
So instead of hello, world, why don't I get him to say hello to me or to you or anyone else?
与其说“Hello, world”，不如让它向我、你或者其他人问好？
So let me do this.
我来演示一下。
Let me go under, say, Let me get rid of this first.
我到下面，比如， 我先把这个删掉。
And you'll notice this neat trick.
你会注意到这个技巧。
As soon as you start dragging on a block, if it gets close to it, it kind of goes gray, and it can be magnetically snapped together.
当你开始拖动一个块时，如果它靠近另一个块，它会变成灰色，可以像磁铁一样吸附在一起。
You don't have to do it very precisely.
你不需要做得非常精确。
Conversely, if I want to get rid of a puzzle piece, I can just drag it anywhere on the left, let go, and that deletes it.
相反，如果我想删除一个拼图块，我可以把它拖到左侧的任何地方，放开，它就会被删除。
Or you can right-click or control-click, and a little menu will let you delete it as well.
或者你可以右键单击或按住 Ctrl 键单击，会弹出一个菜单，你也可以选择删除它。
Well, let me do this instead.
我这样做。
Under Sensing, which I know is there because I've done this before, are a whole bunch of things related to sensing, whereby the cat can kind of feel out its world in some sense.
在“侦测”类别下，我知道它在那里，因为我以前用过，有一堆与“侦测”相关的功能，猫可以用它来感知它的世界。
It can do things like ask this question.
它可以做一些事情，比如问这个问题。
Am I touching the mouse pointer, like the user's cursor?
我是否碰到了鼠标指针，比如用户的鼠标光标？
Am I touching a specific color that you can override to be anything you want?
我是否碰到了一种特定的颜色？你可以把它覆盖成任何你想要的颜色。
Is the distance to the mouse pointer some specific value?
到鼠标指针的距离是否是某个特定的值？
But for now, I'm going to focus this.
但现在，我将重点关注这个。
On this, this blue puzzle piece that asks a question, which itself is this white oval that I can apparently change, and then it's going to wait for a response.
这个蓝色的拼图块提出了一个问题，它本身是一个白色的椭圆形，我显然可以改变它，然后它会等待响应。
But this puzzle piece is a little different.
但这个拼图块有点不同。
It's a little special.
它有点特殊。
It comes with a freebie.
它附带一个赠品。
It comes with what we're going to call technically a return value.
它附带一个我们将在技术上称之为返回值的东西。
So some functions don't just do something on the screen.
所以有些函数不仅仅是在屏幕上做一些事情。
They hand you back, so to speak, a value that you can do anything that you want with.
可以这么说，它们会给你返回一个值，你可以用它做任何你想做的事情。
Nothing happens immediately unless you do something with that so-called return value.
除非你对这个所谓的返回值做些什么，否则不会立即发生任何事情。
So let me go ahead and drag this thing over here.
让我继续把这个东西拖到这里。
Ask, what's your name?
问，what's your name?
And I'll use the default question.
我将使用默认问题。
That seems a reasonable place to start.
这似乎是一个合理的起点。
I'm not going to override that default.
我不打算覆盖默认值。
And now let me go ahead and zoom out.
现在让我继续并缩小。
Let me go back to looks.
让我回到外观。
Let me go to say.
让我去说一下。
And let me just form the English sentence I want.
让我来组成我想要的英文句子。
So let me zoom in here and type in hello, maybe comma, space.
让我在这里放大并输入 hello，也许是逗号，空格。
I could do David, but that's obviously not right, because I'm asking for a name, and then I'm in advance hardcoding my name.
我可以输入 David，但这显然不对，因为我要求输入一个名字，然后我提前硬编码了我的名字。
That's not what I want.
这不是我想要的。
I just want hello, comma.
我只需要“Hello”后面加个逗号。
And now let me zoom out and grab one more say block.
现在让我缩小一下，再拿一个 say 图块。
Let me maybe say here.
我可能想在这里说。
OK, I don't want to say hello, hello.
我不想说“Hello，Hello”。
I don't want to just type in my own name because, again, then what's the point of asking the user for their name?
我不想直接输入我的名字，因为，再说一次，那样的话询问用户的姓名又有什么意义呢？
But notice this.
但是请注意这一点。
If I go back to the sensing block, this is where that oval that's blue called answer is useful.
如果我回到 sensing 图块，这就是那个叫做 answer 的蓝色椭圆形派上用场的地方。
This will be the so-called return value of that function.
这将是该函数的所谓返回值。
So I'm just going to go ahead and do this and drag and drop.
所以我将继续这样做并拖放。
Even though it's not the right size, it is the right shape.
即使它的大小不合适，但它的形状是合适的。
And so Scratch will be smart about it and grow to fill that puzzle piece for you.
Scratch 会很聪明地帮你把它放大以填满那个拼图块。
Let me zoom out now.
让我现在缩小。
And now let me click the green flag.
现在让我点击绿旗。
You'll see that Scratch is indeed prompting me with a speech bubble.
你会看到 Scratch 确实在用一个对话框提示我。
What's your name?
what's your name?
Notice the little text box below the cat is asking, what's your name?
注意猫下面的那个小文本框在问，what's your name?
So I'm going to type in D-A-V-I-D and hit Enter.
所以我将输入 D-A-V-I-D 并按回车键。
Or I can click the blue check.
或者我可以点击蓝色复选标记。
Enter.
回车。
OK.
It's a little weird.
有点奇怪。
I wanted him to say hello, not just my name.
我想让它说“Hello”，后面加上我的名字，而不仅仅是我的名字。
So let me stop.
让我停下来。
Let me start it again.
让我重新开始。
All right.
Hello.
Hello。
What's your name?
what's your name?
D-A-V-I-D.
D-A-V-I-D。
Enter.
回车。
Huh, kind of rude.
有点粗鲁。
Why is there this bug?
为什么会有这个错误？
Like, I wanted to say hello, David, not just David, and yet twice it has failed to do so.
我想让它说“Hello，David”，而不仅仅是“David”，但它两次都没有做到。
Yeah.
Yeah, the computer is processing my directions, my actions really quickly.
计算机正在非常快速地处理我的指令，我的动作。
And so it actually is doing it.
所以它实际上正在这样做。
It's just you and I in the room.
房间里只有你和我。
We're just way too slow to notice that it said, hello, David.
我们只是太慢了，没有注意到它说了“Hello，David”。
It just seems to have just said David.
它似乎只说了“David”。
So all right, how can I fix this?
那么，我该如何解决这个问题呢？
Well, here's where you start to poke around and think about how you might solve this.
这就是你开始四处探索并思考如何解决这个问题的地方。
Let me go back under looks.
回到外观模块。
Maybe there's a smarter way to do this.
也许有更巧妙的方法。
Maybe I could do this.
也许我可以这样做。
How about instead of just say hello, there's apparently another puzzle piece where I can time it.
除了说“Hello”之外，显然还有另一个拼图块可以用来计时。
So I can maybe slow things down a little bit.
我可以把速度放慢一点。
So let me do this.
让我这样做。
Let me throw away all of this.
让我把这些都删掉。
Let me drag a say hello for two seconds.
让我拖动一个“说‘Hello’2 秒”的模块。
Let me drag another say hello for two seconds.
再拖动一个“说‘Hello’2 秒”的模块。
Let me change the first one to indeed hello, comma.
把第一个改成“Hello，”。
And then let me go back to sensing.
然后回到“侦测”模块。
Let me grab that same answer, because I threw it away a second ago, and I'll just change it.
让我抓住刚才扔掉的“回答”，把它改一下。
I don't even have to delete hello.
我甚至不需要删除“Hello”。
I can just overwrite it like this.
我可以像这样直接覆盖它。
So now I think we'll kind of pump the brakes and see things more slowly.
现在我们可以踩一下刹车，慢慢观察。
Let me stop.
停止。
Let me start.
开始。
D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
D-A-V-I-D，回车。
Hello, David.
Hello，David。
OK.
So it's better.
这样好多了。
It seems to be working.
看起来好像可以了。
I think your hypothesis was right.
我觉得你的假设是对的。
It just looks kind of stupid, right?
只是看起来有点蠢，对吧？
The fact that it's saying hello.
它只会说 “Hello”。
David, we can do better.
David，我们可以做得更好。
And literally every piece of software on your phone or Mac or PC is better than that.
实际上你手机、Mac 或 PC 上的每一个软件都比这好。
It adds words together in the user interfaces you and I are familiar with.
在你我熟悉的界面中，它们能将单词组合在一起。
So let's go a little more fishing here.
我们再试试看。
Let me throw away these.
让我把这些扔掉。
Let me go back to looks and just get the simpler say.
让我回到外观，用更简单的 “说” 就可以了。
I want this to say hello, comma, hello.
我希望它显示 “Hello，”。
Name, where name comes from that answer return value.
其中 “name” 来自答案返回值。
So how can I do this?
那我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me go under operations, which we haven't been before.
让我看看 “操作”，我们之前没看过。
There's a lot of stuff in here.
这里面有很多东西。
Some of it's mathematically related, adding, subtracting, and so forth.
有些是跟数学相关的，加法、减法等等。
You can generate random numbers, which might be useful.
你可以生成随机数，这可能会有用。
And if I keep scrolling down, there's this join apple and banana.
如果我继续往下滚动，会看到 “连接苹果和香蕉”。
But that's just placeholder text.
但这只是占位符文本。
You can join one piece of text with another piece of text.
你可以将一段文本与另一段文本连接起来。
By default, apple and banana, but let's change it to hello and my name.
默认情况下是 apple 和 banana，但让我们将其更改为 hello 和 my name。
So this too, wrong size but right shape.
所以这个也是，大小错误但形状正确。
So let me let it snap into place.
让我把它放到正确的位置。
Let me go ahead now and do hello, comma.
现在让我继续，输入 hello，逗号。
And now I think I just want to go grab that answer return value.
现在我想我要获取答案返回值。
Let me drag the same oval as before, clobber that is overwrite banana.
让我拖动与之前相同的椭圆形，覆盖掉 banana。
So now I'm kind of composing functions, the output of one function,
所以现在我有点像在组合函数，一个函数的输出，
Join is going to be the input of another function, say.
Join 将成为另一个函数的输入，比如说。
So let's see what happens now that they're kind of stacked on top of each other or nested, so to speak.
让我们看看现在它们相互堆叠或嵌套在一起会发生什么，可以这么说。
Click the green arrow, a green flag, d-a-v-i-d, Enter.
单击绿色箭头，绿色旗帜，d-a-v-i-d，回车。
Hello, David.
Hello，David。
All right, that was pretty fast.
这很快。
Let's just do it once more.
让我们再做一次。
Stop, start, here we go, d-a-v-i-d, Enter.
停止，开始，我们开始，d-a-v-i-d，回车。
OK, right, it's not the most exciting program in the world, but it's more correct.
它不是世界上最令人兴奋的程序，但它更正确。
It's better designed just because that's what you would kind of expect the software to do and not be some kind of lame user interface that's just inserting random delays to just make it kind of work.
它的设计更好，因为这是你期望软件应该做到的，而不是那种糟糕的用户界面，只是插入随机延迟来让它勉强工作。
Like, that's a workaround, a hack, if you will.
如果你愿意，那是一种变通方法，一种技巧。
But there's some cool things you can do with Scratch.
但是你可以用 Scratch 做一些很酷的事情。
And we won't really go down the rabbit hole of all of the fun and family-friendly features that it has, but there is one that's kind of cool here.
我们不会深入探讨它所有有趣和适合家庭的功能，但这里有一个很酷的功能。
Let me go into the Extensions button at the bottom left of my screen.
点击屏幕左下角的“扩展”按钮。
And this one's kind of cool.
这个功能很酷。
Let me go to text to speech.
我们来看看“文本转语音”。
And you'll notice that this one requires internet because it's cloud-based.
你会注意到，这个功能需要联网，因为它基于云端。
But this just gave me some new puzzle pieces in a new category, text to speech.
这给了我一些新的拼图碎片，一个新的类别——文本转语音。
And these green ones do exactly what they say.
这些绿色的积木的功能和它们的名字一样。
So let me do this.
我们来试试。
Let me zoom out again.
缩小一点。
Let me keep the join block.
保留“连接”积木。
And I'm just going to temporarily toss it over here.
我暂时把它扔到这边。
It's not going to delete itself because I didn't drag it over to the other side.
它不会消失，因为我没有把它拖到另一边。
But I'm going to get rid of the say block in purple.
我要把紫色的“说”积木删除。
I'm going to do the speak block here in green and let it snap into place.
我要用绿色的“朗读”积木，把它放到合适的位置。
And then I'm going to drag and drop this onto the input to speak.
然后我把这个拖放到“朗读”的输入框中。
And now, perhaps a little more adorably, let's try this.
现在，也许会更可爱一点，我们试试这个。
Green flag.
点击绿旗。
What's your name?
what's your name?
D-A-V-I-D.
D-A-V-I-D。
Enter.
回车。
And?
然后呢？
OK, it's a little robotic, but at least now it has synthesized speech.
虽然有点机械化，但至少现在它能合成语音了。
And I've kind of got my own Siri or Google Assistant or Alexa thing going on here now, where it's now recognized whatever text it is and it's played it.
现在我好像有了自己的 Siri、Google Assistant 或 Alexa，它可以识别任何文字并播放出来。
Well, let's make this an actual cat that doesn't talk in that weird human voice.
我们来让这只猫不要再用那种奇怪的人声说话了。
Let me go ahead and get rid of most of this stuff.
我先把这些东西大部分都去掉。
And let's get the cat to actually meow like a cat tends to.
我们让猫像真正的猫一样喵喵叫。
And let me go under the Sounds block.
我们进入“声音”模块。
Now, MIT gives you a few sounds for free because it's designed around a cat by default.
MIT 默认提供了一些免费的声音，因为它是围绕着一只猫设计的。
And I'm going to go ahead and grab this one.
我要用这个。
Play sound meow until done.
播放声音“meow”直到结束。
And now, we saw or heard a teaser for this earlier in the crowd.
我们之前在人群中听到过这个声音的预告。
It's a little piercing, admittedly.
不得不承认，这声音有点刺耳。
We can lower the volume a little bit there.
我们可以把音量调低一点。
But notice, if I want the cat to meow a second time, I'll just click it again.
注意，如果我想让猫再叫一声，我只需要再点击一次。
And over there, too, I hear.
我也听到了。
OK, all right, so it's kind of cute now, right?
现在有点可爱了，对吧？
So it's just meow.
只是喵了一声。
OK, yes, echo, echo.
是的，回声，回声。
So it's meowing now every time I hit the green flag.
现在每次我点击绿旗，它都会喵喵叫。
Now, that's great, but even a kid is probably going to, like, would prefer that it just meow, perhaps, like, again and again without having to keep hitting the button.
这很好，但即使是孩子，可能也会更希望它不停地喵喵叫，而不需要一直按按钮。
So how might we do this?
那我们该怎么做呢？
All right, well, if I wanted to meow multiple times, why don't I just, like, grab it another time?
如果我想让它喵好几次，我不能直接再抓取一次吗？
And another time, alternatively, you can right click or control click a puzzle piece and just duplicate it from a little menu that drops down.
或者，你可以右键单击或按住 Control 键单击一个拼图块，然后从弹出的菜单中选择复制。
So here we go, three meows.
这样就有了三个“喵”。
All right, that's not really a happy cat, it sounds.
好吧，听起来这只猫不太高兴。
Maybe hungry.
可能是饿了。
So can we slow that down?
那我们可以放慢速度吗？
Well, maybe.
也许可以。
In fact, if I poke around, let me go under Control.
我找找看，我去“控制”类别下看看。
Looks like there's a wait block.
看起来这里有一个“等待”积木。
Wait one second by default.
默认等待一秒钟。
And notice, Scratch will be pretty accommodating.
注意，Scratch 非常灵活。
If you just hover in between blocks, it will grow to fill that too.
如果你将鼠标悬停在两个积木之间，它会自动填充到那里。
So I could change it to one or two or anything seconds.
所以我可以把它改成 1 秒、2 秒或任意秒。
I'll just leave it at the default for now one.
现在我将保留默认值 1 秒。
And now I'll go ahead and do this.
现在我开始运行了。
OK, so cuter and less hungry and just more friendly.
现在更可爱了，也不饿了，更友好了。
But this isn't the best design.
但这并不是最佳设计。
It is correct.
它是正确的。
And let's use that as a term of art.
让我们把这作为一个专业术语。
Correct means the code does what you want it to do.
“正确”意味着代码按你的预期执行。
I want the cat to meow three times, slowly, and it did.
我希望猫慢慢地叫三声，它做到了。
So I'd wager this is correct.
我敢打赌这是对的。
But it's not the best design.
但这不是最好的设计。
And this is where things get more subjective, right?
这就是事情变得更加主观的地方，对吧？
Like, you could write accurate sentences in an essay for an English class, but otherwise, it's just completely a mess, like your arguments here and there.
就像，你可以用英语课上写出语法正确的句子，但在其他方面，它完全是一团糟，就像你到处都是的论点一样。
And you don't say anything wrong, but you don't say it well.
你没有说错什么，但你也没有说好。
In the context of code, we can do better than this.
在代码的上下文中，我们可以做得更好。
And copy, paste, or repeating yourself again and again tends to be bad practice.
一遍又一遍地复制、粘贴或重复自己往往是不好的做法。
Why?
为什么？
Suppose that you want to change the weight to two seconds instead of one.
假设你想把时间改成两秒而不是一秒。
It's admittedly not a big deal.
诚然，这没什么大不了的。
Fine, I click there.
好吧，我点击这里。
I change it to two.
我把它改成2。
I click there.
我点击这里。
I change it to two.
我把它改成2。
But what if you, now, five times, 10 times?
但是如果你现在有5次，10次呢？
Now I have to change the weight, like, in five, 10 different places?
现在我必须在5个、10个不同的地方改变时间？
Like, that's just stupid.
那太蠢了。
It's taking unnecessary human time.
这会浪费不必要的人力时间。
And you're going to screw up eventually.
你最终会搞砸的。
Especially if your program's getting longer, you're going to miss one of the inputs.
特别是当你的程序越来越长，你可能会漏掉一个输入。
You're going to leave the number wrong.
你可能会输入错误的数字。
And that's a bug.
这就是一个 bug。
So just based on what you've seen already, or if you've programmed before, which a few of you have, what's the term of art here that will solve this?
根据你已经看到的，或者如果你以前编写过程序，有些人已经编写过，那么解决这个问题的技术手段是什么？
How could we design this better?
我们怎样才能更好地设计它？
I heard it here.
我听到了。
Yeah, so a loop, a loop, some kind of cycle that says, do that again, do that again.
循环，某种循环，它表示再次执行，再次执行。
Not infinitely many times necessarily, but some finite number.
不一定无限次，而是有限的次数。
Well, you can perhaps see a spoiler on the screen.
你可能已经在屏幕上看到了答案。
Under the same orange control category is a repeat block.
在相同的橙色控制类别下，有一个“重复”块。
And by default, it's proposing 10, but we can change that.
默认情况下，它是 10 次，但我们可以更改它。
So let me do this.
我来演示一下。
I'm going to throw away most of this copy paste as redundant.
我要删除大部分重复的复制粘贴内容。
I'm going to detach this temporarily just to make room for something else.
我将暂时分离这个，以便为其他内容腾出空间。
And I'm going to drag a repeat block over here.
我要把一个“重复”块拖到这里。
And let that snap into place.
让它吸附到位。
And I'm going to change it for now just to be 3 for consistency.
为了保持一致性，我现在将其更改为 3。
And this is the correct shape, even though it's too small.
这就是正确的形状，即使它太小。
But Scratch will accommodate that for us.
但 Scratch 会为我们调整它。
And now, same output, but arguably better designed.
现在，输出相同，但设计 arguably 更好。
Why?
为什么？
Because if I want to change the number of meows, I change it in one place.
因为如果我想改变喵叫的次数，我只需要在一个地方改。
No copy-paste messiness.
不用复制粘贴，一团糟。
If I want to change the weighting, one place.
如果我想改变权重，也是一个地方。
I don't have to change it in multiple places and not screw up.
我不需要在多个地方改，还搞砸。
So let me hit the green flag.
让我点击绿旗。
All right, so nice.
很不错。
Now, it would have been nice if MIT had just given us a meow block that just automates all of this for us.
如果麻省理工学院能直接给我们一个喵叫块来自动完成这一切就好了。
Let me wager.
我敢打赌。
They gave us the low-level implementation details.
他们给了我们底层的实现细节。
They gave us the play sound meow.
他们给了我们播放声音“喵”。
But I had to implement a decent number of blocks just to get a cat to meow again and again.
但我必须实现很多块才能让猫一遍又一遍地喵叫。
I feel like we should have gotten that for free from MIT.
我觉得我们应该从麻省理工学院免费得到这个。
Well, they don't have to be the only ones that invent blocks for us to use.
他们不一定是唯一能为我们发明块的人。
You can write your own functions, your own verbs or actions.
你可以编写自己的函数，自己的动词或动作。
So how can we do this?
那我们该怎么做呢？
Let's make our own puzzle piece called Meow that uses this code but creates it in such a way that it's reusable elsewhere.
让我们创建自己的拼图块，叫做“喵”，它使用这段代码，但要以一种可以在其他地方重复使用的方式创建它。
So let me do this.
让我来做。
Under my blocks in pink here, I'm going to go ahead and click, literally, Make a Block.
在我的块下面，粉红色的这里，我要点击“创建块”。
Now, here's an interface by which I can give the block a name.
现在，这里有一个界面，我可以给这个块起个名字。
M-E-O-W will be the name of this block.
这个积木的名字就叫“喵”。
And I'm just going to go ahead and quickly click OK.
我直接点“确定”。
That just gives me a very generic pink puzzle piece that starts with the word define, because Scratch is asking me to define, that is, implement or create this new puzzle piece for me.
这创建了一个很普通的粉色拼图块，上面写着“定义”。Scratch 要求我定义，也就是实现或创建这个新的拼图块。
Well, what does it mean to meow?
“喵”是什么意思呢？
I'm going to claim that it means to do these two steps, to play the sound meow and then just wait for one second.
我认为它指的是执行这两个步骤：播放声音“喵”，然后等待一秒钟。
But what's powerful about this idea is look at this up top.
但这个想法的强大之处在于，看这里。
Now that I've made a block, it exists in Scratch.
现在我创建了一个积木，它就存在于 Scratch 中了。
MIT didn't need to create this for me.
MIT 不需要为我创建它。
I created it for myself, and even you, if we end up sharing code.
我自己创建的，如果我们最终共享代码，你也可以使用它。
So I can now drag meow up in here.
所以现在我可以把“喵”拖到这里。
And what's nice about meow is that itself is, yes, a function, but it's also an abstraction.
“喵”的好处在于，它本身是一个函数，但它也是一种抽象。
Like, never again do I, or even you, Need to worry or care about what it means to meow or implement it.
就像，我，甚至你，再也不用担心或关心“喵”是什么意思或如何实现它。
I can sort of drag it out of the way.
我可以把它拖到一边。
I didn't delete it.
我没有删除它。
Drag it out of the way, out of sight, out of mind.
把它拖到一边，眼不见心不烦。
Why?
为什么呢？
Because my code is now even better designed, in some sense, because it's more readable.
因为我的代码现在设计得更好了，在某种意义上，因为它更易读了。
What is it doing?
它在做什么？
When the green flag is clicked, repeat three times, meow.
当点击绿旗时，重复三次“喵”。
It just says what it means.
它就是它的字面意思。
And so it's a lot easier to read it, and it's a lot easier to think about it, especially if you're using meow in other projects, too.
所以它更容易阅读，也更容易理解，特别是如果你在其他项目中也使用 meow 的话。
Now, let me go ahead and hit Click Play.
现在，让我点击“播放”。
Same thing, so it's not really fundamentally any different.
结果一样，所以它本质上没有任何不同。
But I can make this custom puzzle piece, this own function of mine, meow, even more powerful.
但我可以让这个自定义拼图块，也就是我自己的函数 meow，变得更强大。
Let me kind of rewind a bit and go to my meow puzzle piece.
让我稍微倒回去一点，回到我的 meow 拼图块。
And I am going to Control-click or right-click on my pink puzzle piece, and I'm going to edit it.
我将按住 Control 键并单击或右键单击我的粉色拼图块，然后点击“编辑”。
So I kind of regret making meow so simple.
我有点后悔把 meow 设置得这么简单。
Wouldn't it be nice if meow took an input, a.k.a. an argument, that tells meow how many times to meow?
如果 meow 可以接受一个输入，也就是一个参数，来告诉 meow 要发出多少次叫声，那不是很好吗？
Then I can get rid of that loop and just tell meow how many meows I actually want.
然后我就可以摆脱那个循环，直接告诉 meow 我到底想要多少声叫声。
So I'm going to click on another button here called literally add an input.
所以我将点击这里另一个按钮，叫做“添加输入”。
And it's going to have placeholder here.
这里会有一个占位符。
So I'm just going to put a placeholder there.
所以我就在那里放一个占位符。
I keep using n for number, which is a go to in computer scientist terms.
我会继续使用 n 来表示数字，这是计算机科学家常用的一个表达方式。
And I'm going to add some descriptive text just so that it's a little more self-explanatory.
我将添加一些描述性文字，这样它就更容易理解了。
I'm just going to say meow n times.
我只会写上“发出 n 次猫叫声”。
But there's only one oval.
但这里只有一个椭圆形。
Times is just going to be explanatory text.
“次”只是一个解释性文字。
And now notice what has happened.
现在注意发生了什么。
Now my puzzle piece takes an input, a.k.a. an argument, that will tell that function to meow some number of times.
现在我的拼图块接受一个输入，也就是 一个参数，它会告诉函数要喵叫多少次。
But it's not just going to work magically.
但它不会魔法般地工作。
I need to implement that lower level detail.
我需要实现更底层的细节。
So let me zoom out.
让我缩小一下。
I have to remind myself what this function was.
我得提醒自己这个函数是什么。
I'm going to drag it higher up just so they're on the screen at the same time.
我要把它拖高一点，这样它们就能同时出现在屏幕上了。
I'm going to go ahead now and temporarily move this over here.
我要继续，暂时把它移到这里。
I'm going to temporarily detach this over here.
我要暂时把它分离到这里。
Why?
为什么？
Because what I think I want to do is move my loop into the function itself.
因为我认为我想做的是把循环移到函数本身。
Move the play and the weight into the loop.
把播放和等待移到循环中。
But I don't want to hard code 3.
但我不想硬编码
Notice that n here is its own oval.
注意，这里的 n 是它自己的椭圆形。
I can drag a copy of n and just let it go there.
我可以拖动 n 的副本，然后把它放在那里。
So now I have a new version of meow that takes an argument, n, that tells meow how many times to meow.
所以现在我有了一个新版本的 meow，它接受一个参数 n，告诉 meow 要喵叫多少次。
And now, let me again drag this out of sight, out of mind, because who cares how I implemented it?
现在，让我再次把它拖到看不见的地方，眼不见为净，因为谁在乎我是怎么实现它的呢？
Once it's implemented, it's sort of done.
一旦实现，就相当于完成了。
Now my program is even better designed in some sense.
现在，在某种意义上，我的程序设计得更好了。
Why?
为什么？
Because now it really just says what it means.
因为现在它确实表达了它的含义。
There's no loop.
没有循环。
There's no implementation details.
没有实现细节。
When green flag clicked, meow three times.
当绿旗被点击时，发出三次“喵”的声音。
And so functions indeed let you implement algorithms.
函数确实可以让你实现算法。
They're just code that do something for you.
它们只是为你做某事的代码。
But they're also themselves abstractions.
但它们本身也是抽象。
Why?
为什么？
Because once a function exists, it has a name.
因为一旦函数存在，它就有一个名字。
Think about it in that term, and you can use it by its name.
从这个角度思考，你可以通过它的名字来使用它。
You don't have to care or remember how the function itself was built, whether it's by you or even MIT.
你不需要关心或记住函数本身是如何构建的，无论是你还是麻省理工学院构建的。
So again, here, I'll click the green flag.
我再次点击绿旗。
It's the same thing.
结果是一样的。
So still correct, but better and better designed.
仍然正确，但设计得越来越好。
And so any time here and out with Scratch or soon C and eventually Python, when you find yourself doing anything resembling copy paste or again and again grabbing the same code, probably an opportunity to say, wait a minute, let me refactor this, so to speak.
在 Scratch，或者是 C 语言，以及最终的 Python 中，当你发现自己在做任何类似于复制粘贴的事情，
或者一遍又一遍地抓取相同的代码时，这可能是一个让你停下来思考的机会，等等，让我重构一下这段代码。
That is, rip out the code that seems to be repeated again and again and put it in its own function so you can give it a descriptive name and use and reuse it.
也就是说，把那些似乎重复了一遍又一遍的代码提取出来，放到它自己的函数中，这样你就可以给它一个描述性的名字，并且可以反复使用它。
Any questions just yet on now saying, or these loops, or these functions that we're using?
关于我们现在说的循环或函数，还有什么问题吗？
Yeah.
有。
How did I make it so it meows three times?
我是怎么让它发出三次“喵”的声音的？
So I originally only had a puzzle piece called Meow, and I decided to improve it.
我最初只有一个叫做“喵”的拼图块，我决定改进它。
So I held down Control, and I right-clicked or Control-clicked on the pink puzzle piece at top left, and I clicked Edit.
我按住 Control 键，然后右键单击或 Control 加单击左上角的粉色拼图块，然后单击“编辑”。
And that brought back the original interface that lets me add some arguments to the puzzle piece itself.
它会回到初始界面，允许我给拼图块本身添加一些参数。
And I clicked Add an Input on the left here, and then I clicked on Add a Label over here.
我点击左边这里的“添加输入”，然后点击上面的“添加标签”。
So that just lets you customize it even further.
这样就可以进一步自定义它。
All right, so we've done this.
我们已经做完了。
Let's add one of those other primitives, too, to do something optionally.
让我们再添加一个基本元素，来做一些可选的操作。
So how about we make the cat meow only if it's being petted by a human, as by moving the mouse to hover over the cat like a human would pet a cat?
比如，我们让猫只有在被人类抚摸时才喵喵叫，就像移动鼠标悬停在猫身上，就像人类抚摸猫一样？
Well, let me go ahead and throw away the meowing for now.
让我先把喵喵叫声去掉。
And let me simplify it by just using a sound.
让我简化一下，只用一种声音。
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要这样做。
I'm going to go ahead and have a control block that says if, because I want to implement the idea of if the cursor is touching the cat, then play sound meow.
我要使用一个控制块，上面写着“如果”，因为我想实现“如果光标碰到猫，就播放喵喵声”的想法。
Or I could use my same pink puzzle piece, but I'm going to throw that away and focus only now on the sounds.
或者我可以使用相同的粉色拼图块，但我现在要把它扔掉，只关注声音。
And I'm going to do this.
我要这样做。
Touching mouse pointer, so I need to sense something about the world.
“碰到鼠标指针”，所以我需要感知外界的一些信息。
And we saw this earlier.
我们之前见过这个。
So if touching mouse pointer, so notice this shape here, way too big, but it is the right shape.
所以“如果碰到鼠标指针”，注意这里的形状，太大了，但形状是正确的。
So if I hover just right, it'll snap into place.
如果我将鼠标悬停在正确的位置，它就会卡进去。
And this now in blue is my Boolean expression, a yes, no question, true, false.
现在这个蓝色的部分是我的布尔表达式，一个“是”或“否”的问题，真或假。
If is a conditional.
“如果”是一个条件语句。
And what do I want to do?
我想做什么？
Well, if the cat is touching the mouse pointer, I want to go ahead and play sound meow until done.
如果猫碰到鼠标指针，我想播放“喵”的声音，直到播放完成。
So let's do this.
我们来试试。
I'm going to hit green flag, click.
我要点击绿旗，点击。
Now, nothing's happened yet because it's a conditional, right?
现在什么也没发生，因为它是一个条件语句，对吧？
It's only supposed to do something if I'm touching the cat.
只有当我碰到猫的时候，它才会执行。
Let me move the cursor over to the cat and, and, and, wait for it.
让我把光标移到猫身上，等等。
Hmm. Another bug.
又是一个 bug。
Why is the cat not meowing, even though I very explicitly said, if touching mouse pointer, meow?
为什么猫没有叫，即使我明确地说过，如果碰到鼠标指针，就喵一声？
Yeah, in the middle.
是的，在中间。
Yeah, this is, again, my computers are so darn fast.
这也是因为我的电脑太快了。
Like yours, I click the green flag, it asks the question, am I touching the mouse pointer?
和你们的一样，我点击绿旗，它会问一个问题，我是否碰到了鼠标指针？
Well, no, because my cursor was up there not touching the cat.
没有，因为我的光标在上面，没有碰到猫。
It's too late. The cat's out of the bag.
太晚了。 木已成舟。
And so we have to instead solve this some other means, by some other means.
所以我们必须用其他方法来解决这个问题。
How can we fix this?
我们该如何解决这个问题？
How do we fix that sort of race?
我们如何解决这种竞争条件？
Yeah?
是吗?
Yeah, so why don't we just keep asking the question until I eventually am or am not actually petting the cat?
我们可以一直询问这个问题，直到我最终真的在抚摸猫或者没有抚摸猫？
So let me detach this temporarily.
我暂时把它断开。
Let me go under Control.
然后进入“控制”。
Let me go under, instead of repeat some finite number of times, let's just do it forever.
进入之后，我们不再重复有限次数，而是永远重复。
So sometimes loops that do work forever are a good thing.
所以有时永远循环的代码是件好事。
Like the clock on your phone, that's in a loop forever because you want it to always tell time and not stop at the end of the day.
比如你手机上的时钟，它就永远循环，因为你希望它一直显示时间，而不是在一天结束后停止。
So sometimes you do want code to loop forever.
所以有时你确实希望代码永远循环。
As in this case.
就像这种情况。
So let me go ahead and drag and drop it there.
我把它拖放到这里。
Let me again click the green flag.
再次点击绿旗。
Nothing's happening yet, but notice the program's still running.
虽然什么也没发生，但程序仍在运行。
And so if I move my cursor, move my cursor, move my cursor, and.
如果我移动光标，移动光标，移动光标，然后……
Oh, OK.
哦，好吧。
So maybe we could add some weighting, but.
也许我们可以加一些权重，
The cat does not want to be pet in this case, but it's indeed conditional.
这只猫不想在这种情况下被抚摸，但这确实是条件性的。
So there we have an incarnation in Scratch of doing something conditionally.
这就是 Scratch 中条件执行的例子。
Now, we can make this really cool really fast, if you will.
我们可以很快地把它变得更酷。
Let me stop this version.
我先停止这个版本。
Let me go ahead and do this.
接下来我这样做。
Let me go ahead and throw all of this away.
我把这些都删掉。
Let me go into my little extensions bucket over here.
进入“扩展”部分。
And let me do video sensing, since most laptops or phones these days have cameras.
让我来试试视频感应，现在大部分笔记本电脑和手机都有摄像头。
And there, indeed, I am with Sanders behind me.
看，我在，Sanders 在我身后。
And let me do this.
让我来试试这个。
When video motion, and let me get out of the way.
当视频画面运动，我先躲开。
When video motion is greater than some value, so 10 is the default.
当视频画面运动大于某个值时，默认是 10。
This is just a number that measures how much motion there is or isn't.
这个数字表示画面运动的程度。
So a small number is like no motion.
数字小就代表画面基本不动。
Big number is lots of motion.
数字大就代表画面运动剧烈。
So I'm going to choose 50 somewhat arbitrarily here.
我随意选个 50。
So 50.
就是 50。
This is not normal to program off to the side.
把程序写到旁边不符合规范。
But I'm now going to say this.
但我现在要这么做。
When video motion is 50, go ahead and play sound meow like this.
当视频画面运动程度达到 50，播放「喵」的声音。
So the cat is still in that world.
猫还在那个世界里。
I'm going to stop the program and rerun it.
我要停止程序，重新运行。
So here we go.
来了。
Green flag.
绿旗。
And now here come.
我来了。
All right, this is a little creepy the way I'm petting the cat, but.
好吧，我这样撸猫有点吓人，但是。
And.
然后。
Ah, OK.
There we go.
这就对了。
OK, so 50 was too big of a number.
50 这个数字太大了。
I have to pet the cat faster.
我得更快地抚摸猫咪。
Whereas this, if I don't know.
然而这个，我不知道。
Yeah, so.
OK, so you can make things even more interactive in this way by just assembling different puzzle pieces.
你可以通过组合不同的拼图块，让事情变得更具互动性。
And honestly, there are so many different puzzle pieces in here.
老实说，这里有太多不同的拼图块了。
We're not going to even scratch the surface of a lot of them.
我们甚至不会触及其中很多内容的皮毛。
But they generally just do what they say.
但它们通常只是按字面意思执行。
And indeed, when you see on the screen here, this palette of puzzle pieces, really a lot of programming, especially early on when learning a language, is just trying different things.
事实上，当你在这里的屏幕上看到这些拼图块的时候，很多编程，尤其是在学习一门语言的早期，就是在尝试不同的东西。
And try and fail, and if it doesn't work quite, look for.
尝试并失败，如果它不能正常工作，就寻找。
Doesn't work quite right.
不能正常工作。
Look for an alternative solution there, too, as even I just had to do a moment ago.
就像我刚才那样，寻找另一种解决方案。
Well, let's go ahead and use, actually, how about another example of something a predecessor of yours made?
我们继续，实际上，不如看看你的前辈做的另一个例子？
Let me go ahead and grab a program I opened in advance here called whack-a-mole.
让我打开一个我提前打开的程序，叫做 whack-a-mole。
Might we get a brave volunteer to come up who is willing to whack-a-mole with their head virtually?
我们能请一位勇敢的志愿者上来，用他们的头在虚拟世界里玩打地鼠吗？
Maybe.
也许吧。
OK.
Let's see.
让我们看看。
How about way back?
以前呢？
You want to come on down?
你想下来吗？
All right.
Come on down.
下来吧。
And in just a moment, sure, a round of applause for our volunteer.
稍等片刻，当然，请大家为我们的志愿者鼓掌。
All right.
So here we have, come on down.
我们来看看，下来吧。
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Oh, actually, say it into the microphone.
实际上，对着麦克风说。
OK, nice.
很好。
Welcome, Josh.
欢迎你，Josh。
Come on over.
过来吧。
All right, so same idea here.
想法一样。
I'll take the mic back.
我把麦克风拿回来。
You'll have to stand in front of the camera.
你得站在摄像机前面。
In just a moment, you're going to have to position your head in a box that your classmate from yesteryear created.
稍等片刻，你得把头放在你去年同学创建的盒子里。
And we'll start with beginner.
我们从初学者开始。
So line your head up in the box at the moment.
现在把你的头对准盒子里。
12 seconds.
12 秒。
5 seconds.
5 秒。
Notice the score is up to 18 already.
注意，分数已经达到 18 分了。
Pretty good.
很棒。
All right, a round of applause for Josh, if we could.
我们一起为 Josh 鼓掌。
So notice how using some fairly simple primitives, things do get interesting pretty fast.
可以看到，使用一些相当简单的元素，事情很快就变得有趣了。
And how was that implemented?
这是怎么实现的呢？
Well, there were probably at least four sprites.
至少有四个 sprites。
So you're not confined to just one cat.
所以你并不局限于只有一只猫。
You can create more and more sprites, change what they look like.
你可以创建越来越多的 sprites，改变它们的外观。
So they actually look like a mole in this case.
所以在这个例子中，它们实际上看起来像鼹鼠。
There's probably some conditionals in there, some loops for 30 seconds that's checking if Josh's head's movement is
里面可能有一些条件语句，一些循环会持续 30 秒，用于检查 Josh 头部的移动是否
Exceeding some value over this way or over this way, then increment something called a variable.
超过这边或那边的某个值，然后增加一个叫做变量的东西。
We'll see those two.
我们稍后会看到这些。
Just like in algebra, you might have x and y and z storing values like numbers.
就像在代数中，你可能有 x、y 和 z 存储数字这样的值。
So can computer programs have variables called x or y or z, or more descriptively, called score.
计算机程序也可以有叫做 x、y 或 z 的变量，或者更具描述性的，叫做 score。
As in this case, at top right.
就像在这个例子中，在右上角。
Or another variable called countdown.
或者另一个叫做 countdown 的变量。
Typically one word in code, but in this case, two words that just store some value.
通常在代码中是一个词，但在这个例子中，是两个词存储了一些值。
So there's probably some math going on in there, whereby the author of this program just is incrementing.
所以里面可能有一些数学运算，这个程序的作者只是在递增。
That is, adding one and one every time it detected that a mole had been whacked, in this case, with movement.
也就是说，每次检测到一只鼹鼠被击中时，在这个例子中是用动作击中，就加一。
So back in the day, I myself, actually,
回想当年，我自己，实际上，
Implemented my very first program in Scratch when I was at a graduate student actually at MIT, cost registered at MIT, taking a class from MIT's Media Lab, specifically the lifelong kindergarten group, which is the group that created Scratch itself.
实际上，我第一个程序是用 Scratch 写的，当时我还是麻省理工学院的研究生，
在麻省理工学院注册，在麻省理工学院媒体实验室上课，特别是“终身幼儿园”小组，也就是创造 Scratch 的小组。
And the program I wrote all those years ago And still rather cling to is a little something here called Oscar time that I thought I'd play just a quick excerpt of myself here.
多年前我写了这个程序， 至今仍然很喜欢它，它叫做 Oscar time，我想在这里播放一小段我自己录制的片段。
So in this case, consider as the music starts playing how this program, which is much more sophisticated certainly than the earliest say hello examples we just did, might also be implemented.
当音乐开始播放时，想一想这个程序，它当然比我们刚才看到的第一个 say hello 例子要复杂得多，它可能是如何实现的。
Let me go ahead now and click the green flag.
我现在要点击绿旗了。
So some trash is moving, presumably in some kind of loop from the top.
一些垃圾正在移动，可能是从顶部开始的某种循环。
If I'm touching the mouse cursor, it follows me.
如果我触碰鼠标光标，它就会跟着我。
If I hover over the trash can, it responds.
如果我把鼠标悬停在垃圾桶上，它就会有反应。
If I let go, in some kind of loop, Oscar pops out, creates a variable with the current score, and it happens again.
如果我松开鼠标，在某种循环中，Oscar 就会跳出来，用当前的分数创建一个变量，然后再次发生。
Pretty easy at first.
一开始很简单。
So I don't need to keep playing this up on stage in front of everyone.
我不需要一直在台上给大家演示这个游戏。
So my score is already now up to some six or so.
我的分数已经涨到六分左右了。
But in a moment, too, you'll see that it's going to escalate.
但一会儿你就会看到，难度会升级。
So I'm taking into account some time, apparently.
显然，我正在考虑时间因素。
So now I have here some newspaper.
现在我这里有一些报纸。
So more and more sprites are suddenly appearing.
越来越多的精灵突然出现了。
And notice that each time they're appearing from a different part of the screen.
注意，每次它们都从屏幕的不同位置出现。
That's an illusion, perhaps, to pick a random number between x and y. So you can actually pick some range of values to have the game constantly changing.
这可能是一种错觉，在 x 和 y 之间选择一个随机数，你可以选择某个范围的值，让游戏不断变化。
And indeed, I'm going to go ahead and click Stop, since I spent like eight hours plus years ago making this, and I can never listen to the song again.
我得点击“停止”了，因为我花了八年多的时间来制作它，而且我再也不能听这首歌了。
Not that I should be anyway at this point in my life.
在我人生的这个阶段，我不应该再听了。
But this song is synchronized then with a lot of the actions that's happening.
但这首歌与很多正在发生的动作同步。
And ultimately, there's just a lot of building blocks.
最终，会有很多构建块。
But I didn't sit down and implement Oscar time, as I called it, all at once.
但我没有马上坐下来实现我称之为“Oscar时间”的东西。
I really did take baby steps, so to speak.
我真的采取了循序渐进的方式。
And I figured out, well, how could I decompose this vision I had at the time to create this game ultimately?
我当时就在想，我怎样才能把我创造这个游戏的愿景分解开来呢？
And how do I bite off maybe the easiest parts first?
我如何才能先从最简单的部分开始呢？
And honestly, the first thing I did was I found this image.
说实话，我做的第一件事就是找到这张图片。
And I just like dragged and dropped it into Scratch.
我只是把它拖放到 Scratch 中。
OK, done.
好了，完成了。
Like, lamppost is installed.
路灯安装好了。
It doesn't do anything.
它什么也不做。
It's not interactive.
它不是交互式的。
But I at least set the stage, so to speak, for the program.
但我至少为程序搭建了舞台。
Then what else might I have done?
然后我还能做什么呢？
Well, let me do this.
让我试试这个。
Let me go ahead and open up in another editor here a early incarnation of Oscar Time by doing this.
让我在另一个编辑器中打开早期版本的 Oscar Time。
Let me go into Oscar Time here.
让我进入 Oscar Time。
Let me full screen this.
让我全屏显示。
And here you have, let me hide the trash for just a moment, is what I might call the second
在这里，我先把垃圾桶隐藏起来，这就是我所说的第二个
A version of my program, wherein at the top right of the stage here, I had the lamppost, which I just dragged and dropped and got going.
版本的程序，在舞台的右上角，我有路灯，我只是把它拖放进去就开始运行了。
But then I added an actual sprite.
然后我添加了一个实际的精灵。
And it has to be a sprite if you wanted to do things interactively.
如果你想进行交互式操作，它必须是一个精灵。
The lamppost, not a sprite.
灯柱不是精灵。
It's just an image, a costume, if you will, for the whole stage itself, a backdrop.
它只是一张图片，一个服装，如果你愿意，可以把它看作整个舞台本身的背景。
But this thing is indeed a sprite because it needs to respond to code and events like dragging and dropping.
但这个东西确实是一个精灵，因为它需要响应代码和事件，比如拖放。
So what might I have done early on with that code?
那么我之前用代码做了些什么呢？
Well, maybe the first version.
也许是第一个版本。
Would have been something like this, whereby my very first version of Oscar time might have said something like, oh, this.
可能是这样的，我的第一个版本的 Oscar time 可能会说，这个。
How about let me control the program as before, or rather events.
不如让我像以前那样控制程序，或者说是事件。
When the green flag is clicked, what do I want to do?
当点击绿旗时，我想做什么？
Well, I want to go ahead and forever.
我想继续，永远。
Do something like this forever.
永远做这样的事情。
So I want the lid to open up if I touch it.
我希望如果我触摸盖子，它就会打开。
So if the cursor gets near the lid, I want the lid to open up.
所以如果光标靠近盖子，我希望盖子打开。
And then if I move away, I want it to close.
然后如果我移开，我希望它关闭。
So how can I do that?
那么我该怎么做呢？
I want an if, but I just don't want one question.
我想要一个 if 语句，但我不想只有一个问题。
I really want two, a fork in the road that goes left or right, so to speak.
我真的想要两个，一个岔路口，可以说，向左或向右走。
And let me grab this puzzle piece here, as I did long ago.
让我抓住这个拼图块，就像很久以前一样。
So notice it grows to fill.
注意它会增长到填满。
What's the question I want to ask?
我想问什么问题？
Well, under sensing, I'm going to go ahead here and say if,
在“侦测”模块下，我要说如果，
This trash can is touching the mouse pointer.
这个垃圾桶碰到鼠标指针。
What do I want to do?
我想做什么？
Well, I want to change what the trash can looks like.
我想改变垃圾桶的外观。
And this part I did in advance of class.
这部分我在课前已经做好了。
If you go up here to costumes, this is where all the graphical stuff happens.
如果你来到“造型”这里，所有图形化的东西都在这里。
And you'll see that I imported a whole bunch of different costumes.
你会看到我导入了一堆不同的造型。
That effectively, much like a video, when you play them quickly, creates the illusion of movement, some animation.
这实际上就像视频一样，当你快速播放它们时，就会产生运动的错觉，也就是动画。
But it's really just dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, different images showing on the screen.
但实际上只是屏幕上显示的不同图像，一个接一个。
Well, some of these costumes are called like Oscar 1, Oscar 2.
其中一些造型被称为 Oscar 1、Oscar 2。
Oscar 1 is closed.
Oscar 1 是关闭的。
Oscar 2 is open.
Oscar 2 是打开的。
So let's just deal with those first.
我们先来处理这些。
So if I'm touching the mouse pointer.
所以如果我碰到鼠标指针。
Let me go under.
让我进入。
How about looks?
“外观”怎么样？
And we didn't use this before, but there's this block.
我们之前没有用过这个，但有这个代码块。
Switch costume to something else.
“切换造型”到其他造型。
I'm going to drag and drop this inside of the if.
我要把它拖放到 if 语句里面。
And notice it's a little bit indented.
注意它有点缩进。
I'm going to change it not to Oscar 8, but Oscar 2.
我要把它改成不是 Oscar 8，而是 Oscar 2。
Otherwise, if not touching the mouse pointer, this is the other direction in the fork in the road, let's go ahead and switch the costume back to what I described as Oscar 1.
否则，如果没碰到鼠标指针，这是岔路口的另一个方向，让我们继续，把服装切换回我描述的 Oscar 1。
So let me run this program.
让我来运行这个程序。
And not much of interest is happening yet.
目前还没发生什么有趣的事情。
But notice, if I move the cursor up, down.
但注意，如果我把光标向上、向下移动。
But how is that working?
但这是怎么运作的？
It's just changing the costume that's being overlaid on the sprite.
它只是改变了覆盖在精灵上的服装。
So it looks like interactivity, but you're really just changing the aesthetics.
所以它看起来像交互式的，但你实际上只是在改变美观。
And we humans are just kind of assuming, oh, it's opening up.
而我们人类只是在假设，它打开了。
Well, no. It's just changing a costume.
并没有。 它只是在换服装。
So here's the difference.
所以区别在于。
The high-level abstraction, trash can opening, the lower-level implementation detail, costume changing, creating that illusion.
高层的抽象是垃圾桶打开，而底层的实现细节是服装变化，创造了这种错觉。
And if I wanted to look prettier, I could just have many other costumes and go boom, boom, boom, boom, boom to create more frames per second, if you will.
如果我想让它看起来更漂亮，我可以使用更多其他的服装，然后砰、砰、砰、砰、砰，以创造更高的帧率。
So I need to do, um.
所以我还需要做，嗯。
One other thing, maybe if I accidentally leave the trash can open, let me make one change here.
还有一件事，也许我不小心把垃圾桶打开了，让我在这里做个修改。
Let me make sure that the very first thing I do when the green flag is clicked is always start with the trash can closed, because otherwise, you might accidentally leave it open.
让我确保在点击绿旗时，做的第一件事就是关闭垃圾桶，否则你可能会不小心把它打开。
So this gets me into some default state.
这让我进入了一个默认状态。
So now it's always closed until I manually hover over it instead.
所以现在它会一直关闭，直到我手动将鼠标悬停在它上面。
Well, what might I have done next?
接下来我该做什么？
Well, if I wanted to introduce something like the trash, I need a second sprite.
如果我想引入像垃圾桶这样的东西，我需要第二个 sprite。
And here in advance, I grab the image already.
我提前准备好了图像。
Let me pretend that this never happened.
假设这从未发生过。
Let me drag this away here.
让我把它拖到这边。
And now I have nothing in my code area for this piece of trash.
现在我的代码区域里没有这块垃圾的代码。
But it is the second sprite.
但它是第二个 sprite。
And all I did was I clicked on the little cat plus icon here.
我所做的就是点击这里的小猫加号图标。
I created a second sprite.
我创建了第二个 sprite。
I named it Trash.
我把它命名为 Trash。
I added a costume for it, sort of the aesthetic stuff I did in advance.
我为它添加了一个服装，这是我提前做的一些美学方面的工作。
But here, I'll do now the code.
但现在，我要来编写代码。
How do I want to do this?
我该怎么做呢？
Well, how about when the green flag is clicked for the trash can?
当点击垃圾桶的绿色旗帜时，会怎么样？
I want the trash can in parallel to do or I want the trash, the piece of trash, to do its own thing.
我希望垃圾桶并行地做，或者我希望垃圾，这块垃圾，做它自己的事情。
So what I want it to do is maybe let's do motion, how about.
所以我希望它做的是，也许让我们做个运动，怎么样。
And let's go to a specific coordinate.
让我们转到一个特定的坐标。
Now, there's a lot of options here.
现在，这里有很多选择。
There's turning, go to a random position, go to x comma y, glide more elegantly.
有旋转，去一个随机位置，去 x，y，更优雅地滑动。
There's a lot of different ways to implement movement.
有很多不同的方式来实现运动。
I just wanted to go to a very specific location first.
我想要先去到一个特定的位置。
So I'm just going to go to x comma y first.
我打算先去坐标 (x, y)。
And I'm going to say x, how about will be
我们把 x 设为...
Let's not hard code this.
先别把这个写死。
Let's just have it be, well, let's do it at 0 initially and then 240.
我们先把它设为，初始值设为 0，然后是 240。
So whoops.
等等。
Let's do 0 comma 240 so that this piece of trash always starts at the top middle of the screen if you think back to that coordinate system.
我们设为 (0, 240)，这样这个垃圾就会出现在屏幕顶部的中间位置，回想一下坐标系。
0, 0 is in the middle.
(0, 0) 在中间。
240 is straight above it.
240 就在它正上方。
All right.
Now, after I do that, what do I want to do?
设置好位置后，我要做什么？
Well, how about I control this thing by forever falling?
让它一直往下掉。
Now, how do I make the trash move?
怎么让垃圾动起来？
We haven't seen this puzzle piece yet, but under motion, the very first thing is called move some number of steps.
我们还没见过这个拼图块，但在“运动”模块下，第一个就是“移动特定步数”。
By default, it's 10, but we'll do it more simply.
默认值是 10，但我们简化一下。
Let me go ahead and move.
我们来移动一下。
Oh, sorry.
抱歉。
Move is going to move it in whatever direction it's facing.
“移动”会让它朝当前方向移动。
I only want it to move down.
我只想让它往下移动。
So here, even I'm getting confused as to how many different ways there are to do things.
我都被绕晕了，实现目标的方法太多了。
What I think I want to do is this.
我想做的是这样。
Let me only change my y-axis as follows.
我只想改变我的 y 轴，像这样。
So here's another puzzle piece called change y. So again, y is the vertical.
这是另一个拼图块，叫做 change y。同样，y 代表垂直方向。
So let me just change y by 1 pixel downward at a time.
让我每次将 y 向下改变 1 个像素。
So negative 1, 1 pixel at a time.
也就是 -1，每次 1 个像素。
So it's kind of slow.
这有点慢。
And I think now, I think that's it.
我想，现在这样就可以了。
Let me hit Stop.
让我点击停止。
Notice that my trash can is still going to be interactive.
注意，我的垃圾桶仍然是交互式的。
I haven't changed or deleted that code.
我没有改变或删除那段代码。
I've just added now code for my piece of trash.
我只是为我的垃圾块添加了代码。
If I click the green flag, notice that.
如果我点击绿色旗帜，请注意。
After I enable it, let me start that again.
启用后，让我重新开始。
I had it hidden before class, but let me enable it now.
上课前我把它隐藏了，现在让我启用它。
Green flag, notice it starts dead center at x equals 0, y equals 240, and it's dropping one pixel at a time.
绿色旗帜，注意它从 x = 0，y = 240 的正中心开始，每次下降 1 个像素。
If that seems a little boring, we can change it to negative 10 pixels at a time, and boom, it's done.
如果这看起来有点无聊，我们可以把它改成每次 -10 个像素，然后，砰，就完成了。
So that's how you might change the speed of a program.
这就是你改变程序速度的方法。
But I'm going to leave it more simply as negative 1.
但我还是把它简单地设为 -1。
And honestly, it would be nice if it doesn't always start from the top.
说实话，如果它不总是从顶部开始就好了。
Otherwise, this game is not going to be very interactive.
否则，这个游戏就不会那么有趣了。
I'm literally going to be grabbing the trash from the same place every time.
每次都从同一个位置抓取垃圾。
So why don't I instead stop this.
所以我不妨停止这个。
Let me go under Operators.
我们打开“运算符”。
And let's pick a random number.
选择一个随机数。
So let me change the hardcoded, the manually inputted 0.
把手动输入的 0 改掉。
And let's make x be somewhere between 0, so in the middle, and all the way over to, what was it, 1.
让 x 介于 0 到 1 之间，也就是在中间到最右边。
Oh, I got my numbers wrong, 240.
数字错了，应该是 240。
And my y will be 180.
y 是 180。
Sorry, I got my x and my y confused.
抱歉，我把 x 和 y 搞混了。
So let me play this again.
我们再玩一次。
And now we have a game that's more like games you might have played growing up or even now, like there's some randomness to it.
现在这个游戏更像大家以前或现在玩的游戏了，带有一些随机性。
So the CPU, so to speak, is doing something more interesting.
CPU 也变得更有趣了。
Let me run it again.
再运行一次。
Now it's a little to the left.
现在稍微偏左一点。
Let me run it again.
再运行一次。
Now it's a little more to the left.
现在更偏左一点。
Again, now it's back to the right.
又回到右边了。
So randomness just makes games more interesting.
随机性使游戏更有趣。
And this is why when you play any video game, if different things are happening, there's probably just some randomness.
这就是为什么玩电子游戏时，如果发生不同的事情，很可能只是随机性在起作用。
And it's quantized.
而且它是量子化的。
It's just a simple number.
它只是一个简单的数字。
Now I think I just need one final flourish here, if I may.
如果可以的话，我想我最后还需要做一点润色。
Let me go ahead and add this.
让我继续添加这个。
How about events, or rather, yes, events.
事件怎么样，或者更确切地说，对，事件。
When green flag is clicked, I can do multiple things within the same sprite.
当点击绿旗时，我可以在同一个 sprite 中做多件事。
They don't all have to be attached to the same one.
它们不一定要全部附加到同一个 sprite 上。
Let me go ahead and forever go ahead and do something else.
让我继续，永远继续做其他事情。
How about whenever the trash is, how about touching
每当垃圾桶，或者说，触摸到垃圾桶的时候。
The trash can, so forever, if, let's see, I need a sensing block.
垃圾桶，所以永远，如果，让我看看，我需要一个感知模块。
So how about is touching, not the mouse pointer this time, but touching Oscar himself there.
那么“接触”怎么样，这次不是鼠标指针，而是接触 Oscar 本身。
Now let's see what happens.
现在让我们看看会发生什么。
All right, so let's go ahead and click the green flag.
让我们继续点击绿旗。
Now I go down over here and let go.
现在我把它放到这里，然后松开。
OK, I kind of want it to go into the trash can.
我有点想让它进入垃圾桶。
How do I make it go into the trash can?
我怎样才能让它进入垃圾桶呢？
How can we take this high-level idea, put trash into the trash can, and make it seem to disappear logically?
我们怎样才能把这个高级的想法，把垃圾放进垃圾桶，并让它看起来合乎逻辑地消失呢？
What could we do?
我们可以做什么？
Yeah?
什么？
OK, so when it touches it, let's have it disappear so I could hide it.
所以当它碰到它时，让它消失，这样我就可以把它藏起来。
Or honestly, if the game's going to be ongoing like it was, letting me drop more and more trash, let me just have it go ahead and pick a new random location.
或者说实话，如果游戏要像之前那样继续进行，让我扔越来越多的垃圾，不如就让它继续，并选择一个新的随机位置。
So let me do this.
我来演示一下。
Let me go ahead and copy this puzzle piece up here and duplicate.
我复制这个拼图块。
And I don't want the whole thing, sorry.
抱歉，我不要全部。
Let me get rid of this.
我把它删掉。
Let me just do this.
就这样。
Let me go back to some random location at the top.
回到顶部一个随机位置。
So now notice what happens.
注意观察。
If I click and drag on it, here it goes.
如果我点击并拖动它，它就会这样。
And I let go.
我松开鼠标。
It looks like it's going into the trash can because it snaps back up to some random location.
它看起来像是掉进了垃圾桶，因为它弹回到一个随机的位置。
Now, the only thing I'm not doing, really, is keeping track of any kind of score.
我唯一没做的是记录分数。
And it turns out, if I full screen this, it's not going to be draggable by default.
事实证明，如果我把它全屏显示，它默认是不能拖动的。
So just as a corner case, so to speak, something that you might trip over otherwise, let me go ahead and under.
举个例子，你可能会遇到这种情况，让我来演示一下。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
Sensing, it turns out I also need this for the piece of trash.
感应部分，我发现垃圾桶也需要这个。
There's this way of setting in Scratch a sprite to be draggable or not draggable.
在 Scratch 中有一种方法可以设置一个精灵是否可以拖动。
I need to explicitly make it draggable so that when I do full screen this thing now, it still remains draggable.
我需要明确地让它可以拖动，这样当我把它全屏显示时，它仍然可以拖动。
And someone like myself can play it again and again.
然后像我这样的人就可以一遍又一遍地玩了。
Well, how about we supplement this with one final flourish?
我们再给它加点花样怎么样？
Why don't we keep track now of the user score?
我们来记录用户的分数吧。
So how about when?
那什么时候呢？
The user actually drags the piece of trash to the trash can.
用户将垃圾拖到垃圾桶里的时候。
Let me go under variables here, where in advance, I've already made myself a variable called score.
我们来看看变量，我已经提前创建了一个名为“score”的变量。
I could have called it x or y or z or abc, but that's not very descriptive.
我本来可以把它叫做 x、y、z 或者 abc，但这不够直观。
In programming, you typically give things a more descriptive English or some other language name.
在编程中，通常会给变量起一个更具描述性的英文或其他语言的名字。
So I called this one score.
所以我把这个变量叫做“score”。
So how do I want to do this in my score?
那我要如何在“score”中实现这个功能呢？
Well, let me go ahead and initially set this game's score to 0 at the very top of one of these scripts or one of these programs up here.
首先，我要在程序脚本的最开始将游戏分数初始化为 0。
And then any time my piece of trash is touching Oscar, let's not just jump to the top.
当垃圾碰到 Oscar 时，我们不只是跳回开始。
Let's change the score by 1 up here.
我们要将分数加 1。
So now notice, if touching Oscar changed the score, that is, add 1 to the score,
注意，如果碰到 Oscar 就会改变分数，也就是加 1，
And then pick a new random location.
然后选择一个新的随机位置。
And now, green flag.
现在，点击绿旗开始。
Let's do this slowly.
我们慢慢来。
Here it goes.
开始了。
The trash can opens.
垃圾桶打开了。
I let go.
我松开了鼠标。
And now notice at the top left of my program, notice the score is now 2.
现在请注意，程序左上角的分数变成了 2。
Notice the score, if I do this again, is about to become 3.
注意，如果我再做一次，分数就会变成 3。
And so here we have building blocks, literally, of making this program better and better and better.
这样我们就有了积木块，可以一步步地改进程序。
And so indeed, that's how you generally approach solving any large program, any problem with code, be it in Scratch or C or Python or some other.
的确，这就是你通常处理任何大型程序、任何代码问题的方法，无论是在 Scratch、C、Python 还是其他语言中。
You take this vision you might have or some vision you've been assigned in a homework assignment and try to break it down into these constituent parts.
你从你可能有的想法或者作业中被分配到的想法开始，试着把它分解成这些组成部分。
And just pluck off the easy ones first.
先把简单的事情做完。
Put the lamppost there first and at least feel like you're making some progress.
先把路灯放好，至少感觉你正在取得一些进展。
Then pluck off something like the trash can and just make it do a little thing.
然后再处理像垃圾桶之类的东西，让它做点小事。
And it doesn't have to be in some same order here.
而且不必按照相同的顺序。
I could have done this in a million different ways.
我可以用一百万种不同的方式来完成这个。
But figure out what the small pieces are that ultimately, like a few of the problems we've solved today, assemble into a greater solution there too.
但是要弄清楚哪些是小的部分，最终，就像我们今天解决的一些问题一样，将它们组合成一个更大的解决方案。
So that you have now a mental model for these types of blocks and others, let's return for a moment to this.
现在你已经对这些类型的块和其他块有了一个心理模型，让我们暂时回到这个例子。
We saw a moment ago that when I started saying, hello, David, and nesting those puzzle pieces, we had a whole different paradigm altogether.
我们刚才看到，当我开始说“Hello，David”，并将这些拼图块嵌套在一起时，我们有了一个完全不同的范式。
My input for that second version of hello, world was to now pass in, for instance, what's your name, into my function called ask.
我对于第二个版本的“Hello, world”的输入变成了，例如，将“你叫什么名字”传递给我称为 ask 的函数。
That gave me not a side effect, but what I called, again, a return value called answer by default in Scratch.
这没有给我带来副作用，而是给了我一个我之前称为返回值的东西，在 Scratch 中默认称为 answer。
And now notice and recall, when I had that same output become the input to my next block, it looked a little something like this, say.
现在请注意并回想一下，当我将相同的输出作为下一个块的输入时，它看起来是这样的。
So how does this type of block and this nesting, this stacking of blocks fit into the same mental model?
那么，这种类型的块以及这种嵌套、这种块的堆叠是如何与同一个心理模型相适应的呢？
Well, same idea.
同样的道理。
My input for that part of the story is now Taking in not one input, but two.
这个故事中这部分的输入现在是接受两个输入，而不是一个。
Two arguments, hello, and the answer from before.
两个参数，“Hello”和之前的答案。
The function in this case is that new block called join.
在这种情况下，函数就是那个叫做 join 的新块。
The output thereof is hello, David, which itself became, if we sort of animate this, the input to my final function, which indeed was still say.
它的输出是“Hello，David”，如果我们把它动画化，它本身就变成了我最终函数的输入，而最终函数仍然是 say。
And this is only to say, no pun intended, that almost
这只是想说，一词双关，
Now, I thought we'd end by taking a look at just a couple of final examples, these ones, too, made by some of your predecessors.
现在，我想我们可以通过查看最后几个例子来结束这节课，这些例子也是由你们的前辈们制作的。
And for this, I thought we would not write code together, but read it instead.
我想我们不需要一起写代码，而是阅读代码。
And so allow me to open up one other example here that will show us a few different versions of a program that a predecessor made.
请允许我在这里打开另一个例子，它将向我们展示一个前辈制作的程序的几个不同版本。
Give me just a moment here.
稍等片刻。
And we'll see how we might build up to something even more interactive.
我们将看到如何构建更具交互性的东西。
And in just a moment, we'll see something they called Ivy's Hardest Game.
稍后，我们将看到他们称之为 Ivy's Hardest Game 的东西。
Focused here on these particular mechanics.
专注于这些特殊的机制。
So here is version 0, so to speak, of this program, wherein the goal was to create a game where you have to get out of some kind of maze.
这就是这个程序的版本 0，可以说，目标是创建一个游戏，你必须走出某种迷宫。
And you have to get out, in this case, the Harvard crest from this maze.
你需要从这个迷宫中取出哈佛校徽。
Let me go ahead and just hit play on this green flag so you can see what the first building block for this program might have been.
让我点击这个绿色的旗帜来运行它，这样你就可以看到这个程序的第一个构建块是什么样子。
Notice that my hand here is actually on the arrow keys of my keyboard.
注意，我的手实际上是在键盘上的箭头键上。
And it seems that by moving up, down, left, or right, this little crest on the screen responds in exactly that way.
通过向上、向下、向左或向右移动，屏幕上的这个小徽章会以完全相同的方式响应。
Now, let's hypothesize for just a moment, even though we've not done anything quite like this before, how might this code be implemented?
现在，让我们假设一下，即使我们以前从未做过类似的事情，这段代码是如何实现的？
How do you get a sprite, be it a cat or a crest, to respond to keys on a keyboard?
如何让一个精灵，无论是猫还是徽章，对键盘上的按键做出反应？
Might you think intuitively?
你凭直觉认为呢？
Yeah.
Yeah, there could be something sensing what key you're pressing on.
可能有什么东西在感应你按的是哪个键。
And if you do it again in a forever loop, you'll just constantly be listening for keystrokes.
如果你在一个无限循环中再次这样做，你就会不断地监听按键。
And this is how every piece of software nowadays works.
这就是现在每个软件的工作原理。
It's constantly waiting for your phone to be tapped or something to be typed on the screen.
它一直在等待你的手机被点击或者屏幕上输入什么东西。
So let me go ahead and look inside of this existing program here.
现在让我打开这个程序看看。
And there's more going on, but we'll take a quick glance.
里面还有更多内容，但我们先快速浏览一下。
What's actually going on?
这到底是怎么回事？
Well, up here at top left notice, we just have go to x equals 0 and y equals 0.
可以看到，左上角显示，我们只需要让 x = 0，y = 0。
That means put the Harvard crest dead center in the middle of the stage.
这意味着将哈佛校徽放置在舞台正中央。
Then we have forever two functions that we made in advance as custom functions.
然后我们有两个预先定义好的自定义函数，它们会一直运行。
Listen for keyboard, feel for walls.
Listen for keyboard 和 Feel for walls。
So it's doing two things at once.
所以它同时在做两件事。
It's forever listening for the keyboard, up, down, left, right, and feeling for the walls in the sense that if I get too far to the left, I don't want it to keep moving past that black wall.
它一直在监听键盘输入，上、下、左、右，并在“感知墙壁”，也就是说，如果它太靠左，我不希望它继续移动超过那堵黑墙。
And if it moves too far to the right, I don't want it to blow through that wall either.
如果它向右移动得太远，我也不希望它穿透那堵墙。
So it's going to do two things constantly, listening for keyboard and feeling for walls, so to speak.
所以它会一直做两件事，监听键盘和感知墙壁。
And how are those implemented?
它们是如何实现的呢？
Well, this one's a bit long, but on the left here is listen for keyboard.
左边这个是 Listen for keyboard，它有点长。
So this pink puzzle piece, listen for keyboard, first checks.
所以这个粉色的代码块，Listen for keyboard，首先会检查。
If the key up arrow is pressed, question mark, Boolean expression in the conditional, change y by 1.
如果按下了向上箭头键，问号表示这是一个布尔表达式，表示条件判断，将 y 的值改变 1。
That means move it up 1.
这意味着向上移动 1。
Else if the key down arrow is pressed, then change y by negative 1.
否则，如果按下了向下箭头键，则将 y 的值改变 -1。
And similar for left arrow, similar for right arrow.
左箭头和右箭头也类似。
And even though there's not a loop in this pink function, there is where I'm using it.
尽管在这个粉色的函数中没有循环，但我在使用它的地方有循环。
So it's constantly being asked again and again.
它不断地被反复询问。
How about feeling for walls?
Feel for walls 怎么样？
Well, over here to the right.
这边右边。
It's a little cut off, but here you have if touching left wall, change x by 1.
它被切断了一点，但这里如果你碰到左边的墙，x 坐标改变 1。
So if you hit the wall, it's too late.
所以如果你撞到墙，就太晚了。
You're kind of blowing through it already.
你已经把它穿过去了。
So I want to move it whack one pixel so it's no longer touching that wall.
所以我想把它移动一个像素，这样它就不再碰到那堵墙了。
Similarly, if it's touching the right wall, I want to back it up one pixel so it's no longer touching that wall.
类似地，如果它碰到右边的墙，我想把它往回移动一个像素，这样它就不再碰到那堵墙了。
So it's kind of like bouncing off ever so slightly so that it doesn't slip through that actual wall.
所以这有点像轻轻地弹开，这样它就不会穿过那堵墙。
And what are those walls?
那些墙是什么？
Well, notice down here, it's just a simple sprite with a black line that I've oriented vertically instead of horizontally.
请注意，下面只是一个简单的精灵，带有一条黑色的线，我把它垂直放置而不是水平放置。
And that's just so that I can ask questions of these other two sprites.
这样我就可以询问其他两个精灵问题了。
Now, that gives me that form of interactivity.
现在，这给了我那种形式的互动性。
What more can I now do?
我现在还能做什么？
Well, what if we make things a little more interactive here?
如果我们让事情变得更具互动性呢？
Let me go ahead and see inside version 1 our second, and let me propose what's going to happen here.
让我继续看看版本 1 中的第二个版本，让我提出这里将要发生的事情。
Well, how might we add a little something like Yale into the mix?
我们怎样才能在其中添加像 Yale 这样的小东西呢？
Well, what's Yale going to do when I hit the green flag now based on this code?
根据这段代码，当我点击绿色旗帜时，Yale 会做什么？
Any hunches?
有什么预感吗？
Here is the code for my Yale sprite.
这是我的 Yale 精灵的代码。
Yeah, it's going to be an adversary by blocking my path, theoretically, if I keep writing more code.
理论上，如果我继续写更多的代码，它会挡住我的路，成为我的对手。
So why?
那为什么呢？
It, too, goes to the middle of the screen.
它也会移动到屏幕中间。
It points in direction 90 degrees.
它指向 90 度的方向。
So similarly, there's a whole degree system as well.
类似地，这里也有一个完整的角度系统。
And it forever asks this, if touching the left wall or, notice the green block, touching the right wall,
它会一直询问，如果碰到左墙，或者，注意看这个绿色块，碰到右墙，
Then just turn around 180 degrees.
那就旋转 180 度。
And indeed, if you think this through logically, that just means you're bouncing this way and this way by just flipping yourself around 180 degrees for just this Yale sprite.
事实上，如果你仔细想想，这只意味着你通过让这个 Yale 精灵旋转 180 度，来让它在这条路上来回弹跳。
So if I go ahead and zoom in on this and click the green flag, I can still move up and down, but Yale is just kind of
如果我继续放大并点击绿旗，我仍然可以上下移动，但是 Yale 只是在
Doing this all day long, back and forth and back and forth forever.
这样来回不停地移动。
Nothing bad happens if I try to go through it, but we could add that, certainly, to the mix.
如果我试图穿过它，并不会发生什么，但我们当然可以在代码里添加这部分内容。
In fact, let's add one final feature before we play this particular game.
事实上，在我们玩这个游戏之前，让我们再添加最后一个功能。
And let me go ahead and open up the final version of these building blocks that adds MIT to the mix.
让我打开这些积木的最终版本，它加入了 MIT 的元素。
So here's MIT.
这就是 MIT。
Someone want to explain what this code does?
有人想解释一下这段代码的作用吗？
And this is what we're doing.
这就是我们正在做的。
This itself is a skill, reading someone else's code and understanding it is half of the part of programming besides writing.
阅读别人的代码并理解它是编程的一半内容，而另一半则是编写代码，这本身就是一项技能。
Yeah, it's chasing down the Harvard logo outline.
它正在追逐哈佛的标志轮廓。
So this is apparently the name of the costume that this student made, Harvard logo outline.
看来这就是这个学生做的服装的名字，哈佛标志轮廓。
And apparently, it goes to a random position first, but then it forever points to Harvard.
而且显然，它首先会移动到一个随机位置，但之后会永远指向哈佛。
So no matter where I'm moving it, up, down, left, or right, MIT is being a little more strategic than Yale, bouncing back and forth like this.
所以无论我把它移动到哪里，上、下、左、右，MIT 都比 Yale 更有策略性，像这样来回弹跳。
So let's go ahead and play this one in full screen.
让我们继续，全屏播放这个。
And here we have a green flag.
这里有一个绿旗。
So if I move up, MIT.
如果我向上移动，MIT。
Rather strategically is following me no matter where I go.
相当有策略性地跟着我，无论我走到哪里。
All right, so still, nothing bad happens.
还是一样，没有发生什么不好的事情。
And now it's struggling, right?
现在它在挣扎，对吧？
It's going up, down, up, down.
它在上下、上下地移动。
It's trying to follow me, even though I'm not moving.
它试图跟着我，即使我没有移动。
So we need some final flourishes.
所以我们需要一些最后的点缀。
And so I think for this, we need perhaps one final volunteer.
所以我想为此，我们可能需要最后一位志愿者。
After this, cake awaits for everyone outside, as is an end of first lecture CS50 tradition.
在此之后，外面有蛋糕等着大家，这是 CS50 第一课结束的传统。
Would you like to come up and be our final volunteer?
你想上来做我们最后一位志愿者吗？
All right, and so this will be the actual version written by one of your predecessors that I'll full screen here.
这就是由你们的一位前辈编写的实际版本，我将在这里全屏显示。
It's going to stitch together all of these same primitives and more, but add the notion of scores and lives so that there's actually a goal, which in this case is to move the Harvard crest to constantly pursue the character on the right hand side so that your sprite touches that one.
它将把所有这些相同的基元以及更多内容拼接在一起，但添加了分数和生命值的概念，
以便实际上有一个目标，在本例中，目标是移动哈佛校徽以不断追赶右侧的角色，以便你的精灵触碰到那个角色。
Would you like to introduce yourself?
你想自我介绍一下吗？
Hi, my name is Mohamed.
嗨，我叫 Mohamed。
All right, wonderful.
好的，太棒了。
Welcome aboard.
欢迎登船。
And here we come with some instructions and final flourish if we want to keep the lights up, but perhaps increase the music.
如果我们想保持灯光亮度，但也许可以增加音乐的音量，我们会提供一些指示和最后的润色。
Notice he's using the up, down, left, right, but there's many more walls now.
注意，他正在使用上、下、左、右，但现在有更多墙了。
First level's pretty easy, but now Yale's in the mix, bouncing back and forth.
第一关非常简单，但现在 Yale 也加入了，来回弹跳。
All right, that's it for CS50.
好的，CS50 就到这里。
Welcome.
欢迎。
Cake is now served.
现在上蛋糕。
We'll see you next time.
下次再见。